<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>children&#8217;s &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/childrens/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>children&#8217;s &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>App of the Week: Millie&#8217;s Crazy Dinosaur Adventure &#8211; Millie Was Here, Book 3</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/09/16/app-of-the-week-millies-crazy-dinosaur-adventure-millie-was-here-book-3/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/09/16/app-of-the-week-millies-crazy-dinosaur-adventure-millie-was-here-book-3/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2013 20:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebook]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=45014</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Millie’s Crazy Dinosaur Adventure</a> tells the tale of one adorable dog’s journey back in time to the land of dinosaurs. When Millie attends Kitty’s birthday party, she’s embarrassed to realize that she’s forgotten her gift at home. Millie decides to build a simple time machine to go back in time and retrieve the gift, but to her surprise, she travels a little <em>too</em> far back.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-45016" alt="Screen Shot 2013-09-15 at 8.01.58 PM" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Screen-Shot-2013-09-15-at-8.01.58-PM.png" /><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/au/app/millies-crazy-dinosaur-adventure/id695161183?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D2&lt;br /&gt;
">Millie’s Crazy Dinosaur Adventure</a> tells the tale of one adorable dog’s journey back in time to the land of dinosaurs. When Millie attends Kitty’s birthday party, she’s embarrassed to realize that she’s forgotten her gift at home. Millie decides to build a simple time machine to go back in time and retrieve the gift, but to her surprise, she travels a little <em>too</em> far back.</p>
<p>This tale of adventure and friendship engages children with rich activities that include interacting with the story, exploring elements of the tale, solving puzzles, and practicing/enhancing vocabulary. The read-along feature highlights each word as the narrator reads, and interactivity clues appear as paw prints to help kids along the way. A particularly clever “bedroom mode” offers a calming pre-sleep reading experience with a dimmed screen, soothing music, and lower volume.</p>
<p class="ac"><img class="wp-image-45015" alt="Millie's adventure screenshot" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Millies-adventure.jpeg" /></p>
<p>Developed by the children&#8217;s app studio <a href=http://www.megapops.com/>Megapops</a>, this is the first “in-house” app from founders Randy Lowenstein and Jennifer Taylor. In 2011, the duo hired a professional developer to create their first two apps, <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/millie-was-here-book-1-meet/id452174851?mt=8>Meet Millie</a> and <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/millie-lost-key-millie-was/id452175094?mt=8>Millie and The Lost Key</a>. For their third book, they decided to develop on their own with <a href=www.coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk>Corona SDK</a>, finding the platform incredibly easy to use.</p>
<p>Randy tells us, “The amazing thing is that it took us about 8 months of development to create our first app, coding natively for iOS with a small team of experienced iOS developers. It took me the same amount of time to learn how to program from scratch, with absolutely zero programming experience, and then to do all of the programming for Millie&#8217;s Crazy Dinosaur Adventure, entirely by myself. It took about 4 months of learning, and then 4 months of programming.”</p>
<p>The hard work paid off, as Millie’s Crazy Dinosaur Adventure soared to #1 in Books and #2 in Education on the App Store. To top it off, the book app was graced with a large promotional banner by Apple, as seen below. To read this charming story with your child, head to iTunes and download <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/au/app/millies-crazy-dinosaur-adventure/id695161183?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D2&lt;br /&gt;
">Millie’s Crazy Dinosaur Adventure</a> for $1.99.</p>
<p class="ac"><img class="wp-image-45072" alt="Millie's Adventure" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Millies-Adventure.png" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/09/16/app-of-the-week-millies-crazy-dinosaur-adventure-millie-was-here-book-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>App of the Week: Zala and the Treasure Cave</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/08/26/app-of-the-week-zala-and-the-treasure-cave/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/08/26/app-of-the-week-zala-and-the-treasure-cave/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 22:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kwik]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=42485</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<div>When a group of friends discover a secret treasure map, they need your help to decipher the map and embark on an adventure through the African savanna.</div>
 
<div style="margin-top:10px;">Created for children ages 4-6, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/zala-and-the-treasure-cave/id682584983?mt=8&#38;ign-mpt=uo%3D4">Zala and the Treasure Cave</a> captivates children’s senses — from touch to sound to sight — through vibrant illustrations and engaging elements to pull kids into the story.</div>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-42486" alt="Zala icon" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Screen-Shot-2013-08-23-at-4.39.54-PM.png" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Screen-Shot-2013-08-23-at-4.39.54-PM.png 183w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Screen-Shot-2013-08-23-at-4.39.54-PM-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 183px) 100vw, 183px" /></p>
<p>When a group of friends discover a secret treasure map, they need your help to decipher the map and embark on an adventure through the African savanna. Created for children ages 4-6, <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/zala-and-the-treasure-cave/id682584983?mt=8&ign-mpt=uo%3D4>Zala and the Treasure Cave</a> captivates children’s senses — from touch to sound to sight — through vibrant illustrations, engaging elements to pull kids into the story, and an excellent mix of sounds and narration.</p>
<p>Zala and the Treasure Cave adds a new dimension to the idea of storytelling, combining an animated film with interactive games and puzzles that are woven into the story. The story-driven app uses the tools of film dramaturgy to transport emotions while integrating puzzles into the plot, while the games and a diverse cast of characters allow children to explore and discover app elements in a playful way.</p>
<p>The app&#8217;s creators are a talented husband and wife duo who wanted to develop an educational eBook based on their own experiences growing up in Turkey and Germany. Their goal was to create a memorable story of friendship using characters of different colors, religions, and genders.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="wp-image-42487" alt="Zala screenshot" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Zala-screenshot.jpeg" /></p>
<p>While the creators had a solid background in filmmaking and 3D animation, they were new to the world of mobile development. They evaluated several tools and found that the majority were either too complicated to work with or too simple in their capabilities, especially when it came to straightforward integration of an interactive environment.</p>
<p>Within a few days of discovering Corona SDK, they learned the Lua programming language, analyzed Corona’s sample projects, and read <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/resources/tutorials/getting-started-with-corona/ target="_blank">Corona</a> and <a href=http://www.kwiksher.com/ target="_blank">Kwik</a> tutorials to get up to speed. In less than two weeks, they had a working prototype for testing on all devices, featuring audio integration, fade-in and fade-out between scenes, and much more.</p>
<p>To experience the striking graphics and high quality narration of <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/zala-and-the-treasure-cave/id682584983?mt=8&ign-mpt=uo%3D4>Zala and the Treasure Cave</a>, head to iTunes and download the app for $2.99.</p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/seQpUt3yv5c" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/08/26/app-of-the-week-zala-and-the-treasure-cave/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>App of the Week: Penguin Rescue</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/07/01/app-of-the-week-penguin-rescue/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 15:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puzzle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[word]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=36634</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Created by Learning Gems, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/learning-gems-penguin-rescue/id652219740?ls=1&#38;mt=8">Penguin Rescue</a> is a word puzzle game that’s centered around saving adorable penguins from the perils of an ice cavern. Available for young players on iOS, Android and Kindle devices, Penguin Rescue is loads of fun, boasting chirpy music and fantastic graphics.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-36635" alt="Penguin Rescue" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Screen-Shot-2013-06-23-at-5.02.38-PM-150x150.png" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Screen-Shot-2013-06-23-at-5.02.38-PM-150x150.png 150w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Screen-Shot-2013-06-23-at-5.02.38-PM.png 201w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />Created by <a href=http://www.learninggems.com/>Learning Gems</a>, <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/learning-gems-penguin-rescue/id652219740?ls=1&mt=8>Penguin Rescue</a> is a word puzzle game that’s centered around saving adorable penguins from the perils of an ice cavern. Available for young players on iOS, Android and Kindle Fire devices, Penguin Rescue is loads of fun, boasting chirpy music and fantastic graphics.</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-36639" alt="Penguin Rescue screenshot" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Penguin-Rescue-screenshot1.jpg" />To save a penguin, you must solve the word puzzle in each game. To start, you’re presented with snowballs that are each marked with a letter. You&#8217;re given twelve attempts to throw the snowballs at icicles above &#8211; with each correctly guessed letter, the snowball hits an icicle causing it to fall and break through the ice below to get your penguin one step closer to safety.</p>
<p>Once you solve the entire word, all the ice blocks break and your penguin friend can swim out. The faster you solve each puzzle, the more points you will earn, and with each completed word you save the life of one penguin. Once you&#8217;ve played several rounds, you can get a snapshot of the rescued birds by visiting the Penguin Village. Upon seeing all your successfully &#8220;rescued&#8221; friends, you&#8217;ll enjoy a sense of accomplishment and will feel even more motivated to forge ahead and save the others.</p>
<p>You can download your copy of Penguin Rescue for just $0.99 in the following app stores:</p>
<p>iTunes: <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/learning-gems-penguin-rescue/id652219740?ls=1&mt=8>itunes.apple.com/us/app/learning-gems-penguin-rescue/id652219740?ls=1&amp;mt=8</a></p>
<p>Google Play: <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bluefireventures.penguinrescue>play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bluefireventures.penguinrescue</a></p>
<p>Amazon Appstore: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Learning-Gems-Penguin-Rescue/dp/B00CYPD4GG/&lt;br /&gt;
">amazon.com/Learning-Gems-Penguin-Rescue/dp/B00CYPD4GG/</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>App of the Week: MixUp DressUp</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/05/27/app-of-the-week-mixup-dressup/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/05/27/app-of-the-week-mixup-dressup/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 22:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=34591</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[MixUp DressUp brings a favorite children's pastime - doll dress-ups and fashion shows - to mobile, allowing children to create stylish outfits and characters with the swipe of a finger. Available on the App Store, the endless possibilities for customization in MixUp DressUp makes for a super fun dress-up experience.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Screen-Shot-2013-05-24-at-9.25.58-AM.png" alt="MixUp DressUp" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-34592" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Screen-Shot-2013-05-24-at-9.25.58-AM.png 201w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Screen-Shot-2013-05-24-at-9.25.58-AM-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 201px) 100vw, 201px" /></p>
<p>While children may love dressing up their dolls, many parents are hesitant to clutter their closets with a variety of miniature outfits. MixUp DressUp brings a favorite children&#8217;s pastime &#8211; doll dress-ups and fashion shows &#8211; to mobile, allowing children to create stylish outfits and characters with the swipe of a finger. Available on the <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mixup-dressup/id571062209?mt=8>App Store</a>, the endless possibilities for customization in MixUp DressUp make for a super fun dress-up experience for children in the digital age.</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/MixUp-DressUp-screenshow.jpg" alt="MixUp DressUp screenshot" class="alignright size-full wp-image-34593" />In MixUp DressUp, the fashion models are split into three horizontal panels, allowing children to play lead designer. To change a model&#8217;s face to reflect different ethnicities, and to switch up her articles of clothing with items ranging from dresses to shoes to everything in between, you simply need to swipe a panel. After picking out the perfect outfit, you can select a background for the character, from options including a castle scene, polka dot wallpaper and more. If you&#8217;d like an endless closet of possibilities for your doll, you can purchase the Spring 2013 Collections&#8217; 3,300 possible outfits for just $0.99. </p>
<p>By far, my favorite element of the app was the ability to create customized voice recordings. MixUp DressUp allowed me to record my own voice with encouraging comments that got played back to me each time I created a new customization on my character. This fun (and free!) <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mixup-dressup/id571062209?mt=8>download</a> for iPad/iPhone is a great alternative to traditional doll dress-ups; highly recommended for young children.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/05/27/app-of-the-week-mixup-dressup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
