<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>math &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/math/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>math &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>From the Forum — Issue #126</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/06/03/from-the-forum-issue-126/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 22:08:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[From the Forum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dusk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gymble]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[math]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maths library]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[objects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tile engine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[touch]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=67025</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Welcome to the latest installment of From the Forum. In this series, guest blogger Alex Jackson highlights outstanding threads from the Corona Forum. The goal is to bring attention to the most captivating, interesting, and thought-provoking discussions taking place in our very own backyard.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-54943" style="margin: 0px 0px 10px 10px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Icon_Resources_Forum.png" alt="From the Forum" /><em>Welcome to the latest installment of <strong>From the Forum</strong>. In <em>this series</em>, guest blogger Alex Jackson highlights outstanding threads from the <a href=http://forum.coronalabs.com/ target="_blank">Corona Forum</a>. The goal is to bring attention to the most captivating, interesting, and thought-provoking discussions taking place in our very own backyard.</em></p>
<p><em>Please <a href=http://forum.coronalabs.com/ target="_blank">visit the forum</a> to join these conversations or start your own!</em></p>
<hr />
<h3>Math libraries</h3>
<p>Shorthand geometry has never been my strong suit. I’ve always struggled with the area of a triangle, circumference of a circle, or any number of esoteric vector math functions. However, it’s vital to have some grasp of these concepts when engaging in extensive game development &#8212; but going back and forth between trigonometry documentation and your code is no way to live! That’s why it’s so nice that there are several math libraries for us to leverage. Extending the usefulness of Corona’s baked-in <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/library/math/index.html>math</a> library, we can start using some simple shorthand functions, easing us into the proverbial bathtub of complicated arithmetic scenarios.</p>
<p>Check out the <a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/63285-working-out-angle-to-apply-force/ target="_blank">original thread here</a> to grab some info on math libraries. Have a helper module of our own? We’d love to hear about it!</p>
<h3>Dusk 1.0 beta</h3>
<p>One of the first posts we highlighted in the <em>From the Forum</em> series was the up-and-coming developments of a little software studio called <strong>Gymbyl Coding</strong>. Over the years, <strong>Caleb</strong>, the main man at Gymbyl, has gifted the Corona community with awesome modules to extend the usefulness of the already-useful Corona SDK.</p>
<p>One of the main focuses of Gymbyl in the last year has been their <strong>Dusk</strong> game engine. What started out as a basic tile management system evolved into a fully-realized library that has helped many new and veteran developers quickly produce fantastic games.</p>
<p>Now, Dusk 1.0 has entered beta testing and it’s your chance to help Gymbyl kick the tires. Head down to <a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/61794-in-development-dusk-10/ target="_blank">the original thread</a> to get in on this great opportunity!</p>
<h3>Stopping objects with a touch</h3>
<p>When prototyping simple object movement mechanics in your games, it’s easy to become entranced by the siren song of updating coordinates during the “moved” phase of a touch function. Dead simple, but it isn’t as extensible when you start dealing with physics objects.</p>
<p>Physics objects need some additional TLC to work with a user’s touch interaction, and this is what initiated the birth of the physics touch joint. This joint lets us modify the location of a physics object without Box2d throwing a fit.</p>
<p>Check out <a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/63392-how-to-stop-movement-of-physics-object-with-touch/ target="_blank">the original thread</a> that discusses one approach to using touch joints, and stick around for other samples that <strong>RoamingGamer</strong> drops on us. That guy is the gift who keeps on giving!</p>
<h4>About Alex</h4>
<p>Alex Jackson is an indie developer and the founder of <a href=http://www.panc.co/ target="_blank">Panc Interactive</a>, specializing in retro-style gaming. He has created several mobile applications, enjoys long walks on the beach, pixel art, and reading the Corona forums. Contact him by <a href=mailto:alex@panc.co>email</a> or follow him on Twitter: <a href=http://twitter.com/pancinteractive>@pancinteractive</a>. Check out his new game <a href=http://www.panc.co/segreta-download-page.html target="_blank">Segreta</a> on iOS, Android, Windows Phone and Amazon devices.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Case Study: DoodleMaths &#8211; teaching math the fun way</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/03/17/case-study-doodlemaths-teaching-math-the-fun-way/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 01:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Case Study - Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lua]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doodle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[math]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[primary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[secondary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=66123</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this case study, dive into EZ Education's DoodleMaths, a math education app from this UK based development studio. Learn more about this innovative team and their accomplishments.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-66126" style="margin: 0px 0px 20px 20px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/vIay5wqa-150x150.png" alt="vIay5wqa" width="150" height="150" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/vIay5wqa-150x150.png 150w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/vIay5wqa-300x300.png 300w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/vIay5wqa-500x500.png 500w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/vIay5wqa.png 551w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />In this post, we highlight <a href=https://www.doodlemaths.com/ target="_blank">DoodleMaths</a> by <a href=http://www.ezeducation.co.uk/ target="_blank">EZ Education</a>. DoodleMaths is an intuitive math app for children that allows them to consistently work at the best level for them. Its algorithm works to understand the level a child is currently working at and then it creates a work program for them so they can continually consolidate and learn new topics, rather than playing it safe and only doing what they know well.</p>
<p>Tom Minor, along with co-founder Nicola Chilman, founded EZ Education in 2012 with the aim of enhancing  the way kids learn through adaptive learning programs. As experienced classroom educators, they have first-hand experience working with kids, and DoodleMaths is the top-selling math app for elementary school children in the UK.</p>
<p><iframe width="1060" height="596" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PvokxEqIDOo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" gesture="media" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>DoodleMaths has won many accolades. &#8220;We have had 5-star reviews from the Educational App Store and have recently won Best Mobile App at The SPARKies, run by TechSPARK. We have been in the top 10 of the education apps in iTunes, and we have been shortlisted for KPMG&#8217;s Best British Mobile Startup,&#8221; says Tom. &#8220;As a company, we have received numerous rewards and can proudly say we have the best selling primary maths app in the United Kingdom.&#8221;</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-66127" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/screen640x640.jpeg" alt="screen640x640" width="640" height="360" /></p>
<h3>Building their app</h3>
<p>The developers realized how much children engage with tablets and the huge potential for them to learn in a way that individually suits their needs. Their background as teachers and tutors meant that they had first-hand experience of how an app could work alongside common teaching methods in order to draw the most out of the child.</p>
<p>For EZ Education, app development is an ongoing process, so they continuously iterate on their design and code base. The company has used Corona for development of their three existing applications and their upcoming fourth application. Thanks to Corona and the Lua language, they can develop a core app in around three months and smaller projects even faster.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-66128" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/unnamed.jpg" alt="unnamed" width="512" height="384" /></p>
<p>When asked about advice for developers, Tom says &#8220;My first bit of advice would be for newcomers. I would recommend that they read the tutorials and try out some sample applications to see how much time they could save. Corona really streamlines the development process.&#8221; He continues, &#8220;It was important to my team to establish a set of programming standards and best practices and we were easily able to find wonderful examples on the Corona <a href=https://code.coronalabs.com/code target="_blank">Code Exchange</a>. I recommend that others look there for patterns and inspiration when developing their own application.&#8221;</p>
<h3>Going online</h3>
<p>Some developers chase problems which they have little experience in solving. For some, it&#8217;s a challenge to learn new things, but sometimes recognizing that you need help is an important step. For EZ Education, their staff is educators. Building and hosting an online service is challenging, but DoodleMaths needed features to enable teachers to get the most out of the app. EZ Education found the solution in Bluefuse Systems (<a href=http://www.bluefusesystems.com>www.bluefusesystems.com/</a>) to develop parent and teacher dashboards. These dashboards contain features such as live monitoring, live messaging, and leaderboards, giving the students the ability to challenge each other while keeping the parents and teachers involved in their progress.</p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>If you want to check out DoodleMaths and EZ Education&#8217;s other apps, visit their <a href=https://www.doodlemaths.com/ target="_blank">website</a> at <a href=https://www.doodlemaths.com/ target="_blank">https://www.doodlemaths.com/</a>. From there, you can download each of their apps on all of the supported platforms. DoodleMaths is a fun (but serious) tool used to educate children, and it was all built with Corona SDK. <a href=/ target="_blank">Get started today!</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
