<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Corona Geek &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/corona-geek/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Corona Geek &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Corona Geek Level Up &#8211; Global Game Jam, Game Coder, and Spine</title>
		<link>/blog/coronageek/corona-geek-level-up-global-game-jam-game-coder-and-spine/</link>
		<comments>/blog/coronageek/corona-geek-level-up-global-game-jam-game-coder-and-spine/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 23:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles McKeever]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona Geek]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.coronalabs.com/?post_type=coronageek&#038;p=28901</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It's been a crazy busy week here at Corona Labs. Here's a quick recap of some the things we've been working on this week. Starting this time last Friday, members of the team hung out at Global Game Jam in San Francisco and it was wicked awesome. There were a ton of creative people all packed into one big warehouse sized space and I got to talk with some amazingly talented people. Here are some images and video from Global Game Jam, San Francisco. Here's a quick interview with one of the teams that participated at Global Game Jam in San Francisco.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/CtOYA7cp0F0?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>It&#8217;s been a crazy busy week here at Corona Labs. Here&#8217;s a quick recap of some the things we&#8217;ve been working on this week.</p>
<p>Starting this time last Friday, members of the team hung out at Global Game Jam in San Francisco and it was wicked awesome. There were a ton of creative people all packed into one big warehouse sized space and I got to talk with some amazingly talented people. Here are some <a href=https://plus.google.com/108159899655420864045/posts/SEEqU5dGJxN target="_blank">images and video from Global Game Jam, San Francisco</a>.</p>
<p>There wasn&#8217;t a normal Monday Corona Geek hangout this week because I was flying back from California, but I did have the opportunity to talk with Ricardo Rauber Pereira about his new Corona SDK development tool, Game Coder which is a new iOS app that allows you to build a game on your iPad. Ricardo explained how projects can be exported to Corona for editing and then published for iOS devices. It’s an amazing tool that was built using Corona SDK. <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/game-coder/id580568570?ls=1&mt=8 target="_blank">Check out Game Coder</a> in the App Store! I&#8217;ll be posting the full interview with Ricardo in next few days along with a blog post that explains how Game Coder works. </p>
<p>Also this week, we&#8217;ve been reaching out to Corona Ambassadors around the world to get their feedback on the program. The ambassadors have been providing us with fantastic feedback about their goals for 2013 and we have begun working to create brand new resources so they can share Corona SDK with everyone they meet. If you missed the new <a href=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CiPuo5fIuZ0 target="_blank">Introduction to Corona SDK video</a>, be sure to watch it. It&#8217;s 7 minutes of focused information to help anyone get started using Corona.</p>
<p>Next Wednesday I&#8217;ll be heading back out to San Francisco for Apps World North America. Walter Luh and David Rangel are speaking at the event in two separate sessions. We&#8217;ll also have a booth at the event and members of the team will be hanging out at Apps World. I&#8217;ll be walking the event floor to talk with developers. Expect to see lots of pictures from the event. We&#8217;ll try to post as much video as possible, but battery life and internet might be limited.</p>
<p>On Monday, be sure to <a href=https://plus.google.com/events/c7tr9lkqh36nsntjmvb3jkafi0s target="_blank">join us on the weekly Corona Geek hangout</a> when we&#8217;ll be recapping Global Game Jam events and talking with the team at Esoteric Software about their <a href=http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/esotericsoftware/spine target="_blank">wildly successful Kickstarter campaign</a> that has raised almost $17K. Their 2D skeletal animation tool is going to support Corona SDK, so we want to talk to them about that.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s it for this week.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t forget to <a href=http://coronapaper.com/ target="_blank">download your FREE copy of Corona Paper</a>. Hurry though, because it&#8217;s only free through Monday, Feb. 4th. It&#8217;s a great magazine dedicated to mobile development using Corona SDK.</p>
<p>Have a great weekend.</p>
<p>Charles McKeever<br />
a.k.a, Corona Geek</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/coronageek/corona-geek-level-up-global-game-jam-game-coder-and-spine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corona Labs Does Global Game Jam, San Francisco Style</title>
		<link>/blog/coronageek/corona-labs-does-global-game-jam-san-francisco-style/</link>
		<comments>/blog/coronageek/corona-labs-does-global-game-jam-san-francisco-style/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2013 21:45:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles McKeever]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona Geek]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=coronageek&#038;p=28715</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So yesterday's launch of Global Game Jam here in San Francisco went well. As people arrived they were encouraged to create fun hats to wear. That helped to bring people together at the various tables around the room. Most people put their name on their hat as a form of name tag. Overall, it was really just a time for people to get to know each other and talk because some people knew each other, but a lot of them didn't.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4itmLlznYpQ?rel=0" height="350" width="620" frameborder="0"></iframe><br />
So yesterday&#8217;s launch of Global Game Jam here in San Francisco went well. </p>
<p>As people arrived they were encouraged to <a href=https://plus.google.com/108159899655420864045/posts/2pmHoY7ZUDa target="_blank">create fun hats to wear</a>. That helped to bring people together at the various tables around the room. Most people put their name on their hat as a form of name tag. </p>
<p>Overall, it was really just a time for people to get to know each other and talk because some people knew each other, but a lot of them didn&#8217;t. </p>
<p>So at first there was a lot of talking and buzz, but once the event organizer revealed the game jam theme and covered the guidlines, people began to team up to discuss game ideas. </p>
<p>Each team started out by creating a list of possible game concepts, which were expressed in just a few words each. Then once they had chosen a which concept they would adopt, based on team skills and time limits, they started talking details. </p>
<p>With <strike>46</strike> 28ish hours left to go, it will be interesting to see what they create.</p>
<p>Read the full recap of last night&#8217;s Global Game Jam events on the <a href=https://plus.google.com/108159899655420864045/posts/5v7PPh2zFZG target="_blank">Corona Geek Google+ page</a>.</p>
<p>If you didn&#8217;t have a chance to <a href=http://globalgamejam.org/ target="_blank">attend one of this year&#8217;s events</a>, you should definitely consider putting it on your calendar for next year. It&#8217;s a lot of fun!</p>
<p><strong>Listen and Rate!</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href=http://CoronaGeek.com/itunes target="_blank">Rate the Corona Geek podcast on iTunes</a></li>
<li><a href=http://CoronaGeek.com/stitcher target="_blank">Listen and rate on Stitcher</a></li>
<li><a href=http://CoronaGeek.com/chrome target="_blank">Get the Corona SDK Quick Reference Chrome Extension</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/coronageek/corona-labs-does-global-game-jam-san-francisco-style/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corona Geek &#8211; Episode 24 &#8211; Hanging with Hiptic Games &#038; SSKCorona</title>
		<link>/blog/coronageek/corona-geek-hangout-24/</link>
		<comments>/blog/coronageek/corona-geek-hangout-24/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 19:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles McKeever]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona Geek]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.coronalabs.com/?post_type=coronageek&#038;p=28682</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[During this week's Corona Geek we hung out with Brian Burton, George Deglin, Long Vo, Ed Maurina, Matthew Chapman, and Gerald Bailey. We started the show off with some technical issues, but fortunately those issues didn't keep us from finding out how Hiptic games created and marketed a brand new game in just 11 weeks, and how a third party Corona SDK library can help you with some of the common tasks involved in creating games and apps. See the show notes below for more details.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qkHGge8MBNY?rel=0" height="350" width="620" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>During this week&#8217;s Corona Geek we hung out with Brian Burton, George Deglin, Long Vo, Ed Maurina, Matthew Chapman, and Gerald Bailey. We started the show off with some technical issues, but fortunately those issues didn&#8217;t keep us from finding out how Hiptic games created and marketed a brand new game in just 11 weeks, and how a third party Corona SDK library can help you with some of the common tasks involved in creating games and apps. See the show notes below for more details.</p>
<p>This week&#8217;s t-shirt winner was Andrew Kinnaman. Andrew followed Corona Geek on social media and then completed the <a href=http://coronageek.com/giveaway target="_blank">Corona Geek giveaway registration form</a> for a chance to win a Corona Labs t-shirt. Congratulations Andrew! Thank you for supporting the show and being a part of the Corona Community.</p>
<p>As always, be sure to <a title="Corona Geek on Google+" href=https://plus.google.com/b/108159899655420864045/108159899655420864045/posts target="_blank">join us next Monday at 12pm PST / 8pm GMT for a new episode</a> and <a title="Corona Geek on Google+" href=https://plus.google.com/b/108159899655420864045/108159899655420864045/posts target="_blank">add us to your Google+ Corona SDK circle</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks for watching,</p>
<p>Charles McKeever<br />
Developer Evangelist, Corona Labs</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Show Geeks:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>George Deglin</strong> &#8211; <a href=http://hiptic.com/ target="_blank">Development, Hiptic Games</a></li>
<li><strong>Long Vo</strong> &#8211; <a href=http://hiptic.com/ target="_blank">Design / Creative, Hiptic Games</a></li>
<li><strong>Ed Maurina</strong> &#8211; <a href=http://roaminggamer.com/ target="_blank">SSKCorona Creator, Roaming Gamer</a></li>
<li><strong>Brian Burton</strong> &#8211; Author of <a href=http://CoronaGeek.com/burton-corona-book target="_blank">Mobile App Development with Corona: Getting Started</a></li>
<li><strong>Charles McKeever</strong> &#8211; <a href=http://coronageek.com>Corona/ Geek</a> / Marathon Runner</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are new to the conversation, the Corona SDK is a cross platform mobile development tool kit that makes it easy for developers to create native applications for Android and iOS devices as well as for Kindle, and Nook. You can find out more about the Corona SDK at <a href=http://www.CoronaLabs.com/ target="_blank">CoronaLabs.com</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Show Notes &#8211; 01/21/2013</strong></p>
<p><strong>Announcements &#038; Events:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Upcoming Events</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href=http://www.meetup.com/CoronaItalia/events/95776102/ target="_blank">Jan 22 &#8211; Torino Italy,  Corona SDK Developers Courses</a></li>
<li><a href=https://www3.gotomeeting.com/register/654162678 target="_blank">Jan 23 &#8211; Kwiksher Webinar &#8211; If you are interested in creating mobile apps without writing code using Photoshop &#8211; sign up to attend the webinar, starting at 2pm PST.</a></li>
<li><a href=http://globalgamejam.org/ target="_blank">Global Game Jam &#8211; January 25th &#8211; 27th</a></li>
<li><a href=http://www.meetup.com/Corona-SDK-Boston-Meetup/events/100694622/?a=ea1_grp&rv=ea1 target="_blank">Jan 31 &#8211; Boston, MA, Corona SDK Developers Meetup &#8211; Guest Speaker &#8211; Dr. Brian Burton</a></li>
<li><a href=http://www.apps-world.net/northamerica/ target="_blank">Apps World San Francisco 2013 &#8211; Feb. 7th &#8211; 8th.</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Keep your New Years Resolution to create that new app!</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>From now until January 31st. Dr. Brian Burton, author of several <a href=http://burtonsmediagroup.com/books target="_blank">beginning Corona SDK books</a> is offering $5 off book purchases when you use the promo code &#8220;coronageek&#8221; during checkout. Visit Brian&#8217;s website, <a href=http://burtonsmediagroup.com/books target="_blank">Burton&#8217;s Media Group</a> for a list of Corona SDK books.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Lastest Build Release Notes</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In Build 1008, OpenFeint and all of its resources were removed for Android, which helps to reduce the APK file size.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Corona Blog highlights</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>If you find yourself working with Corona SDK times and dates, be sure to take 5 minutes to <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2013/01/15/working-with-time-and-dates-in-corona/>read through Rob Miracle&#8217;s tutorial on &#8220;Working With Time and Dates in Corona&#8221;</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Geek Speak</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>ShaqDown &#038; Hiptic Games</strong> &#8211; This week we hung out with George Deglin and Long Vo from <a href=http://hiptic.com/ target="_blank">Hiptic Games</a> to talk about their new hit title, <a href=http://shaqdown.com/ target="_blank">ShaqDown</a>. George and Long are also the creators of <a href=http://goninjagame.com/ target="_blank">GoNinja</a>, which is one of my favorite mobile games. The guys shared how they were able to create a completely custom designed mobile app in just 11 weeks using Corona SDK. They also shared some behind the scenes secrets on how they got exposure for their app. One of the most interesting comments from Long was how they offered exclusive debut coverage to IGN Entertainment who has delivered my than <a href=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tKApL3YAnfA target="_blank">160K+ video views of their game trailer</a>. Combine that with their own push notification efforts through their existing GoNinja install base and you&#8217;re talking about a respectable amount of exposure for a brand new game.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Super Starter Kit (SSK) for Corona SDK</strong> &#8211; We also got the chance to talk with Ed Maurina, creator of <a href=http://roaminggamer.com/sskcorona/ target="_blank">SSKCorona</a>. Ed has created a third party Corona SDK library that helps developers create games and apps. The library grew out of Ed&#8217;s own usage needs and is now offered up to developers as a way to shortcut common app development tasks. The library is written in Lua and can be downloaded and modified to match your project requirements. Find more information about SSKCorona on <a href=https://github.com/roaminggamer/SSKCorona target="_blank">GitHub</a> and <a href=http://roaminggamer.com/sskcorona/ target="_blank">Roaming Gamer</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>App Reviews</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Watch last week’s <a href=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DLLYIQXV0Ds target="_blank">Finger Hoola review</a></strong></li>
<li><strong>Check out <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2013/01/14/app-of-the-week-vidburn/>Last week’s app of the week &#8211; VidBurn</a></strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Closing thoughts</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>There won&#8217;t be a live Corona Geek hangout next week because I&#8217;ll be flying back from the <a href=http://globalgamejam.org/ target="_blank">Global Gam Jam</a> event in San Francisco. However, be sure to look for video updates and live blogging from the event. I&#8217;ll post as much as possible through out the entire 48 hour event.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>How to win a Corona Labs T-Shirt</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Congratulations to Andrew Kinnaman. He is this week&#8217;s winner of the a Corona Labs t-shirt. Each week we give away a t-shirt to someone in the Corona Geek audience. If you&#8217;d like to have a chance to win, just follow Corona Geek on <a href=http://twitter.com/coronageek target="_blank">Twitter</a>, <a href=http://facebook.com/coronageek target="_blank">Facebook</a>, <a href=https://plus.google.com/b/108159899655420864045/108159899655420864045/posts target="_blank">Google+</a>, or <a href=http://youtube.com/coronageek target="_blank">YouTube</a> and then <a href=http://coronageek.com/giveaway target="_blank">complete the registration form</a> to be entered for a chance to win.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Want to suggest a topic for an upcoming Corona Geek hangout?</strong> </p>
<ul>
<li>Submit your ideas on the <a href=http://developer.coronalabs.com/forums/corona-geek target="_blank">Corona Geek Forum Thread</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>That&#8217;s it for this week!</p>
<p>Thank you for watching, listening, and supporting the show and we&#8217;ll see you on next week&#8217;s Corona Geek hangout.</p>
<p><strong>Listen and Rate!</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href=http://CoronaGeek.com/itunes target="_blank">Rate the Corona Geek podcast on iTunes</a></li>
<li><a href=http://CoronaGeek.com/stitcher target="_blank">Listen and rate on Stitcher</a></li>
<li><a href=http://CoronaGeek.com/chrome target="_blank">Get the Corona SDK Quick Reference Chrome Extension</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/coronageek/corona-geek-hangout-24/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://corona-geek.s3.amazonaws.com/corona-geek-show-24-2013-01-21-shaqdown-sskcorona.mp3" length="40273116" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://corona-geek.s3.amazonaws.com/corona-geek-show-24-2013-01-21-shaqdown-sskcorona.mp3" length="40273116" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://corona-geek.s3.amazonaws.com/corona-geek-show-24-2013-01-21-shaqdown-sskcorona.mp3" length="40273116" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://corona-geek.s3.amazonaws.com/corona-geek-show-24-2013-01-21-shaqdown-sskcorona.mp3" length="40273116" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is The Corona SDK Just For Gaming?</title>
		<link>/blog/coronageek/is-the-corona-sdk-just-for-gaming/</link>
		<comments>/blog/coronageek/is-the-corona-sdk-just-for-gaming/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 22:12:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles McKeever]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona Geek]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sdkdallas.com/?p=109</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After the Mobile Introduction to Corona SDK webinar today, someone emailed me to ask if the Corona SDK was only for developing game apps. As an outside observer who is new to Corona, here’s my opinion on the subject.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.coronalabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/sdk-dallas-apps-faq.jpg" alt="" title="sdk-dallas-apps-faq" width="590" height="318" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-111" /></p>
<p>After the Mobile Introduction to Corona webinar today, someone emailed me to ask if the Corona SDK was only for developing game apps. </p>
<p>As an outside observer who is new to Corona, here&#8217;s my opinion on the subject.</p>
<p>I think gaming is a big topic for mobile developers and Corona does a lot of heavy lifting for the developer in that space. That said, all the elements for creating non-game apps is there in the API. Depending on what someone is trying to do, there may be some things missing. It would be nearly impossible for to include support for everything that someone might want to do. But, overall <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2012/02/14/reading-and-writing-files-in-corona/ target="_blank">reading and writing files</a>, <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2012/04/03/tutorial-database-access-in-corona/ target="_blank">database management</a>, <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2011/08/03/tutorial-exploring-json-usage-in-corona/ target="_blank">XML file management using JSON</a>, networking, <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2011/12/21/push-notifications-for-ios-in-corona-sdk/ target="_blank">push notification</a>, etc. are there to build other non-game apps.</p>
<p>So I think the real question is, what do you want Corona to do for you?</p>
<p><strong>Charles McKever</strong><br />
<a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/coronageek/ target="_blank">CoronaGeek</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/coronageek/is-the-corona-sdk-just-for-gaming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
