<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>monetization &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/monetization-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>monetization &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Using Kiip to increase user engagement and loyalty</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/11/30/using-kiip-to-increase-user-engagement-and-loyalty/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 17:07:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles McKeever]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News & Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plugins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rewarded ads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rewards]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=68989</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this special interview, Kabir Mathur, Head of Business Development for Kiip talks about how developers can take advantage of key moments in their game to deliver relevant, branded rewarded ads to players.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this special interview, Kabir Mathur, Head of Business Development for Kiip talks about how developers can <a href=/blog/2016/11/15/introducing-kiip-a-brighter-solution-for-monetization/>take advantage of key moments</a> in their game to deliver relevant, <a href=/blog/2016/11/15/introducing-kiip-a-brighter-solution-for-monetization/>branded rewarded ads</a> to players. As Kabir points out, Kiip isn’t just for games. Productivity and niche apps can use Kiips as well. Kabir also shares two ways developers are creating a sense of urgency when presenting rewards.</p>
<p><iframe width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xVFk7w38g9s?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Thank you for watching and listening!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Maximize app revenue with ironSource rewarded video and offerwalls</title>
		<link>/blog/coronageek/maximize-app-revenue-with-ironsource-rewarded-video-and-offerwalls/</link>
		<comments>/blog/coronageek/maximize-app-revenue-with-ironsource-rewarded-video-and-offerwalls/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 16:49:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles McKeever]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona Geek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google+ Hangouts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plugins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ironSource]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[offerwalls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rewareded video]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=coronageek&#038;p=68329</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this special Corona Geek podcast we talked with ironSource about the importance of reinvesting ad revenue back into app promotion to grow a user base and we discussed the merits of combing rewarded video and offerwalls to engage users and maximize earnings.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this special interview we talk with Garrett Olson about <a href=/blog/2016/05/17/introducing-supersonic-our-latest-monetization-plugin/>app monetization using ironSource</a>. Garrett talked about the importance of reinvesting ad revenue back into app promotion to grow an app&#8217;s user base. We also discussed the merits of combing the use of rewarded video and offerwalls to engage users and maximize earnings from your apps.</p>
<p>To get started, <a href=https://platform.supersonic.com/partners/signup target="_blank">sign up with ironSource</a>, then use the easy <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/supersonic/index.html>ironSource plugin for Corona SDK</a>.</p>
<p><iframe width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/q5cCZZJxrZc?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><img class="alignright wp-image-477" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/corona-geek-head-transparent-150x150.png" alt="Corona Geek" width="105" height="105" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/corona-geek-head-transparent-150x150.png 150w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/corona-geek-head-transparent.png 250w" sizes="(max-width: 105px) 100vw, 105px" /></p>
<p><strong>Promote Your Apps:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href=https://coronalabs.wufoo.com/forms/showcase-app-submission/ target="_blank">Add your app to the Corona Showcase</a></li>
<li><a href=https://coronalabs.wufoo.com/forms/case-study-app-submission/ target="_blank">Submit your app to be a Case Study candidate</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Thank you for watching, listening, and following Corona Geek:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href=http://bit.ly/H0dEgO target="_blank">Subscribe to Corona Geek on YouTube</a></li>
<li><a href=http://bit.ly/19JGUiG target="_blank">Download Corona Geek on iTunes</a></li>
<li><a href=http://on.fb.me/1EWdkLX target="_blank">Follow Corona Geek on Facebook</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/coronageek/maximize-app-revenue-with-ironsource-rewarded-video-and-offerwalls/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://corona-geek.s3.amazonaws.com/corona-geek-show-2016-09-15-ironsource.mp3" length="27533136" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing Kiip, a brighter solution for monetization</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/11/15/introducing-kiip-a-brighter-solution-for-monetization/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 20:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News & Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plugins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rewarded ads]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=68735</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Kiip is a new plugin that helps increase user engagement and loyalty by offering rewarded ads to users. Read on to learn how Kiip can increase app usage and user retention.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Corona Labs is pleased to announce the availability of a new monetization plugin for Corona developers. <a href=http://www.kiip.me/ target="_blank">Kiip</a> (pronounced &#8220;keep&#8221;) provides rewarded ad units that you can integrate into your app.</p>
<p>Typically presented at moments of in-game achievements, these types of ads are great for increasing user engagement and loyalty. According to Kiip, users who claim Kiip rewards tend to spend 68% more time in the app, more than doubling the length of a given session. Users open the app more often and apps show a 30% longer lifespan. Learn more about Kiip at <a href=http://www.kiip.me/ target="_blank">their website</a>.</p>
<p><a href=https://app.kiip.me/register target="_blank"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-68742" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Kiip-Lifestyle-Gaming-1024x768.jpg" alt="kiip-lifestyle-gaming" width="960" height="720" /></a></p>
<p><em>&#8220;Our objective at Kiip is to make the advertising experience rewarding for users. Kiip&#8217;s unique rewards model enables us to deliver industry leading eCPMs, while keeping users engaged with the app that they are in,&#8221;</em> says Kabir Mathur, Head of Business Development at Kiip. <em>&#8220;We&#8217;re very excited to bring our rewards to the sizable Corona developer community via this partnership with Corona Labs.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><a href=https://app.kiip.me/register target="_blank"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-68743" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Kiip-virtual-currency-reward-anatomy-1024x583.jpg" alt="kiip-virtual-currency-reward-anatomy" width="960" height="547" /></a></p>
<p>To integrate Kiip into your app, <a href=https://app.kiip.me/register target="_blank">sign up</a> to access their dashboard. Once your account is created, you can follow their <a href=http://docs.kiip.me/en/guide/corona.html target="_blank">documentation</a> to integrate Kiip into your Corona-built app. You must also include the plugin in your build.settings.</p>
<p><a href=https://app.kiip.me/register target="_blank"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-68849" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/getkiipcta.png" alt="getkiipcta" width="208" height="60" /></a></p>
<p>Join us in the <a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/forum/631-corona-premium-plugins/ target="_blank">Corona Forums</a> to discuss this wonderful addition to our family of monetization plugins.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing Appodeal: intelligent, programmatic ad mediation</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/08/04/introducing-appodeal-intelligent-programmatic-ad-mediation/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2016/08/04/introducing-appodeal-intelligent-programmatic-ad-mediation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 16:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plugins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mediation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plugin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revenue]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=67488</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Corona Labs is pleased to welcome Appodeal as our latest monetization plugin. This is our first plugin to offer complete ad mediation. Read further to learn more!]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/appodeal-3.png><img class="alignright wp-image-67639 size-thumbnail" style="margin: 16px 0px 10px 20px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/appodeal-3-150x150.png" width="150" height="150" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/appodeal-3-150x150.png 150w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/appodeal-3.png 194w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a></p>
<p>Ad mediation is a frequently requested app monetization feature, but it usually requires that you build in support for multiple ad networks in your app. That can be a lot of work.</p>
<p>Fortunately, <a href=https://www.appodeal.com/ target="_blank">Appodeal</a> builds their network of ad provider SDKs directly into their plugin for you &#8212; simply include the Appodeal plugin and get the benefit of every ad network they support.</p>
<p>One benefit of ad mediation is that you should get a 100% fill rate &#8212; never miss an ad! Appodeal&#8217;s service delivers higher-paying ads first, and they also analyze all of the ads available, factor in the user&#8217;s behavior, and find the best ad for the moment.</p>
<p>You just need one account and one plugin (plus support plugins on Android) to benefit from all of Appodeal&#8217;s partners. They offer monthly payouts as well as on-demand payouts.</p>
<p>&#8220;Appodeal is excited about our new partnership with Corona Labs, as it will open new doors and break the many restrictions developers often face. We look forward to helping Corona developers monetize their apps with ease while maximizing their earnings,&#8221; says Pavel Golubev, Appodeal CEO &amp; Founder.</p>
<h3>Getting started</h3>
<p>To begin, <a href=https://www.appodeal.com/ target="_blank">register with Appodeal</a>. Then, create an app for each platform you want to run ads on. Currently the Corona plugin supports iOS, Android, and tvOS. You will get a different application key for each platform. Finally, include the required changes in your <code>build.settings</code> file and implement the plugin much like any other Corona ad provider (see our <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/appodeal/index.html target="_blank">documentation</a> for details).</p>
<p>The Appodeal plugin offers three API calls: <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/appodeal/init.html target="_blank">appodeal.init()</a>, <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/appodeal/show.html target="_blank">appodeal.show()</a>, and <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/appodeal/hide.html target="_blank">appodeal.hide()</a>. If you are deploying your app to both iOS and Android,  you will have to initialize your plugin based on platform:</p><pre class="crayon-plain-tag">if &quot;Android&quot; == system.getInfo( &quot;platformName&quot; ) then
    appodeal.init( adListener, { appKey=&quot;YOUR_ANDROID_APPLICATION_KEY&quot;, testMode=false } )
else
    appodeal.init( adListener, { appKey=&quot;YOUR_IOS_APPLICATION_KEY&quot;, testMode=false } )
end</pre><p>See the Corona <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/appodeal/index.html target="_blank">documentation</a> for more usage details.</p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>Have any questions or comments? To discuss this wonderful addition to our suite of monetization plugins, please join us in the Corona <a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/forum/631-corona-premium-plugins/ target="_blank">community forums</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2016/08/04/introducing-appodeal-intelligent-programmatic-ad-mediation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing Peanut Labs – monetization through surveys</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/08/02/introducing-peanut-labs-monetization-through-surveys/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 22:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plugins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peanut labs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[survey]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=67504</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Corona Labs is pleased to announce the availability of the Peanut Labs plugin, a survey-based monetization option. Click to learn more!]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-67508" style="margin: 10px 0px 10px 20px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/pl-logo1.png" alt="pl-logo1" width="146" height="56" />A growing trend in app monetization is rewarding users for their time. We have seen rewarded video plugins, but there are other ways to engage your customers. Enter <a href=http://web.peanutlabs.com/ target="_blank">Peanut Labs</a>, a monetization solution which lets your users take surveys from popular brands. You can reward your customers with virtual currency for taking the survey and you get paid for doing so. Your users will find a new and free way to earn credits every single day while having a quality customer experience.</p>
<p>&#8220;We are thrilled to partner with Corona Labs to boost the monetization opportunity for its developer community which will help app developers create extra revenue’’ says Noman Ali, Co-Founder and CEO of Peanut Labs.</p>
<h3>Implementing Peanut Labs</h3>
<p>Implementing the Peanut Labs plugin is pretty straightforward. Include the plugin in <code>build.settings</code>, <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/peanutlabs/init.html target="_blank">initialize</a> it, and call the <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/peanutlabs/show.html target="_blank">show()</a> method. Of course, you will first need to <a href=https://www.peanutlabs.com/js/pubdash/bin/?#/register/company target="_blank">apply for a developer account</a> with Peanut Labs. Once they approve your account, you can log into their <a href=https://www.peanutlabs.com/js/pubdash/bin/index.php target="_blank">dashboard</a> and start setting up your app. You will need an <code>appKey</code> and an <code>appId</code> which can be found in the dashboard. In addition, you will need to provide a unique <code>userId</code> for each user. Rewards are tied to this ID. It&#8217;s just a string to them, so it can be any format in your app, but it needs to be unique. One option is to use a person&#8217;s Facebook ID, an email address, or some other ID.</p>
<p>There is a <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/peanutlabs/server.html target="_blank">server-side requirement</a> to use the Peanut Labs plugin. When you show a survey, the user will either be allowed to participate or they will be screened out due to demographics, previously completed surveys, etc. When the results are known, Peanut Labs servers will call a web script that you host on your web server. How you write that script and set up your database is completely up to you, since they expect you to have a server-based economy system in place. If you don&#8217;t, we have included a basic PHP script to handle their callback needs, in addition to a MySQL statement to create the table. Most web hosting providers offer MySQL databases and the ability to execute PHP scripts. See our <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/peanutlabs/server.html target="_blank">documentation</a> for these example scripts.</p>
<h4>Completing the transaction</h4>
<p>If the user completes the survey, you need to reward currency. But even if the user was screened out, they should still get a small reward. This encourages the user to try again another time, so when they do successfully complete a survey, you earn the revenue. After a survey attempt, Peanut Labs will update your server with information about the transaction. The data will indicate survey completion status, the amount of money you made, and an amount of virtual currency to give your user. You need to get that information to your app.</p>
<p>By their design, you should query your database, find that user&#8217;s information, and have your app react to the information found. Their system is set to work with games that drive an app&#8217;s full economic system on a server, so having the ability to inject the information into your system makes sense. However, if your app is not server-connected, you still need the information in your app. We&#8217;ve provided an additional PHP script which will query your database for the most recent entry from Peanut Labs. You can access this with <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/library/network/request.html target="_blank">network.request()</a>:</p><pre class="crayon-plain-tag">local json = require( &quot;json&quot; )

local function getResultListener( event )
    if not event.isError then
        local result = json.decode( event.response )
        print( json.prettify( result ) )
        local currencyAmt = result.currencyAmount
    end
end

local URL = &quot;https://yourserver.com/path/to/getresult.php?userId=&quot; .. yourUserId
network.request( URL, &quot;GET&quot;, getResultListener )</pre><p>Using this, you can compare the time stamp in the result with the current time using <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/library/os/time.html target="_blank">os.time()</a>. If they are in close proximity to each other, it&#8217;s probably the transaction for the most recent survey completed. In this case, you can process the rewards.</p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>Peanut Labs is a different kind of monetization tool that you can add to your arsenal. To learn more, visit their website and read our <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/peanutlabs/index.html target="_blank">documentation</a> and, if you have any further questions, please contact the Peanut Labs Team at <a href=mailto:publishers@peanutlabs.com>publishers@peanutlabs.com</a>. Join us in the <a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/forum/631-corona-premium-plugins/ target="_blank">forums</a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcome Pollfish! Earn money with polls in your app</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/07/27/welcome-pollfish-earn-money-with-polls-in-your-app/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 22:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plugins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plugin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surveys]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=67512</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Corona Labs is pleased to announce the availability of the Pollfish plugin. This plugin lets you include polls and surveys in your app. Read on to learn more.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Pollfish_logo-1.png><img class="alignright wp-image-67526 size-thumbnail" style="margin: 0px 0px 20px 20px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Pollfish_logo-1-150x150.png" alt="Pollfish_logo" width="150" height="150" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Pollfish_logo-1-150x150.png 150w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Pollfish_logo-1-300x300.png 300w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Pollfish_logo-1.png 360w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a>Corona Labs is pleased to announce the availability of our Pollfish plugin. <a href=https://www.pollfish.com/ target="_blank">Pollfish</a> allows you to earn money by displaying surveys/polls in your apps and it can be used along with other ad platforms to create an additional revenue stream. In addition to showing others&#8217; polls to monetize, you can create your own polls to collect feedback from your own audience.</p>
<p>Andreas Vourkos, Co-Founder &amp; COO of Pollfish, says &#8220;here at Pollfish we are proud to announce our latest partnership with Corona Labs. This new partnership will give Corona publishers access to Pollfish surveys, one of the most trending and high-paying solutions available in the app monetization field.</p>
<p>&#8220;Pollfish is a survey network providing a DIY survey tool on its website in order for anyone to easily create a survey, select a target audience, pay and get results in a few hours. These surveys are distributed through the Pollfish app publishers’ network.</p>
<p>&#8220;Corona publishers can integrate Pollfish surveys in their app quickly and easily, since no changes to the app’s UI are needed and surveys are displayed as an overlay. Users responding to surveys enter into drawings for prizes (satisfied customers!) without leaving the app environment to complete them. Publishers get paid up to 20x more compared to traditional advertising solutions and also gain access to the Pollfish DIY tool to survey their users for free, without any time limits, and thus get valuable feedback from their own users.&#8221;</p>
<h3>Getting started</h3>
<p>Start by <a href=https://www.pollfish.com/publisher target="_blank">signing up for an account</a> with Pollfish and setting up your app in their dashboard. After you set up your first app, you will get an API key. You will have separate app and API keys for both iOS and Android versions.</p>
<p>Setting up for your app is similar to other plugins. You can learn about all of the API calls and setup information in our <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/pollfish/index.html target="_blank">documentation</a>. One call that is relatively unique to Pollfish is <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/pollfish/setUserDetails.html target="_blank">pollfish.setUserDetails()</a>. This gives you a chance to tell Pollfish more about your app&#8217;s user which could lead to higher-performing polls. Just be aware that if you collect this information and provide it to Pollfish, you should have a user-facing privacy policy explaining what you&#8217;re collecting and sharing.</p>
<h3>Wrapping up</h3>
<p>Pollfish is a great way to engage your audience and help you earn more money for your apps! Join us in the <a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/forum/631-corona-premium-plugins/ target="_blank">forums</a> to discuss the plugin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Looking for beta developers to test Appodeal plugin</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/07/19/looking-for-beta-developers-to-test-appodeal-plugin/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2016/07/19/looking-for-beta-developers-to-test-appodeal-plugin/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 17:10:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plugins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mediation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plugin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revenue]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=67492</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Corona Labs is looking for some developers to help us test a new monetization plugin from Appodeal. Learn how you can join the beta test program for it.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright wp-image-67490 size-medium" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/appodeal_logo-300x67.jpg" width="300" height="67" />Corona Labs is working on a plugin for <a href=https://www.appodeal.com/ target="_blank">Appodeal</a>, a monetization partner that supports mediation.</p>
<p>We are looking for a few developers to test the plugin. If you&#8217;re interested in getting an early look at the plugin and helping us test, please email <a href=mailto:ads@coronalabs.com>ads@coronalabs.com</a> from your registered Corona developer email. Please include the app you would like to integrate and the daily active users (DAU) for that app. We will get back with you if you&#8217;re selected.</p>
<p>We look forward to hearing from you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2016/07/19/looking-for-beta-developers-to-test-appodeal-plugin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monetize kids apps using the KIDOZ plugin for Corona SDK</title>
		<link>/blog/coronageek/monetize-kids-apps-using-the-kidoz-plugin-for-corona-sdk/</link>
		<comments>/blog/coronageek/monetize-kids-apps-using-the-kidoz-plugin-for-corona-sdk/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 18:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles McKeever]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona Geek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google+ Hangouts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App Monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COPPA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kids apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetization]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?post_type=coronageek&#038;p=67482</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On this week's Corona Geek podcast, Noah Malewicz showed the panel how to add visual depth and interest to character animations while reducing the number of sprite sheets needed, using Spine and meshes.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this special Corona Geek podcast we talked with Eldad Ben Tora at KIDOZ about their <a href=/blog/2016/06/01/introducing-kidoz-a-coppa-compliant-monetization-plugin/>COPPA compliant kids app monetization solution</a> and how the company went from being an app to providing full service to developers. We talked about the challenges children&#8217;s app developers face and how KIDOZ filters content to ensure that parents, kids, advertisers, and developers are all happy.</p>
<p><iframe width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2tAi0NNU6xw?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><img class="alignright wp-image-477" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/corona-geek-head-transparent-150x150.png" alt="Corona Geek" width="105" height="105" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/corona-geek-head-transparent-150x150.png 150w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/corona-geek-head-transparent.png 250w" sizes="(max-width: 105px) 100vw, 105px" /></p>
<p><strong>Promote Your Apps:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href=https://coronalabs.wufoo.com/forms/showcase-app-submission/ target="_blank">Add your app to the Corona Showcase</a></li>
<li><a href=https://coronalabs.wufoo.com/forms/case-study-app-submission/ target="_blank">Submit your app to be a Case Study candidate</a></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Thank you for watching, listening, and following Corona Geek:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href=http://bit.ly/H0dEgO target="_blank">Subscribe to Corona Geek on YouTube</a></li>
<li><a href=http://bit.ly/19JGUiG target="_blank">Download Corona Geek on iTunes</a></li>
<li><a href=http://on.fb.me/1EWdkLX target="_blank">Follow Corona Geek on Facebook</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/coronageek/monetize-kids-apps-using-the-kidoz-plugin-for-corona-sdk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://corona-geek.s3.amazonaws.com/corona-geek-2016-07-14-kidoz-interview.mp3" length="25737998" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing SuperAwesome &#8211; kid-friendly monetization for Corona apps</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/07/12/introducing-superawesome-kid-friendly-monetization-for-corona-apps/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 16:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News & Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[COPPA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kids apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetization]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=67024</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Corona Labs is pleased to announce our latest monetization plugin for kids app. SuperAwesome is a great plugin for you to integrate in your family friendly games and apps. Learn more in this announcement.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright wp-image-67426" style="margin: 8px 0px 10px 20px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/large_superawesome_1500px-300x35.png" alt="large_superawesome_1500px" width="240" height="28" />If you make apps for kids, you know that data privacy laws like <a href=https://www.kidsafeseal.com/knowaboutcoppa.html target="_blank">COPPA</a> in the U.S. and <a href=https://blog.superawesome.tv/2016/04/21/gdpr-passes-into-law-what-this-means-for-kids-marketing-in-europe/ target="_blank">GDPR</a> in Europe have strict guidelines on how you can monetize. Because of this, we are pleased to welcome the <a href=http://www.superawesome.tv/en/ target="_blank">SuperAwesome</a> &#8220;AwesomeAds&#8221; platform to our growing repertoire of monetization plugins. What makes them special? SuperAwesome’s platform is built specifically for the data-privacy requirements of the under-13 demographic.</p>
<p>AwesomeAds matches top kids&#8217; brands like LEGO, Disney, and Hasbro with exciting and relevant content owners, delivering high-performing brand campaigns to kids worldwide. As well as being fully COPPA-compliant, every ad campaign goes through SuperAwesome’s industry-standard content review procedure to ensure it’s 100% kid-safe.</p>
<p>We reached out to SuperAwesome’s Chief Product Officer, Joshua Wohle, for his comments on the Corona plugin: &#8220;Through developing AwesomeAds, we are constantly defining new, easier ways for publishers to increase revenue whilst ensuring a 100% kid-safe environment. We’re excited to open up our plugin to Corona developers, allowing them to focus on creating amazing new apps and digital experiences for kids, whilst SuperAwesome helps monetize their efforts in a safe and effective way.&#8221;</p>
<h3>Getting started</h3>
<p>Before you can use their ads, you must register in the SuperAwesome <a href=http://dashboard.superawesome.tv/ target="_blank">developer portal</a>. After that, you will need to include the plugin in your <code>build.settings</code>, <code>main.lua</code> and other <code>.lua</code> files where you need to access the APIs. SuperAwesome uses similar API calls to other ad providers and you can learn about them in our <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/superawesome/index.html target="_blank">SuperAwesome documentation</a>.</p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>SuperAwesome&#8217;s &#8220;AwesomeAds&#8221; is a 100% kid-safe solution for ad monetization in your kids&#8217; apps and it’s really simple to use. To find out more, see our <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/superawesome/index.html target="_blank">documentation</a>, and if you have any further questions, please visit the <a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/forum/631-corona-premium-plugins/ target="_blank">Corona forums</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing Persona.ly, an offer wall plugin for Corona</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/06/28/introducing-persona-ly-an-offer-wall-plugin-for-corona/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 19:58:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plugins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[offer wall]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=67157</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Corona Labs is pleased to announce the availability of the Persona.ly plugin. Learn more about this plugin and how you can use it to improve your app's monetization.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="size-full wp-image-67297 alignright" style="max-width: 200px; margin: 4px 0px 15px 25px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/personaly.png" alt="personaly" width="400" height="145" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/personaly.png 400w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/personaly-300x109.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 400px) 100vw, 400px" />In today&#8217;s app ecosystem, it can be challenging to get your users to engage with your monetization sources. Rewarding the user for their time is a popular way to improve engagement.</p>
<p>We have several plugins that support rewarded videos (watch a video, get in-app goodies). Another way to engage users is with an <strong>offer wall</strong>. Offer walls provide the user an opportunity to do something &#8211; take a survey, install another app, sign up for a magazine, provide some personal information, etc. In exchange, the user gets rewarded with some form of in-app currency like gems, coins, tokens, credits, etc.</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-67333" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/Mobile_Demo1-300x251.png" alt="Mobile_Demo(1)" width="300" height="251" />Along these lines, Corona Labs is pleased to announce <a href=http://persona.ly/ target="_blank">Persona.ly</a>, a plugin that lets you implement offer walls in your app. In contrast to many monetization partners, Persona.ly is a &#8220;white glove&#8221; service &#8212; when you register with them, you will get assigned an account manager who will guide you through the setup and other requirements for using this plugin.</p>
<h3>Implementation</h3>
<p>Using Persona.ly in your Corona app is very similar to most other monetization plugins. First, you will need to include the plugin code in your <code>build.settings</code>. Then, in your Lua modules, <code>require()</code> and <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/plugin/personaly/init.html target="_blank">init()</a> the plugin using an <strong>app hash</strong> that you get from Persona.ly, along with a unique ID for the user. From there, it&#8217;s simply a matter of calling the <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/plugin/personaly/show.html target="_blank">show()</a> method to display an offer wall in your app.</p>
<p>Because Persona.ly is a more hands-on service, there are a couple of additional requirements. First, you have to provide a unique ID for each user, and it&#8217;s up to you to determine and keep track of that unique ID. This ID is passed as part of the <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/plugin/personaly/init.html target="_blank">init()</a> call. You also need to set up a server that their servers can talk to. Your Persona.ly account manager can help you with these aspects.</p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>Persona.ly is a great way to increase your app&#8217;s earning potential. You can learn more about Persona.ly from <a href=http://persona.ly/ target="_blank">their website</a>. For more information on the Corona implementation, see our <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/plugin/personaly/index.html target="_blank">documentation</a>, and if you have further questions, please visit the Corona <a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/forum/631-corona-premium-plugins/ target="_blank">forums</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
