<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Composer &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/topics/composer-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Composer &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>State of Corona: Thoughts and Reflections 2015</title>
		<link>/blog/2015/01/30/state-of-corona-thoughts-and-reflections-2015/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2015/01/30/state-of-corona-thoughts-and-reflections-2015/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2015 18:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[walter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Composer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona Editor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona native builds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CoronaCards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News & Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plugins]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=60991</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A lot has happened in the past year, so let's talk about where we've been and where we're headed in 2015.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A lot has happened in the past year, so let&#8217;s talk about where we&#8217;ve been and where we&#8217;re headed.</p>
<p>The biggest thing that happened was that we were acquired by <a href=http://fusepowered.com>Fuse/ Powered</a>. We&#8217;re all really happy to be part of the Fuse family. It sounds cliché but there couldn&#8217;t be a better cultural fit. The more we interact, the more it feels like we&#8217;ve all been working together for a lot longer — and having been through a couple of other acquisitions, that actually is a pretty big deal.</p>
<p>As I&#8217;ve mentioned before, Fuse&#8217;s products help developers make more money. Right now, we&#8217;re in a small pilot with a small group of Corona developers. We want to make sure the Fuse/Corona integration is rock solid and battle-tested before we open the doors to everyone.</p>
<p>On the Corona and product side there are lots of highlights, including CoronaCards, Windows Phone 8 support, debugging introspection, CoronaViewer, Composer API, Composer GUI Beta, Particle Designer support, and much more. These were all great additions to the Corona platform and we continue to work on them.</p>
<h3>Looking ahead</h3>
<p>Now, as I look ahead, I&#8217;m incredibly excited about where Corona is headed this year, so I&#8217;d thought I&#8217;d share the direction we&#8217;re taking this year.</p>
<p>Before we dive in, I should emphasize that this is not a roadmap. I&#8217;ve previously discussed our thoughts on <a href=http://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/52439-fuse-acquires-corona/?p=272367>why we don&#8217;t do roadmaps</a> (and neither do other companies, at least not successfully) as well as our strong bias to talk about what we&#8217;ve actually delivered.</p>
<p>So instead, I&#8217;ll touch on some of our thinking around four different themes where we will be doing significant work:</p>
<ul>
<li>Platforms</li>
<li>Plugins</li>
<li>Graphics</li>
<li>Workflow</li>
</ul>
<p>And in keeping with our philosophy, I&#8217;ll talk about our approach and direction, holding off on specifics until I have concrete news to share.</p>
<h3>Platforms</h3>
<p><a href=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/platform-logos.png><img src=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/platform-logos.png alt="platform logos" width="108" height="40" class="alignright size-full wp-image-60995" /></a>Corona has been designed to be portable and cross-platform, but that doesn&#8217;t mean there aren&#8217;t challenges in supporting new platforms. There&#8217;s a lot of effort to support an initial port, and a continuing cost to support OS updates and new hardware for that OS.</p>
<p>That complexity is compounded by the sheer amount of features in Corona SDK. In this context, it only makes sense to target platforms with iOS/Android-level market traction.</p>
<p>So how do we square the circle?</p>
<p>We think the way forward is to simplify, as we did with Windows Phone 8. Support for new platforms becomes a lot more feasible if we only have to commit to a core set of features, leaving out ancillary feature and/or services.</p>
<h3>Plugins</h3>
<p><a href=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/plugin-icon.png><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/plugin-icon-150x131.png" alt="plugin icon" width="150" height="131" class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-60996" /></a>When we first introduced plugins, we architected it to be optimized for distribution. A plugin could be hosted on our server and be made available instantly to all Corona developers.</p>
<p>Originally, we focused on 3rd parties that wanted to offer their services to the Corona community via these plugins.</p>
<p>Today, we recognize that we could do more to make this more open. So our goal is to broaden the types of folks who can offer their plugins to the entire Corona community. At the same time, there are some key steps we need to take to help would-be plugin writers, especially resources focused on learning by example.</p>
<h3>Graphics</h3>
<p><a href=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/2Dvenndiagram.png><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/2Dvenndiagram-150x144.png" alt="2Dvenndiagram" width="150" height="144" class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-60997" /></a>Our vision for 2D graphics has always been very ambitious. With our graphics engine, we&#8217;ve vastly simplified how you achieve numerous visual effects intuitively and efficiently on modern GPU&#8217;s.</p>
<p>This is all possible thanks to a lot of insightful and clever work under the hood. However, we&#8217;ve limited what you can do to what&#8217;s available in our API. In other words, we still haven&#8217;t taken full advantage of what our engine can offer.</p>
<p>One reason we took a conservative approach was that GPU support was not consistent. We&#8217;ve rewritten our shaders numerous times to work around driver-specific bugs in the shader compiler — in some cases, basic GLSL language features did not work on certain GPU&#8217;s.</p>
<p>Nowadays there&#8217;s just a little less fragmentation (hopefully), so we think the time is ripe to start opening up our graphics system. This means giving you more control and more techniques to extend beyond what we&#8217;ve done. We&#8217;ll also keep an eye out for obvious, missing gaps in the API.</p>
<h3>Workflow</h3>
<p><a href=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/shortcut-thru-maze.png><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/shortcut-thru-maze-150x108.png" alt="shortcut thru maze" width="150" height="108" class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-60999" /></a>We&#8217;ve always been very proud of Corona&#8217;s incredibly simple workflow. By eliminating complexity and the associated learning curves, we helped save you time and hopefully enabled you to find a little more delight in your day-to-day development.</p>
<p>With Corona&#8217;s Lua API, you can put images on the screen and interact with them with just a few lines of code. With Corona Simulator, you can test our your ideas rapidly and in real-time. With Corona Editor, you&#8217;re focusing on editing code without worrying about how to navigate a confusing IDE.</p>
<p>We think there&#8217;s a lot more to do here. Our work, for example, on Composer GUI and CoronaViewer is far from finished.</p>
<p><center>* * *</center></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve focused a lot on what we&#8217;re doing with Corona specifically, and only briefly touched on what the combination of Corona and Fuse will achieve together. Corona&#8217;s strength is helping you turn your ideas into working realities, building your apps faster. Fuse&#8217;s strength is enabling you to convert your apps into financially-viable realities, monetizing your apps better.</p>
<p>So the direction we&#8217;re taking collectively is guided by the same principle that I&#8217;ve expressed many times before — your success is our success.</p>
<h4><span style="font-family: serif; font-style: italic;">Walter</span></h4>
<p>&nbsp;<br />
&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2015/01/30/state-of-corona-thoughts-and-reflections-2015/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Composer GUI Beta Update</title>
		<link>/blog/2014/06/11/composer-gui-beta-update/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2014/06/11/composer-gui-beta-update/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 23:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[walter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Composer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Build]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News & Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[composer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GUI editor]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=58796</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today, we have a new update to our visual editor Composer GUI, available in daily build 2014.2332. 

This update makes significant improvements over the <a href="/blog/2014/04/17/composer-gui-beta/">previous beta</a>. We've focused on polishing the existing feature set as well as improve your workflow. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, we have a new update to our visual editor Composer GUI, available in daily build 2014.2332 (Mac only for now). </p>
<p>This update makes significant improvements over the <a href=/blog/2014/04/17/composer-gui-beta/>previous beta</a>. We&#8217;ve focused on polishing the existing feature set as well as improve your workflow. Several key features were missing like resizable windows, full-screen mode, zooming in/out, and multiple selection (marquee or shift-click). Plus, all Pro subscribers can start using the Composer GUI right away, no need to enable it in the terminal as required in the previous version.</p>
<p>We also focused on lots of small things that you don&#8217;t notice until they&#8217;re missing. For example, if you&#8217;re a long-time user of Adobe products, you&#8217;re used to quickly toggling the hand tool by holding down the spacebar. In the latest Composer GUI, you&#8217;ll be able to do the same thing.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a short preview of what you can do in the updated Composer GUI:</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/tfyg-MYz3-g" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re ready to play, here&#8217;s a <a href=https://github.com/coronalabs/aliens-vs-mutant-mice-final>sample</a> you can use with the latest daily build, the same one we use in the video. And as always, more information is available in our <a href=http://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/composer/>docs</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2014/06/11/composer-gui-beta-update/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Composer GUI Beta</title>
		<link>/blog/2014/04/17/composer-gui-beta/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2014/04/17/composer-gui-beta/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 14:49:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[walter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Composer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Build]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[composer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GUI editor]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=58258</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today, we are seeding out a new product that we call the "Composer GUI", a visual editor that allows you to rapidly create scenes, user interfaces, and game levels! 

Read on to learn more.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[UPDATE: A new <a href=/blog/2014/06/11/composer-gui-beta-update/>Composer GUI Beta</a> is now available]</p>
<p>Today, we are seeding out a new product that we call the &#8220;Composer GUI&#8221;, a visual editor that allows you to rapidly create scenes, user interfaces, and game levels! </p>
<p>It allows you to visually design in a drag-and-drop GUI interface. And as the name suggests, the Composer GUI is designed to work in conjunction with the Composer API.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a quick video to give you a sense for what you&#8217;ll be able to do with the Composer GUI:</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/K8zLU-2wtYQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>In addition, we designed the Composer GUI to be an integrated part of Corona Simulator. When you edit scenes in Composer, the Simulator automatically refreshes just like when you edit/save Lua files. You&#8217;ll also be able to preview individual scenes within Composer itself for even faster iteration.</p>
<p>As you can see, there are lots of great features. For example, timeline animation and physics body editing will dramatically speed up your app development. We envision Composer GUI being used in many different ways: </p>
<ul>
<li>First, it makes Corona even more accessible by allowing people with no coding experience to get up and running very quickly.</li>
<li>Second, it allows experienced developers to design UIs or levels in a fast and visual way and then refine/augment by further coding.</li>
<li>Third, it improves team workflow by allowing members like designers to lay a scene out visually before passing it on to developers. </li>
</ul>
<h4>Early Beta Access</h4>
<p>Before I tell you how to get access, I want to mention that the Composer GUI is very much a work in progress. It&#8217;s beta, but a really early beta. So even though we&#8217;ve integrated it into the daily builds, it won&#8217;t be visible by default. It&#8217;s something you&#8217;ll have to &#8220;unlock&#8221;.</p>
<p>To play with (and unlock) Composer GUI, you&#8217;ll need to have a Pro (or higher) subscription:</p>
<ol>
<li>Download <a href=http://developer.coronalabs.com/downloads/daily-builds>daily build</a> 2014.2264 (Mac only for now)</li>
<li>In Terminal, run the following command:
<ul>
<li>
<pre class="crayon-plain-tag">defaults write com.coronalabs.Corona_Simulator enableExtensions -bool YES</pre>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Run the Corona Simulator and you&#8217;ll see an option for &#8216;Corona Composer&#8217; on the Welcome window. It&#8217;s also accessible from the menu: &#8216;Window&#8217; => &#8216;Corona Composer&#8217;.</li>
</ol>
<h4>Docs</h4>
<p>The best way to get up to speed is to go through the <a href=http://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/composer/tutorial.html>tutorial walkthrough</a> which parallels the video, and shows you how to take a <a href=https://github.com/coronalabs/aliens-vs-mutant-mice>starter project</a> and turn it into a really cool <a href=https://github.com/coronalabs/aliens-vs-mutant-mice-final>sample</a>.</p>
<p>A list of known issues is available at the bottom of the preliminary <a href=http://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/composer/>Composer GUI docs site</a>.</p>
<h4>Feedback</h4>
<p>We&#8217;ve created a special <a href=http://forums.coronalabs.com/forum/636-composer-gui-beta-testing/>forum</a> for your feedback/comments.</p>
<p>
The Composer GUI furthers our vision of making Corona the tool of choice for designing, developing and distributing rich interactive content. It is still very early in its lifecycle, but we are looking forward to seeing how you use it and to your feedback!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2014/04/17/composer-gui-beta/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>38</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
