<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>iCloud &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/icloud/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>iCloud &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>From the Forum — Issue #117</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/04/01/from-the-forum-issue-117/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 17:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[From the Forum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GPS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iCloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[KVS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[locationServices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pasteboard]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=66340</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Welcome to the latest installment of From the Forum. In this series, guest blogger Alex Jackson highlights outstanding threads from the Corona Forum. The goal is to bring attention to the most captivating, interesting, and thought-provoking discussions taking place in our very own backyard.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-54943" style="margin: 0px 0px 10px 10px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Icon_Resources_Forum.png" alt="From the Forum" /><em>Welcome to the latest installment of <strong>From the Forum</strong>. In <em>this series</em>, guest blogger Alex Jackson highlights outstanding threads from the <a href=http://forum.coronalabs.com>Corona/ Forum</a>. The goal is to bring attention to the most captivating, interesting, and thought-provoking discussions taking place in our very own backyard.</em></p>
<p><em>Please <a href=http://forum.coronalabs.com>visit/ the forum</a> to join these conversations or start your own!</em></p>
<hr />
<h3>Copy and paste across the board</h3>
<p>We all know about the pasteboard plugin and how useful it is on mobile devices. Since Corona apps exist in the OpenGL layer, it’s necessary to use an additional Corona-provided plugin in order to get intuitive “copy and paste” into our mobile apps.</p>
<p>The next hurdle for natural copy and paste is our desktop apps. It’s arguably even more important for our programs to have some of the basic functionality that uses expect from applications running on OSX and Windows. The thing is, the pasteboard plugin is only supported on iOS and Android!</p>
<p>Fortunately, the below thread has us covered. There are some very useful code snippets that enable this simple desktop functionality. Click through to check it out now!</p>
<p><a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/62377-copy-and-paste-on-win32-desktop-osx-builds/ target="_blank">https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/62377-copy-and-paste-on-win32-desktop-osx-builds/</a></p>
<h3>Accurate GPS on your device</h3>
<p>Getting pinpoint GPS coordinates is a difficult task for any developer, Corona or otherwise. The handshake agreement between the app and the user is of vital importance, as every setting need to be configured correctly to get the results your app expects.</p>
<p>In the below thread, Corona support engineer Rob Miracle tells us about the pitfalls and provides some pointers when it comes to collecting GPS values on your mobile device. Head on down to check it out now!</p>
<p><a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/60254-making-gps-as-accurate-as-possible/ target="_blank">https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/60254-making-gps-as-accurate-as-possible/</a></p>
<h3>Use iCloud KVS right now!</h3>
<p>Now that tvOS has been opened up to Corona development, we have quite a few decisions to make about how we are going to port and/or develop on this platform. There is plenty of new functionality to take advantage, and not just related to the awesome new remote control.</p>
<p>The main issue that we are encountering is enabling the back-up of data, be it for saved games, or a persistent playlist. Since tvOS doesn’t allow us to save data to the device, we have to get creative. Using iCloud storage is one of the more intuitive methods, and I say that more so in regards to the ease in which a user would interact with it, rather than the methods a developer would take to get it to work correctly in a project. Those steps are a bit more involved, but thank goodness we have the below thread to which we can refer.</p>
<p>A Corona engineer and a developer were kicking the tires for us on Corona versions, and were able to come to a conclusion on the working order for iCloud KVS integration. Roll through to the original thread to read up on their convo and how you can get iCloud storage working on tvOS with minimal fuss!</p>
<p><a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/62249-icloud-kvs-between-ios-and-osx-app/ target="_blank">https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/62249-icloud-kvs-between-ios-and-osx-app/</a></p>
<h4>About Alex</h4>
<p>Alex Jackson is an indie developer and the founder of <a href=http://www.panc.co/ target="_blank">Panc Interactive</a>, specializing in retro-style gaming. He has created several mobile applications, enjoys long walks on the beach, pixel art, and reading the Corona forums. Contact him by <a href=mailto:alex@panc.co>email</a> or follow him on Twitter: <a href=http://twitter.com/pancinteractive>@pancinteractive</a>. Check out his new game <a href=http://www.panc.co/segreta-download-page.html target="_blank">Segreta</a> on iOS, Android, Windows Phone and Amazon devices.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Announcing OS X, tvOS updates, and the new iCloud plugin!</title>
		<link>/blog/2015/12/18/announcing-os-x-tvos-updates-and-the-new-icloud-plugin/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2015/12/18/announcing-os-x-tvos-updates-and-the-new-icloud-plugin/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News & Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OS-X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plugins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tvOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iCloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[release]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=64961</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The holiday season is upon us and once again the Corona engineering team is in a festive mood. This season they have been hard at work on OS X builds, tvOS builds, and the new iCloud plugin.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The holiday season is upon us and once again the Corona engineering team is in a festive mood. This season they have been hard at work giving us some exciting new features and platforms to explore.</p>
<h3>OS X initial release</h3>
<p>As of <a href=https://developer.coronalabs.com/downloads/daily-builds/ target="_blank">Daily Build 2015.2795</a>, we are proud to announce that OS X is no longer in beta! We have the core features working at a level where we feel comfortable encouraging you to release apps to the Mac App store. Platforms like this are never complete and there are more features to add, but this marks a stable point in OS X development where we think you can successfully deploy desktop apps for Mac. To learn more, see our <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/guide/distribution/osxBuild/index.html target="_blank">Creating OS X Desktop Apps</a> guide.</p>
<h3>tvOS now in beta</h3>
<p>Additionally, we are removing the &#8220;alpha&#8221; label from our <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/guide/tvos/index.html target="_blank">tvOS support</a>. We believe that you should be able to publish apps to iTunes Connect for tvOS. Of course there is more to do before we can mark this as fully released, but the core features are now in place. You can pick this up in <a href=https://developer.coronalabs.com/downloads/daily-builds/ target="_blank">Daily Build 2015.2795</a> as well. To learn more, check out our <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/guide/tvos/index.html target="_blank">Apple TV and tvOS guide</a>.</p>
<h3>The iCloud plugin (beta)</h3>
<p>We are also pleased to announce the immediate availability of the new <a href=https://store.coronalabs.com/plugin/iCloud target="_blank">iCloud plugin</a>. This plugin lets you store various data types in Apple&#8217;s iCloud service. The three main types of data you can store are:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Key-Value Storage</strong> &#8212; This lets you store simple data values like numbers, strings, and tables.</li>
<li><strong>Documents</strong> &#8212; This lets you develop apps where you can save whole files to the cloud and sync them with other devices.</li>
<li><strong>CloudKit</strong> &#8212; This is a full database implementation where you can have public and private database implementations which your app can access from multiple devices.</li>
</ul>
<p>In its simplest use, iCloud (all three methods) lets you save data from your app to iCloud and retrieve it later when you need it. In addition, if you have your app installed on multiple devices, for example your iPhone and iPad, the app can share data.</p>
<p>To get started with the <a href=https://store.coronalabs.com/plugin/iCloud target="_blank">iCloud plugin</a>, see the <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/plugin/iCloud/index.html target="_blank">documentation</a> and our <a href=/blog/2015/12/18/tutorial-implementing-icloud-key-value-storage/ target="_blank">first tutorial</a>.</p>
<h3>Get started!</h3>
<p>With this progress on both OS X desktop builds and tvOS builds, now is a great time to consider additional platforms for your existing apps!</p>
<hr />
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2015/12/18/announcing-os-x-tvos-updates-and-the-new-icloud-plugin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tutorial: Using iCloud Key-Value Storage</title>
		<link>/blog/2015/12/18/tutorial-implementing-icloud-key-value-storage/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2015/12/18/tutorial-implementing-icloud-key-value-storage/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Plugins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tutorials, Tips and Demos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iCloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[storage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tvOS]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=64971</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this tutorial, learn how to save and retrieve key-value pairs in Apple's iCloud.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, we are pleased to introduce the <a href=https://store.coronalabs.com/plugin/iCloud target="_blank">iCloud plugin</a>, available as of <a href=https://developer.coronalabs.com/downloads/daily-builds/ target="_blank">Daily Build 2015.2795</a>. This plugin is currently in &#8220;beta&#8221; while we finish polishing the <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/plugin/iCloud/index.html target="_blank">documentation</a> and give it further rounds of testing.</p>
<p>In this tutorial, we&#8217;ll explore <strong>Key-Value Storage</strong> or <strong>KVS</strong> (we will address &#8220;Documents in iCloud&#8221; and &#8220;CloudKit&#8221; in other tutorials).</p>
<h3>Overview</h3>
<p>KVS allows you to store &#8220;key-value&#8221; pairs in Apple&#8217;s iCloud using a very simple set of API calls. With KVS you can store strings, numbers, and tables of data using a simple <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/plugin/iCloud/set.html target="_blank">iCloud.set()</a> call.</p>
<p>Before you dive in, there are some KVS limits to be aware of:</p>
<ul>
<li>You can use 1 megabyte of storage at most.</li>
<li>You can have up to 1024 total keys.</li>
<li>Keys can be up to 64 bytes long and include unicode characters. Unicode characters take up more space than alpha-numeric characters. You can use up to 63 alpha-numeric characters.</li>
</ul>
<p>Depending on your requirements, you can use one key with a lot of tabled data, or you can use many keys with separate bits of data. Keep in mind that when you sync one key with a lot of data, you&#8217;re changing a lot at once. Also remember that data is generally synced over both WiFi and Cellular, so syncing keys with large amounts of data can be time consuming, even when only one small part of that data changed.</p>
<h3>Provisioning your app</h3>
<p>Before you can deploy your iCloud-capable app to the store, your provisioning profile must have iCloud enabled. This is done in the <strong>Member Center</strong> of the <a href=https://developer.apple.com/ target="_blank">Apple Developer</a> portal under <strong>Certificates, Identifiers &amp; Profiles</strong>. Once there, click <strong>Identifiers</strong> → <strong>App IDs</strong>. Click on the desired app (it can <strong>not</strong> use a wildcard App ID) and scroll down to the <strong>iCloud</strong> row. There, check the box to enable iCloud. Next, click the radio button to enable CloudKit, then click on the <strong>Edit</strong> button.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-64973" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/Screen-Shot-2015-12-16-at-7.01.58-PM.png" alt="Screen Shot 2015-12-16 at 7.01.58 PM" width="667" height="132" /></p>
<p>On the next screen, check the box for your app&#8217;s bundle ID:</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-64972" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/Screen-Shot-2015-12-16-at-7.00.01-PM.png" alt="Screen Shot 2015-12-16 at 7.00.01 PM" width="658" height="77" /></p>
<p>Click <strong>Continue</strong> and then <strong>Done</strong>. At this point, you will need to regenerate your provisioning profile (see the <strong>Creating Provisioning Profiles</strong> section <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/guide/distribution/iOSBuild/index.html>here</a>).</p>
<h3>Updating build.settings</h3>
<p>To include the iCloud plugin, you must add it to your <code>build.settings</code> file:</p><pre class="crayon-plain-tag">settings = {

    plugins =
    {
        [&quot;plugin.iCloud&quot;] =
        {
            publisherId = &quot;com.coronalabs&quot;,
            supportedPlatforms = { iphone=true, osx=true, appletvos=true },
        },
    },
}</pre><p>In addition, you must edit the block for <code>iphone</code> and/or <code>tvos</code>:</p><pre class="crayon-plain-tag">settings = {

    iphone = {
        iCloud = true, 
        plist = {
 
        }
    },

    -- Optional (only for use with Apple TV and tvOS)
    tvos =
    {
        iCloud = true,
    },
}</pre><p></p>
<h3>Corona Enterprise</h3>
<p>For Enterprise builds, you have to include the <code>Corona_plugin_iCloud.framework</code> which is located in the Enterprise plugins download tab on the <a href=https://developer.coronalabs.com/downloads/daily-builds/ target="_blank">Daily Builds page</a>.</p>
<p>In addition, there are some Xcode settings required for enabling iCloud, located on the project&#8217;s <strong>Capabilities</strong> screen. Here, ensure that iCloud is enabled and that <strong>Key-value storage</strong> is checked.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-64976" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/Screen-Shot-2015-12-16-at-7.27.05-PM.png" alt="Screen Shot 2015-12-16 at 7.27.05 PM" width="695" height="264" /></p>
<h3>Saving values to iCloud</h3>
<p>In any scene or Lua file where you need to access iCloud services, you must require the plugin:</p><pre class="crayon-plain-tag">local iCloud = require( &quot;plugin.iCloud&quot; )</pre><p>Then, when you&#8217;re ready to save some data, simply call <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/plugin/iCloud/set.html target="_blank">iCloud.set()</a> with a key and value, for example:</p><pre class="crayon-plain-tag">iCloud.set( &quot;playMusic&quot;, &quot;on&quot; )</pre><p>This will set a key named <code>playMusic</code> with the value of <code>"on"</code>.</p>
<h4>Accepted values</h4>
<p>KVS allows you to store the following data types:</p>
<ul>
<li>numbers</li>
<li>strings</li>
<li>tables</li>
</ul>
<p>While you cannot store booleans this way, they can be part of table data. Alternatively, you can simply use numbers like <code>1</code> or <code>0</code> to indicate true or false, or just store the strings <code>"true"</code> or <code>"false"</code>, but you will need to convert them back to boolean values before you use them as Lua booleans.</p>
<p>Note that if you choose to store a table, it must contain only <strong>key-value pairs</strong>. Tables with numeric keys (arrays) can not be stored directly as tables. In other words, the following array will produce an error if you attempt to store it to KVS:</p><pre class="crayon-plain-tag">local array = { true, 0, 10 }   -- This is analogous to { 1=true, 2=0, 3=10 }
iCloud.set( &quot;myArray&quot;, array )  -- This value will not be stored</pre><p>If you have an array to store, one option is to use <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/library/json/encode.html target="_blank">json.encode()</a> on the table and save it as string data, then use <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/library/json/decode.html target="_blank">json.decode()</a> on the string to convert it back into a table after you retrieve it from iCloud.</p>
<h3>Retrieving data</h3>
<p>To get data back from KVS, simply call the <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/plugin/iCloud/get.html target="_blank">iCloud.get()</a> method:</p><pre class="crayon-plain-tag">local musicOn = iCloud.get( &quot;playMusic&quot; )</pre><p>If the value can&#8217;t be found, <code>nil</code> will be returned. It&#8217;s that simple!</p>
<h3>Deleting data</h3>
<p>If you no longer need some data, you can recover used storage by deleting the key from iCloud using the <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/plugin/iCloud/delete.html target="_blank">iCloud.delete()</a> method:</p><pre class="crayon-plain-tag">iCloud.delete( &quot;playMusic&quot; )</pre><p></p>
<h3>Synchronizing data</h3>
<p>An important purpose of iCloud is to allow users with multiple devices to share data between them. In other words, if you finish a level in a game on your iPad, you should be able to pick up your iPhone and play the next level. If you load certain saved settings (data) from KVS when the app starts, the app should have the latest data &#8212; but what if the app is open at the same time on both devices and changes to the data occur?</p>
<p>One option is to enable a listener function via <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/plugin/iCloud/setKVSListener.html target="_blank">iCloud.setKVSListener()</a> that will execute when values change, effectively keeping your app up-to-date. Consider this block of code:</p><pre class="crayon-plain-tag">local function on_iCloudUpdate( event )
    if ( event.type == &quot;initialSync&quot; or event.type == &quot;serverChange&quot; ) then
        musicOn = iCloud.get( &quot;playMusic&quot; )
    end
end

iCloud.setKVSListener( on_iCloudUpdate )</pre><p>See the <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/plugin/iCloud/event/iCloudKVSEvent/index.html target="_blank">iCloudKVSEvent</a> documentation for the various values returned as part of the <code>event</code> table.</p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>This tutorial is just the first in respect to storing and sharing data in Apple&#8217;s iCloud. To learn more, please refer to the <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/plugin/iCloud/index.html target="_blank">iCloud documentation</a>.</p>
<hr />
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2015/12/18/tutorial-implementing-icloud-key-value-storage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
