<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Indiegogo &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/indiegogo/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Indiegogo &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Guest Piece: Columbus Little &#8211; Crowdfunding 101</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/08/28/guest-piece-columbus-little-crowdfunding-101/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 17:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crowdfunding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indiegogo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=42963</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Philip and Tobias Schneider are the creators of <a href="http://en.columbuslittle.com/">Columbus Little</a>, an app that lets kids discover the world in a playful way. Philip and Tobias are currently running an Indiegogo campaign to raise funds for Columbus Little.

This is the second piece in a two-part series on crowdfunding an app. The first piece covers <a href="/blog/2013/08/23/guest-piece-little-columbus-from-app-concept-to-working-prototype/">turning an app idea</a> into a working prototype, while today's piece covers the campaign itself.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Philip and Tobias Schneider are the creators of <a href=http://en.columbuslittle.com/>Columbus Little</a>, an app that lets kids discover the world in a playful way. Philip and Tobias are currently running an Indiegogo campaign to raise funds for Columbus Little.</p>
<p>This is the second piece in a two-part series on crowdfunding an app. The first piece covers <a href=/blog/2013/08/23/guest-piece-little-columbus-from-app-concept-to-working-prototype/>turning an app idea</a> into a working prototype, while today&#8217;s piece covers the campaign itself.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Columbus-Little-300x117.png" alt="Columbus Little" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-42261" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Columbus-Little-300x117.png 300w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Columbus-Little.png 694w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />A few months ago we had a great idea for an app, built a business model around it, formed a team and started app design and development. You can read about our experience in our <a href=/blog/2013/08/23/guest-piece-little-columbus-from-app-concept-to-working-prototype/>first blog piece</a>.</p>
<p>Over the course of three months we built a great prototype that implemented about 60% of the final app. But finishing the details, doing beta testing, adding professional sounds and marketing the app requires money. In this article, we’ll share some lessons learned from crowdfunding our app.</p>
<h4>Funding a startup</h4>
<p>There are many ways to fund your startup. A very common method is bootstrapping, or using your own savings and getting help from family and friends. While some personal investment is always necessary, this can be quite risky. You’re already forgoing potential income due to the opportunity cost of investing your time, so you need to consider if you want to invest your savings as well.</p>
<p>Entrepreneurs also often seek the help of angel investors that specifically target startups in the very early stages. However, these investors often aren’t interested in providing small investments less than $100,000 or even $500,000 USD. The relatively small sum you may need to develop an app – let’s say $10,000 – is often below their radar. </p>
<p>Moreover, the major disadvantage of working with investors is that they usually expect equity in your company. As your business starts to scale, this may lead to some problems. For example, in Berlin there are a number of incubators that demand up to 30% of your company for just $30,000 in funding. It’s your job to determine if giving up the control and stake of your company is worth that initial investment. </p>
<p>Finally, there are a variety of government programs to increase entrepreneurship. In Germany for instance, the EXIST program supports founders with a salary of about 2000 EUR after tax for 12 months plus some material expenses. They do not require an equity stake but have a rather complex and time-consuming application process that would have required two months of work for our project.</p>
<p>Luckily, a new form of funding has become very popular in recent years: crowdfunding. With crowdfunding, anyone with an interest in your project can help with funding by purchasing your product upfront before you launch. This is a great approach when you’re looking for a small amount of funding, without having to give away equity. To be successful with this approach, it&#8217;s important to take the time to set up a high quality campaign. </p>
<h4>Setting up your crowdfunding campaign</h4>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Columbus-Little-icon-134x150.png" alt="Columbus Little icon" class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-42966" />There are many crowdfunding websites including <a href=http://Kickstarter.com>Kickstarter/</a> and <a href=http://Indiegogo.com>Indiegogo/</a>. While Kickstarter is the most popular, we worked with Indiegogo for two reasons. Firstly, Indiegogo is available in Germany, as opposed to Kickstarter, which is limited to UK and US campaigners. Secondly, Indiegogo offers the possibility to use a flexible funding goal so that you can receive donations even if your target amount is not reached. </p>
<p>The optimal target goal for funding is quite hard to determine. We believe it is best to aim for a realistic amount of money that will enable you to do what you want to do &#8211; no less and no more. In our case, we went with a flexible funding goal that would enable us to complete the project and head to market. We determined that if we reached only a portion of our goal, we would concentrate on the most important elements of the app, and get it ready for release.</p>
<p>The optimal starting point of a campaign can be hard to determine. We started our campaign once we were about halfway done with the app. Before starting the campaign, you should have a working prototype to show so that you can truly communicate your idea and generate interest within your community of funders. However, you should also leave some tasks to complete once the campaign is over. </p>
<h4>Campaign description, video, and perks</h4>
<p>The video is the most essential part of a campaign. It has to explain the most important aspects and show the prototype. We used a DSLR to film and Adobe Premiere to edit the video. We tried to show as much as possible in pictures and videos so that people could understand the project quickly. We also showed the development team so that people could see who they are giving money to. Lastly, in the description, we addressed why the project is important to us.</p>
<p><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/70726651" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe> </p>
<p><a href=http://vimeo.com/70726651>Columbus Little</a> from <a href=http://vimeo.com/columbuslittle>Columbus Little</a> on <a href=https://vimeo.com>Vimeo/</a>.</p>
<p>If you crowdfund an app that will later sell for a few dollars, the majority of crowdfunding money will not come from upfront app purchases, because you are unlikely to find thousands of backers. The money will come from people buying your other perks, or unique products that you sell for higher funding amounts as a sign of gratitude. It is key to define alluring perks at various price points and calculate the margin. In our case, we designed various perks between 5 and 500 EUR &#8211; some for the backers’ children, and some for backers’ without kids (for example, a t-shirt and chocolate).</p>
<h4>Campaign marketing</h4>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Columbus-Little1-300x214.png" alt="Columbus Little" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-42964" />Marketing is the hardest part of the process. We aimed to be present on all channels and promoted our campaign in as many places as possible, on <a href=http://igg.me/at/columbuslittle>Indiegogo</a>, our company website at <a href=http://zestlab.net>zestlab.net/</a>, <a href=http://ColumbusLittle.com>ColumbusLittle.com/</a> and social media channels such as Facebook and Twitter.</p>
<p>We also contacted all our friends and encouraged them to tell their friends about the project. In general, about 30% of crowdfunding campaign funds come from personal contacts. We also tried to mix global marketing and local marketing into the process. We didn’t have much success with the marketing firm we hired, however we did purchase some semi-effective Facebook ads and discovered that you can buy “likes.” However, you should be wary of this as there is a huge difference between liking a page and actually backing the campaign. For local marketing we did it the old-fashioned way and we spread flyers around Berlin.</p>
<h4>Lessons learned</h4>
<p>One major lesson we learned was that we should have had all the marketing ready before launching the campaign. We did that far too late – for example, the flyer was printed two weeks after the campaign launched. We also found it more challenging to market a crowdfunding campaign for an app versus a physical product.</p>
<p>That being said, we are quite happy with the success of our campaign. We definitely reached the most important goal: We will now be able to finish the app and release it this fall. While we wish that more people found their way to our campaign, we&#8217;re thrilled to be able to finish the project with the money we&#8217;ve raised.</p>
<p>There are of course many more details to successfully developing and crowdfunding an app, but we hope to have covered some of the most important lessons we learned in our journey so far. We look forward to our next big milestone &#8211; releasing the app this fall.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest piece: Columbus Little &#8211; From app concept to working prototype</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/08/23/guest-piece-little-columbus-from-app-concept-to-working-prototype/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 21:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crowdsourcing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indiegogo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=42260</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Philip and Tobias Schneider are the creators of <a href="http://en.columbuslittle.com/">Columbus Little</a>, an app that lets kids discover the world in a playful way. Philip and Tobias are currently running a campaign on <a href="http://igg.me/at/columbuslittle/x/3916812">Indiegogo</a> to raise funds for Columbus Little. 

This piece is the first of a two-part series on turning an app idea into a crowd-sourcing campaign.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Philip and Tobias Schneider are the creators of <a href=http://en.columbuslittle.com/>Columbus Little</a>, an app that lets kids discover the world in a playful way. Philip and Tobias are currently running a campaign on <a href=http://igg.me/at/columbuslittle/x/3916812>Indiegogo</a> to raise funds for Columbus Little. </p>
<p>This piece is the first of a two-part series on turning an app idea into a crowd-sourcing campaign.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-42261 alignleft" alt="Columbus Little" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Columbus-Little-300x117.png" width="300" height="117" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Columbus-Little-300x117.png 300w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Columbus-Little.png 694w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />In January, we decided to dive feet first into building an app called <em>Columbus Little</em>. Based on our experience, we&#8217;d like to share some lessons from our journey, starting with how we transformed our idea into a business model to build a prototype. Our second article, to be published next week, will discuss the lessons we learned as a result of starting a crowd-funding campaign on <a href=http://igg.me/at/columbuslittle/x/3916812>Indiegogo</a>.</p>
<h4>It starts with an idea</h4>
<p>Do you have a great idea but don&#8217;t know where to start? Or, do you have many ideas but are having trouble determining which one to focus on? We had various ideas for potential apps — some more complex, others very sleek and simple — but we had trouble deciding on just one.</p>
<p>In early 2013, we imagined an iPad app for children to discover the world. This idea caught our focus because it was very much in line with our own interest in traveling. This was our first important lesson: that many ideas have potential, but the important part is to pursue one idea that you&#8217;re passionate about.</p>
<h4>Building a business model</h4>
<p>To start, it&#8217;s important to determine the value in your idea. Will people like it? Is there a need for it in the market? Enriching and validating your idea should be done with a systematic approach. We used two different methodologies to figure out what we want to do and what not to do.</p>
<p>First, we used a method called &#8220;the golden circle.&#8221; In a famous <a href=http://www.ted.com/talks/simon_sinek_how_great_leaders_inspire_action.html>TED talk</a>, Simon Sinek describes that you should always address the &#8220;Why?&#8221; of what you&#8217;re doing. In our case, we wanted children to discover the world and enjoy it as much as we did.</p>
<p>Simon then continues to ask about the &#8220;How?&#8221; or the way you deliver that value to your customers. For us, this was to be accomplished by showing children interesting locations in the world in a playful way.</p>
<p>Finally, the &#8220;What?&#8221; describes the actual product with all its features. For us, the development of Columbus Little answered this question. Though this model seems obvious, many companies successfully communicate what they do, but struggle with why they do it.</p>
<p>Second, it is important to have a comprehensive overview of your business model, not just the product. A business model describes how your product or service will deliver value to your customers and generate revenue. There are many different ways to describe business models, and we used a very simple method called the <a href=http://businessmodelgeneration.com/canvas>business model canvas</a> by Osterwalder. In a business model canvas, you sketch a company&#8217;s business model in 9 important dimensions. While we cover them briefly below, please refer to Osterwalder&#8217;s book for more details.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Value Proposition</strong>: What are the core values of your product? Why will customers buy it?</li>
<li><strong>Customer Segments</strong>: Who are your customers?</li>
<li><strong>Sales Channels</strong>: How will you reach your customers?</li>
<li><strong>Customer Relationships</strong>: How will you build a lasting relationship with your customers?</li>
<li><strong>Key Resources</strong>: Which key resources do you need to run your business?</li>
<li><strong>Key Activities</strong>: What are the key activities you need to pursue?</li>
<li><strong>Key Partners</strong>: Which partners might help you?</li>
<li><strong>Cost Structure</strong>: What are the most important cost drivers? How can you keep them lean?</li>
<li><strong>Revenue Streams</strong>: What revenue can you estimate? Where will it come from?</li>
</ul>
<p>Bringing all these together provides a good overview of your business. This will enable you to focus on the essentials of your idea &#8211; this allowed us to see where our app could live in the market, what we could charge, which elements could later become part of the project etc.</p>
<h4>Building a strong team</h4>
<p>One important realization was that while our customers would value nice design, we lacked the capabilities to create something truly impressive. To help us flesh out the idea, we reached out to a designer who shared our vision.</p>
<p>Moreover, although we had some coding skills, we knew we couldn&#8217;t develop the app ourselves and searched for a talented developer. As a team, we were lucky to stumble across Corona SDK and enjoyed fast and easy app development, as well the ability to publish to multiple app markets. </p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-42262" alt="Colombus Little team" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Colombus-Little-team.png" /></p>
<h4>Beginning app development</h4>
<p>Once we had a team in place, the development finally started. We scoured Corona&#8217;s countless tutorials, API descriptions and code snippets. For task management, we used a simple 7-week plan with Post-it notes as overview combined with Evernote for notes on Wunderlist for bugs and coding tasks.</p>
<p>After trying several code editors we decided on <a href=http://www.mydevelopersgames.com/Glider/>Lua Glider</a>, which worked quite well for code highlighting, auto completion, and bug tracking. For graphic composition we used Adobe Photoshop and predesigned all scenes in there before exporting layers into different PNG files. We then used <a href=http://www.codeandweb.com/texturepacker>TexturePacker</a> to compose an image sheet of all images within a scene so that loading times were minimized.</p>
<p>Animations were drawn as sprites in Photoshop and added to the image sheet. For the animations we used sprites that consisted of sometimes more than 50 different images that were played in a defined time frame and order to show an animation. To limit memory usage we sometimes used multiple sprites for one object (e.g. the head and arms of the Columbus Little character are separate).</p>
<p>The app itself relied heavily on different scenes. Hence we used the <a href=http://docs.coronalabs.com/api/library/storyboard/>Storyboard API</a> for loading scenes and overlaying and managing memory usage. In the createScene events of each scene, we then loaded the respective image sheets and displayed all the images, create Sprite objects that we use for animation. Simple animations were done with transition.to function, while complex ones were done with transitioning along a beizer curve in the Runtime enterFrame event. All interaction was done with touch events and event listeners &#8211; very basic stuff.</p>
<p>All in all, we loved working with Corona SDK and enjoyed the ease of development. With the help of Corona&#8217;s community, we were able to focus on our idea and not get hampered down with technological uncertainties.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-42263" alt="Colombus Little app" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Colombus-Little-app.png" /></p>
<h4>In conclusion</h4>
<p>We started with a great idea, built a business model around it, formed a team and started app design and development. The next big milestone was building the framework for the app and developing a working prototype that we could show off in our crowd-funding campaign.</p>
<p>Of course, there are many more details to successfully developing an app, but we hope to have covered some of the most important lessons in this piece.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s an overview of the 5 major lessons we learned:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Lesson 1: Having great ideas is important &#8211; what&#8217;s more important is being decisive and sticking to the one idea you&#8217;re most passionate about.</em></li>
<li><em>Lesson 2: It&#8217;s important to figure out why you want to do something and why the world needs your product.</em></li>
<li><em>Lesson 3: To figure out how to transform your idea into a business, use a business model canvas to flesh out your thoughts and plan of action.</em></li>
<li><em>Lesson 4: Build a strong team and use Corona SDK for easy and fast development.</em></li>
<li><em>Lesson 5: Though an app can be quite complex, remember that it consists of a sequence of small logic snippets. Don&#8217;t get overwhelmed by the scope of the project &#8211; take it one day at a time and celebrate the little victories.</em></li>
</ul>
<p>We&#8217;d love your support on <a href=http://igg.me/at/columbuslittle/x/3916812>Indiegogo</a> and encourage you to preorder the app, enjoy our cool perks as a contributor, and share the campaign with family and friends.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest Piece: Crowdfunding Near Humanity &#8211; A Corona SDK &#038; Kwik Horror Comic Series</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/05/24/guest-piece-crowdfunding-near-humanity-a-corona-sdk-kwik-horror-comic-series/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 18:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horror]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indiegogo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kwik]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=34596</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Xavier Bottet is the art director of Near Humanity, an upcoming series of horror comics for digital devices. Xavier and his partner Emmanuel Beaudry turned to Indiegogo to crowdfund their Corona SDK and Kwik-powered project. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Xavier Bottet is the art director of Near Humanity, an upcoming series of horror comics for digital devices. Xavier and his partner Emmanuel Beaudry turned to Indiegogo to crowdfund their Corona SDK and Kwik-powered project. You can contribute to their campaign on the <a href=http://www.indiegogo.com/projects/near-humanity-the-motion-comics/x/2914783?c=home>Near Humanity Indiegogo</a> page, and <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/id643325144?mt=8&s=143455>download NearHumanityNews</a>, the project&#8217;s teaser app, from Apple&#8217;s App Store.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-34597" alt="Near Humanity" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Near-Humanity-300x220.jpg" /></p>
<p>A few months ago, my partner and I put ourselves up to a challenge: to create a mature horror comic series with Corona SDK and <a href=http://www.kwiksher.com/>Kwik</a>. Today, that vision is called <em>Near Humanity</em>. I, Xavier Bottet, am an art director with game design experience, and my partner Emmanuel Beaudry is a writer with movie scripting experience.</p>
<p>Near Humanity blends horror stories, comics, animation, and interactive contents into one visceral experience. We&#8217;re still working on the project, but we plan to develop 12 full episodes, each lasting 5-7 minutes. I&#8217;m in charge of the technical aspects, while Emmanuel is responsible for the text definition.</p>
<p>Near Humanity’s core starts with the script, written by Emmanuel. After I view the script, we exchange ideas, make modifications, and then discuss the conceptual art. I then proceed to the illustration stage and mix in other media such as photos, scanned sketches, 3D elements, and digital paintings. Then I put all of the contents into Adobe After Effects. As the final step, Emmanuel edits the videos in Final Cut and &#8220;viola!&#8221;, we have an episode.</p>
<p>As with <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2012/10/29/app-of-the-week-halloween-recreation/>Halloween Recreation</a> — a 2012 App of the Week winner and my first Kwik and Corona SDK app — I prepare videos and present them to several &#8220;candidates&#8221; to see how they react to the app. Using Corona SDK and Kwik, we&#8217;ve also released NearHumanityNews, an app based around the entire campaign. We hope that this teaser app will help people discover our motion comics, peek at the official trailer, check out stills from the first episode, and maybe even discover some extra content.</p>
<p>We developed NearHumanityNews in just one week, and I used some video content from our <a href=http://www.indiegogo.com/projects/near-humanity-the-motion-comics/x/2914783?c=home>crowdfunding</a> campaign. You can experience Near Humanity in a video, and then you interact with the same content in the app.</p>
<p>Our plan is to continue this project at full speed. Since we&#8217;re a small team — just the two of us, plus a few partners such as Melanie Jane, an English vocal artist who plays &#8220;Rachel&#8221; — we need to work as quickly and efficiently as possible. Recently, we discovered Indiegogo and set a flexible funding campaign which helped us to raise funds. Now, we&#8217;re reaching out to the Corona SDK community for help.</p>
<p>We hope that you enjoy NearHumanityNews as a free teaser, and that it inspires you to contribute to our cause, even in a small way. If funded, our motion comic will come to life, and we promise to deliver you more episodes soon. You can contribute to the <a href=http://www.indiegogo.com/projects/near-humanity-the-motion-comics/x/2914783?c=home>Near Humanity Indiegogo</a> campaign and <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/id643325144?mt=8&s=143455>download NearHumanityNews</a> from the App Store. If you want to check out more videos, head to our <a href=https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC_UyKkdJDREkdP20qGsJR6w>YouTube channel</a>.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/VnqRKMqRZHc" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
