<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>partner &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/partner/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>partner &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Guest piece: SponsorPay Meets Corona, and Revenues Soar!</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/06/06/guest-piece-sponsorpay-meets-corona-and-revenues-soar/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 17:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ad network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plugin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SponsorPay]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=35301</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Projjol Banerjea is VP Marketing &#038; Business Development at SponsorPay, the world’s leading value-exchange advertising platform. He oversees marketing, including online/offline presence, PR/communications, industry relationships and market research, as well as strategic business development, presales and sales support.

SponsorPay is one of our inaugural <a href="/resources/plugins/">Corona Plugin partners</a>, which are available for all Corona SDK developers. For more info please see the SponsorPay <a href="http://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/sponsorpay/index.html">plugin documentation</a>. Read on for more information about SponsorPay's great monetization services for mobile developers.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Projjol Banerjea is VP Marketing &#038; Business Development at SponsorPay, the world’s leading value-exchange advertising platform. He oversees marketing, including online/offline presence, PR/communications, industry relationships and market research, as well as strategic business development, presales and sales support.</p>
<p>SponsorPay is one of our inaugural <a href=/resources/plugins/>Corona Plugin partners</a>, which are available for all Corona SDK developers. For more info please see the SponsorPay <a href=http://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/sponsorpay/index.html>plugin documentation</a>. Read on for more information about SponsorPay&#8217;s great monetization services for mobile developers.</em></p>
<hr/>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Projjol-Banerjea-headshot1.png" alt="Projjol Banerjea headshot" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-35305" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Projjol-Banerjea-headshot1.png 200w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Projjol-Banerjea-headshot1-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />At <a href=http://sponsorpay.com/>SponsorPay</a>, we strive to be the number one monetization partner in the market. That’s why we’re so excited about our <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2013/05/21/corona-weekly-update-new-plugin-partners-core-gets-lighter/>new partnership</a> with Corona Labs!</p>
<p>Our value-exchange advertising platform brings <a href=http://sponsorpay.com/brands>advertisers</a> and <a href=http://sponsorpay.com/developers>developers</a> together for mutual benefit. It drives the monetization of premium content on platforms such as Facebook, iOS and Android through brand engagement, user acquisition and direct response ad campaigns.  </p>
<p>Our innovative monetization products include <a href=http://sponsorpay.com/developers?#brandengage>BrandEngage®</a>, our social video and engagement advertising product, and our <a href=http://sponsorpay.com/developers?#mediation>Mediation Platform</a> which gives publishers access to campaigns from top ad networks, DSPs and agencies worldwide, as well as our direct sales teams in the US, Europe and Asia.</p>
<p>The industry we move in is dynamic and fast-paced with two-digit growth, especially in gaming and mobile. The <a href=http://mobilemarketingmagazine.com/content/mobile-time-spend-overtakes-tv-says-inmobi>average daily time spent</a> on mobile (117 minutes) has now surpassed TV (98 minutes) whereas the digital games market <a href=http://www.emarketer.com/Article/Mobile-Social-Support-Digital-Game-Revenue-Growth/1009726>grew by 39%</a> between January 2012 and January 2013. </p>
<p>A great example of the effectiveness of our solution is the <a href=http://www.brandengage.com/campaigns/>engagement campaign</a> we ran with Coca-Cola across several platforms, including mobile. Gamers could watch a video ad from the Happiness Truck campaign and share it on Facebook. The result: more than 150,000 completed views and a 63.7% share rate. We’ve run similarly successful BrandEngage® campaigns with other premium brands such as Volkswagen, Warner Brothers, McDonald’s and Domino’s. </p>
<p>We’re incredibly proud to be the first and only offer wall and rewarded video provider partnering with Corona Labs, and look forward to working with them to empower developers with a more seamless and effective monetization experience.</p>
<p>Interested in learning more? Get to know us better by reading our <a href=http://blog.sponsorpay.com/>blog</a> and following us on <a href=http://twitter.com/sponsorpay>Twitter</a>. If you have any questions, please <a href=http://sponsorpay.com/company>contact us</a> directly – we’d love to hear from you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
