<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ambassador &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/ambassador-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Ambassador &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Corona Ambassador Accomplishments – October 2013</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/11/06/corona-ambassador-accomplishments-october-2013/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 16:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News & Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ambassador]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=51022</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With the release of <a href="/blog/2013/10/08/graphics-2-0-public-beta/">Graphics 2.0</a> and our new <a href="/blog/topics/announcements/">partnership with Microsoft</a>, October was a busy month! Our Ambassadors have also been hard at work creating Corona-powered apps, organizing events in their local areas, and sharing their knowledge with the community. Here's a recap of some of our Ambassadors' fantastic October accomplishments.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/Corona-Ambassador-136x150.png" alt="Corona Ambassador" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-25598" />With the release of <a href=/blog/2013/10/08/graphics-2-0-public-beta/>Graphics 2.0</a> and our new <a href=/blog/topics/announcements/>partnership with Microsoft</a>, October was a very busy month! Our Ambassadors have also been hard at work creating Corona-powered apps, organizing events in their local areas, and sharing their knowledge with the community. Here&#8217;s a recap of some of our Ambassadors&#8217; fantastic October accomplishments.</p>
<p><strong>Austin, TX</strong>: Gerald Bailey represented us at the <a href=http://www.captivateconference.com/>Captivate Conference</a>, an annual event that brings together individuals in the film, music, mobile and video game industries to learn, engage and discover. Gerald shared a session entitled <a href=http://captivateconference.com/portfolio/tips-for-indie-developers-building-hits-generating-revenue/gallery/schedule/>Tips for Indie Developers: Building Hits, Generating Revenue</a>, where he provided information on publishing to multiple markets and optimizing mobile content. The presentation was such a success that Gerald was invited to present at a local <a href=http://www.meetup.com/Video-Game-Makers-Unite/events/144869692/>Austin Meetup</a> later in the month.</p>
<p><strong>Boston, MA</strong>: Jennifer Looper of <a href=http://www.ladeezfirstmedia.com/>LadeezFirstMedia</a> released a language learning app called <a href=http://www.ladeezfirstmedia.com/apps/gabbler/>Gabbler</a> along with <a href=http://www.ladeezfirstmedia.com/apps/mathbrew/>MathBrew</a>, a Halloween math game, in response to NOOK&#8217;s call for holiday apps. As the organizer of the <a href=http://www.meetup.com/Corona-SDK-Boston-Meetup/>Boston Corona SDK Meetup</a>, Jen has been spreading the word about Corona in collaboration with Boston Indies, an umbrella organization for game developers in the Boston area.</p>
<p><strong>London, UK</strong>: Stefan Nowak joined <a href=http://hellomogo.com/>HelloMogo™</a> to focus on their <a href=http://www.authormobile.com/>AuthorMogo™</a> brand, a service for authors and publishers to deliver custom devotional and children&#8217;s book apps. Their latest project is a revised version of <a href=http://thejesuscallingapp.com/>Jesus Calling</a>, the #1 Book App in the App Store. Stefan is also working on a follow-up to last year&#8217;s holiday book app, <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2012/12/19/corona-holiday-gems-app-roundup/>Angel&#8217;s Great Escape : A Christmas Story</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Minneapolis, MN</strong>: Peter Chang and his team won a <a href=http://www.brandon-hall.com/>Silver Award from Brandon Hall</a> for having one of the best certification training programs in 2013. The team received the award for running a first-class corporate training program &#8211; a great skill to boast when championing Corona SDK to the developer community.</p>
<p><strong>Philadelphia, PA</strong>: Greg Pugh of <a href=http://gpanimations.com/>GP Animations</a> is working on his next Corona children&#8217;s book app, Maddie Bear&#8217;s Birthday, with plans to the app for iPad, Kindle Fire, and even in print. You can follow his progress on Twitter: <a href=https://twitter.com/MaddieBearBooks>@MaddieBearBooks</a>.</p>
<p><strong>San Diego, CA</strong>: Mario Roberti has been spending his free time teaching kids how to code with Corona SDK. He&#8217;s also working to get Corona introduced to Qualcomm&#8217;s Hire-A-Youth staff and Internship team. Lastly, his marathon tracking app, <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/case-study/crossing-the-finish-line-with-bibs/>Bibs</a>, is celebrating over 15K downloads.</p>
<p><strong>Springfield, MO</strong>: Richard Harris offered Corona Ambassadors a full page ad in <a href=http://appdevelopermagazine.com/>App Developer Magazine</a> so that our evangelists could show off their apps. How&#8217;s that for Corona awesomeness?</p>
<p>Thanks to our Ambassadors, the Corona community is growing strong with over 300,000 developers worldwide! If you&#8217;d like to connect with an Ambassador in your area, please visit our <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/community/events/>Meetup groups and event calendar</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
