<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ipad &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/ipad-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>ipad &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>App of the Week: MixUp DressUp</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/05/27/app-of-the-week-mixup-dressup/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/05/27/app-of-the-week-mixup-dressup/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 22:08:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=34591</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[MixUp DressUp brings a favorite children's pastime - doll dress-ups and fashion shows - to mobile, allowing children to create stylish outfits and characters with the swipe of a finger. Available on the App Store, the endless possibilities for customization in MixUp DressUp makes for a super fun dress-up experience.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Screen-Shot-2013-05-24-at-9.25.58-AM.png" alt="MixUp DressUp" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-34592" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Screen-Shot-2013-05-24-at-9.25.58-AM.png 201w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Screen-Shot-2013-05-24-at-9.25.58-AM-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 201px) 100vw, 201px" /></p>
<p>While children may love dressing up their dolls, many parents are hesitant to clutter their closets with a variety of miniature outfits. MixUp DressUp brings a favorite children&#8217;s pastime &#8211; doll dress-ups and fashion shows &#8211; to mobile, allowing children to create stylish outfits and characters with the swipe of a finger. Available on the <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mixup-dressup/id571062209?mt=8>App Store</a>, the endless possibilities for customization in MixUp DressUp make for a super fun dress-up experience for children in the digital age.</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/MixUp-DressUp-screenshow.jpg" alt="MixUp DressUp screenshot" class="alignright size-full wp-image-34593" />In MixUp DressUp, the fashion models are split into three horizontal panels, allowing children to play lead designer. To change a model&#8217;s face to reflect different ethnicities, and to switch up her articles of clothing with items ranging from dresses to shoes to everything in between, you simply need to swipe a panel. After picking out the perfect outfit, you can select a background for the character, from options including a castle scene, polka dot wallpaper and more. If you&#8217;d like an endless closet of possibilities for your doll, you can purchase the Spring 2013 Collections&#8217; 3,300 possible outfits for just $0.99. </p>
<p>By far, my favorite element of the app was the ability to create customized voice recordings. MixUp DressUp allowed me to record my own voice with encouraging comments that got played back to me each time I created a new customization on my character. This fun (and free!) <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/mixup-dressup/id571062209?mt=8>download</a> for iPad/iPhone is a great alternative to traditional doll dress-ups; highly recommended for young children.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/05/27/app-of-the-week-mixup-dressup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>App of the Week: Move and Fire</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/05/06/app-of-the-week-move-and-fire/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/05/06/app-of-the-week-move-and-fire/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 21:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crossplatform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puzzle]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=33134</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Move and Fire is a puzzle game that weaves the basic principles of pinball with the laws of physics. It's both challenging and entertaining, and features standout graphics that pop right off the screen.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Screen-Shot-2013-05-05-at-10.37.43-AM.png" alt="Move and Fire logo" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-33135" /></p>
<p>Move and Fire is a puzzle game that weaves the basic principles of pinball with the laws of physics. It&#8217;s both challenging and entertaining, featuring standout graphics that pop right off the screen.</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Move-and-Fire-screenshot-200x300.jpg" alt="Move and Fire screenshot" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-33136" />In Move and Fire, your goal is to hit yellow orbs with a small ball that ricochets off blocks and obstacles within each level. To collect all the orbs, you must strategically position the blocks, which direct the ball in the right direction. Once you collect all the orbs, you receive a score that&#8217;s based on the amount of time it took you to complete the level, as well as the number of block readjustments you made. Of course, a faster time and a minimum number of block readjustments awards you with a higher score. Though this puzzler becomes quite difficult from the start, there&#8217;s nothing more gratifying than successfully completing a level and moving ahead. </p>
<p>With 100 challenging puzzles across four worlds and an interactive leaderboard, you can easily kill several hours conquering Move and Fire. Best of all, the game is <a href=www.coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk>cross-platform</a>, and offered as a free download for players on both <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yakaz.mtb>Android</a> and <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/move-and-fire/id597457573?ls=1&mt=8>iOS</a>.</p>
<p>Also, for those of you that followed our Corona April App of the Month poll on Facebook, we&#8217;d like to applaud <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2013/04/01/app-of-the-week-garfields-trivia-party/>Garfield’s Trivia Party</a> on winning the community vote! Remember to like <a href=https://www.facebook.com/CoronaLabs>Corona Labs on Facebook</a> to vote in future App of the Month polls.</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/CgoDTvblXHE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="clearfix spacerDiv"></div>
<h3>Honorable Mention</h3>
<div class="clearfix  spacerDiv">
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Screen-Shot-2013-05-05-at-10.50.40-AM.png" alt="The Three Little Pigs icon" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-33140" /></a></p>
<h4 style="margin-bottom: 10px;">The Three Little Pigs</h4>
<p>The Three Little Pigs is an interactive storybook for iOS, that offers a twist on the fairytale that we all know and love. The adorable illustrations, easy navigation and delightful storyline is perfect for young children to read aloud, or to enjoy via the storybook&#8217;s narration. Thanks to <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2012/08/19/guest-post-developing-ebooks-with-kwik-2/>Kwik 2.0</a>, a popular third party tool, The Three Little Pigs was created <em>without any code</em> by a team of talented artists at <a href=http://www.backseat-driver.com/>Backseat Driver</a>. Download The Three Little Pigs from <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/three-little-pigs-interactive/id625171096?mt=8>iTunes</a> for $1.99 to experience this lovely interactive tale.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/05/06/app-of-the-week-move-and-fire/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>App of the Week: Jackpot Words</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/04/29/app-of-the-week-jackpot-words/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/04/29/app-of-the-week-jackpot-words/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 22:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=32715</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Created by Naomi Kokubo of LavaMind, Jackpot Words combines the thrill of casino slots with the challenge of word games.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Jackpot-Words-145x150.png" alt="Jackpot Words" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-32716" />After a brief hiatus, we’re back with another awesome App of the Week! Created by Naomi Kokubo of LavaMind, <a href=http://developer.coronalabs.com/showcase/jackpot-words>Jackpot Words</a> combines the thrill of casino slots with the challenge of word games.</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Jackpot-Words-screenshot-300x168.jpg" alt="Jackpot Words screenshot" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-32717" />While traditional slot machines display only symbols such as cherries and bells, Jackpot Words overlays these objects with bubble letters that can be used to create words. To collect coins and to win jackpots, use your finger to swipe across letters on the screen. With more coins, you&#8217;ll even unlock special mini-games and treasures. You can choose to play against friends, a randomly selected opponent, or simply challenge yourself to see how many coins you can earn.</p>
<p>For a refreshing take on your favorite word puzzles, head over to <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/jackpot-words/id546722251?mt=8>iTunes</a> and download Jackpot Words for free. Stay tuned for the game&#8217;s upcoming release for Android, Kindle and NOOK!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/04/29/app-of-the-week-jackpot-words/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>App of the Week: Stay Alight!</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/04/15/app-of-the-week-stay-alight/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/04/15/app-of-the-week-stay-alight/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 19:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arcade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puzzle]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=31697</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Developed by Wyse Games, Stay Alight! is a stunning new physics-based game for iPad/iPhone. Within a week of launch, Stay Alight! rose to the App Store's Top 10 of puzzle and arcade games.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Screen-Shot-2013-04-11-at-6.57.59-PM.png" alt="Stay Alight icon" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-31698" />Created by Russia-based <a href=http://www.wysegames.com/en/>Wyse Games</a>, <a href=http://developer.coronalabs.com/showcase/stay-alight-hd-0>Stay Alight!</a> is a stunning new physics-based game for iPad/iPhone. Within a week of launch, Stay Alight! rose to the App Store&#8217;s Top 10 of puzzle and arcade game in five countries. The game&#8217;s allure lies in the captivating gameplay and the gorgeous, highly detailed graphics. Each level also provide a host of unique features, from the beautiful music, to the unique movements and sounds of the characters.</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Staying-Alight-screenshot.jpg" alt="Stay Alight screenshot" class="alignright size-full wp-image-31699" />In the opening scene of the game, players are shown a world filled with garbage, pollution and destruction. In short, microbes have captured the planet and it’s your job destroy them. Making use of physics-based game mechanics, you’re given power balls to complete levels by eliminating a slew of microbes.</p>
<p>Each level provides a set number of energy balls and the challenge is to use your weapon strategically so you don&#8217;t run out or balls. By aiming a light ball at boxes and barrels in a level, you can eliminate multiple microbes at one time. When hit, these objects roll and bounce towards the monsters and instantly destroy them. </p>
<p>Whether you’re a fan of graphical games, or if you love puzzles and arcades, Stay Alight! is sure to capture your attention. Check out Stay Alight! on <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/stay-alight!/id628008290?mt=8
">iTunes</a> for just $0.99.</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/GnNZTINHOpg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="clearfix spacerDiv"></div>
<h3>Honorable Mention</h3>
<div class="clearfix  spacerDiv">
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Screen-Shot-2013-04-12-at-1.05.22-PM.png" alt="Hideout icon" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-31748" /></a></p>
<h4 style="margin-bottom: 10px;">Hideout: Early Reading</h4>
<p>Developed by <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/case-study/brigham-young-university/>Brigham Young University</a>, a Corona Labs educational partner, Hideout: Early Reading teaches children to read through a series of interactive activities. Emphasizing letter-sound association and word repetition to enhance the reading experience, Hideout: Early Reading has already earned a 5-star rating in the App Store. The app&#8217;s vibrant illustrations, positive messages, and catchy music are nothing short of impressive. Download <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/id625966929?mt=8>Hideout: Early Reading</a> as a free app for your iPhone/iPad.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/04/15/app-of-the-week-stay-alight/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corona Geek #34 &#8211; Hanging out with Climate Clock&#8217;s Ben Wong</title>
		<link>/blog/coronageek/corona-geek-hangout-34/</link>
		<comments>/blog/coronageek/corona-geek-hangout-34/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 01:50:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles McKeever]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona Geek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google+ Hangouts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indie developer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[utility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weather]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.coronalabs.com/?post_type=coronageek&#038;p=31456</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week, we hung out with Climate Clock's, Ben Wong. Climate Clock is a beautifully designed iOS weather app that puts the temperature on your home screen. Ben describes himself as a designer who is interested in app development. He has a background in designing websites and used the creation of Climate Clock to expand his skills into app development. Climate Clock was built in 8 weeks while Ben developed his own back end web server, taught himself Lua, and Corona SDK. Climate Clock uses a third party API to provide weather information. The app is very elegant in it's design and has been written about by Lifehacker, CNET, and TUAW. Climate Clock soared to the #1 weather app spot in the App Store, in a dozen countries, in March of this year.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/S3OWp49EqVo?rel=0" height="436" width="640" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-477" alt="Corona Geek" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/corona-geek-head-transparent-150x150.png" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/corona-geek-head-transparent-150x150.png 150w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/corona-geek-head-transparent.png 250w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />This week, we hung out with Climate Clock&#8217;s, Ben Wong. Climate Clock is a beautifully designed iOS weather app that puts the temperature on your home screen. Ben describes himself as a designer who is interested in app development. He has a background in designing websites and used the creation of Climate Clock to expand his skills into app development. Climate Clock was built in 8 weeks while Ben developed his own back end web server, taught himself Lua, and Corona SDK. Climate Clock uses a third party API to provide weather information. The app is very elegant in it&#8217;s design and has been written about by Lifehacker, CNET, and TUAW. Climate Clock soared to the #1 weather app spot in the App Store, in a dozen countries, in March of this year.</p>
<p>Also joining us on the developer panel were <a href=http://burtonsmediagroup.com/ target="_blank">Dr. Brian Burton</a>, <a href=http://echoecho.es/ target="_blank">Dean Murphy</a>, <a href=http://roaminggamer.com/ target="_blank">Ed Maurina</a>, and <a href=http://www.origintech.net/ target="_blank">Matthew Chapman</a>.</p>
<p>Be sure to watch/listen to the full hangout for more information and <a title="Download Climate Clock" href=http://climateclockapp.com/ target="_blank">check out Climate Clock</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<hr />
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div style="clear: both;"></div>
<p><strong>Corona Labs T-Shirt Winner</strong></p>
<p>This week&#8217;s t-shirt winner was Justin Giles. Congrats Justin! For your chance to win, follow Corona Geek on <a href=http://www.twitter.com/coronageek>Twitter</a> and <a href=http://www.facebook.com/coronageek>Facebook</a>, and complete the <a href=http://coronalabs.wufoo.com/forms/corona-geek-giveaway/ target="_blank">Corona Geek giveaway form</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Thank you for watching, we&#8217;ll see you on next week&#8217;s Corona Geek hangout!</p>
<p><strong>Listen and Rate!</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href=http://CoronaGeek.com/itunes target="_blank">Rate the Corona Geek podcast on iTunes</a></li>
<li><a href=http://CoronaGeek.com/stitcher target="_blank">Listen and rate on Stitcher</a></li>
<li><a href=http://CoronaGeek.com/chrome target="_blank">Get the Corona SDK Quick Reference Chrome Extension</a></li>
<li><a href=http://youtube.com/coronageek target="_blank">Subscribe to Corona Geek on YouTube</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/coronageek/corona-geek-hangout-34/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://coronageek.coronalabs.com/cdn/corona-geek-show-34-2013-04-08-climate-clock.mp3" length="42266613" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://coronageek.coronalabs.com/cdn/corona-geek-show-34-2013-04-08-climate-clock.mp3" length="42266613" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://coronageek.coronalabs.com/cdn/corona-geek-show-34-2013-04-08-climate-clock.mp3" length="42266613" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://coronageek.coronalabs.com/cdn/corona-geek-show-34-2013-04-08-climate-clock.mp3" length="42266613" type="audio/mpeg" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>App of the Week: Garfield&#8217;s Trivia Party</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/04/01/app-of-the-week-garfields-trivia-party/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/04/01/app-of-the-week-garfields-trivia-party/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 20:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trivia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=30829</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For fans of Garfield, comes a cross-platform trivia game featuring the classic characters. In Garfield’s Trivia Party, your job is to fill out portions of a comic strip that have been wiped away by Odie’s coffee spill. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-31-at-5.47.13-PM-147x150.png" alt="Garfield&#039;s Trivia Party" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-30830" /></p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Garfields-screenshot-168x300.jpg" alt="Garfield&#039;s screenshot" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-30831" /><br />
For fans of <a href=http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Garfield>Jim Davis’ Garfield</a> comic, comes a brand new, cross-platform trivia game featuring the classic characters. In <a href=http://developer.coronalabs.com/showcase/garfields-trivia-party>Garfield’s Trivia Party</a> your job is to fill out portions of a comic strip, that have been wiped away thanks to Odie’s coffee spill. Developed by Lamplighter Games, the same folks who brought you <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2013/01/14/app-of-the-week-vidburn/>Vidburn</a>, Garfield’s Trivia Party is a free to play, turn-based game for <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/garfields-trivia-party/id607165658?ls=1&mt=8>iOS</a> and <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.lamplightergames.garfieldstriviaparty>Android</a>.</p>
<p>Playing against friends or randomly selected opponents, the game starts by spinning a wheel to determine the comic strip category. Each game displays a real Garfield comic with a portion of the text blotted out and four answers to choose from. When selecting the correct answer, you score points that can be used throughout the game. By cashing in your points or buying coins through in-app purchases, you can: opt to have the game wipe out two incorrect answers, see a community poll that illustrates how others answered the question, or get a hint that will guide you in the right direction. </p>
<p>Beyond the simple and entertaining gameplay, the schmoozy jazz music and eye-catching graphics of Garfield’s Trivia Party, make for a fun way to reminisce with your favorite gang of characters. Download Garfield’s Trivia Party for free from <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/garfields-trivia-party/id607165658?ls=1&mt=8>iTunes</a> or <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.lamplightergames.garfieldstriviaparty>Google Play</a> and test your Garfield knowledge.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/62791125" width="500" height="375" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe> </p>
<p><a href=http://vimeo.com/62791125>Garfields Trivia Party &#8211; iOS &#038; Android</a> from <a href=http://vimeo.com/lamplightergames>Lamplighter Games</a> on <a href=http://vimeo.com>Vimeo/</a>.</p>
<div class="clearfix spacerDiv"></div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/04/01/app-of-the-week-garfields-trivia-party/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Game Coder 101: Building a mobile game on the iPad (Guest post)</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/03/21/game-coder-101-building-a-mobile-game-on-the-ipad-guest-post/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/03/21/game-coder-101-building-a-mobile-game-on-the-ipad-guest-post/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 18:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Partners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tool]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=30392</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ricardo Rauber is the creator of Game Coder, a revolutionary tool that allows developers of all backgrounds, to build apps on the iPad. Best of all, Game Coder is built entirely with Corona SDK! 

Read through Ricardo's walk-through to learn more about Game Coder and to get up and running with the app.
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Ricardo Rauber is the creator of <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/game-coder/id580568570?ls=1&mt=8>Game Coder</a>, a revolutionary tool that allows developers of all backgrounds, to build apps directly on the iPad. Best of all, Game Coder is built entirely with Corona SDK! </p>
<p>Read through Ricardo&#8217;s walk-through to learn more about Game Coder and to get up and running with the app.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-20-at-2.26.08-PM-150x150.png" alt="Game Coder" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-30402" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-20-at-2.26.08-PM-150x150.png 150w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-20-at-2.26.08-PM.png 200w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />Game Coder is a wonderful new way to build your dream game on the iPad. By using simple tap and drag-and-drop features, Game Coder facilitates the game development process for newbies, skilled developers, and everything in between. Game Coder was built entirely with <a href=/products/Corona-sdk>Corona SDK</a>, and is the perfect compliment to the Corona platform.  </p>
<p>If you just want to start a project or prototype an idea, Game Coder is good for that. If you want to work directly with Lua files, you can export from Game Coder as a Corona SDK project.</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/menu-804x1024.jpg" alt="menu" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-30393" /></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s take a look at Game Coder. You can <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/game-coder/id580568570?ls=1&mt=8>download Game Coder</a> from the App Store for $9.99. On the first screen, you&#8217;ll see your projects, images, sounds and the Game Coder configuration. When you download Game Coder, you&#8217;ll see a sample project called Dogs vs. Aliens. This is a complete game made with Game Coder. It is free for everyone that downloads Game Coder and is a great sample project for testing commands and learning how to develop. Using the &#8220;?&#8221; on each screen, you can see what each component on the screen does. </p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/project-804x1024.jpg" alt="project" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-30394" /></p>
<p>When you tap on a project, it will show the project properties. Here you can change the project orientation, name and scenes. </p>
<p>By touching the &#8220;+&#8221; button, you can create a new scene where you can put objects. Touching the gear next to the scene thumbnail, you can change the scene&#8217;s name and select which scene will be first. You can also touch the trash icon, and Game Coder will ask if you really want to delete the scene. </p>
<p>Tapping the “Code” button in the top right of the screen will open the main project code, and will be similar to writing code in the main.lua file within a Corona project. The Code button is context sensitive, so it will display code for the screen or object you are working with based on where you are in Game Coder. For example, if you are on the project screen, the Code button will show the project code, if you are on the Object screen, the Code button will show the object code. We will take a look at the code screen in a moment. First, let’s cover the Scene Edit screen. Tap on a scene to view that specific scene. </p>
<p>As a side note, you can touch the big green &#8220;Play&#8221; button at the bottom of Game Coder at any time to run your game.</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/scene-804x1024.jpg" alt="scene" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-30395" /></p>
<p>Scene edit is one of the greatest things available in Game Coder. It shows a stage with the orientation of the project and all your objects listed at the bottom of the screen. You just need to touch and hold the object and drag it to the stage. After that, you can move, rotate and resize the object using two fingers, or by double tapping to edit its properties. One cool thing is that all objects work with layers. They are positioned the same way display groups are positioned in Corona. </p>
<p>At the top right you have the same Code button from the Projects screen but tapping it now shows you the scene code. When you want to create a new object, just tap the &#8220;+&#8221; button, or if you want to edit an object, just double tap on it and Game Coder will go to the next screen.</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/object-804x1024.jpg" alt="object" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-30396" /></p>
<p>Let’s look at the at the Object content. Here you can see the object images, attributes and a list of images. The object images at the top are the animation frames. You can play, stop and change the frame with commands in the code screen. </p>
<p>To add new images to the animation, just double tap on an image at the list on the bottom. These are all images imported on Game Coder. If you want to delete a frame, just touch the &#8220;trash&#8221; icon right under the appropriate image. Tap the Code button again! Now it will show the object code and we will take a look at it!</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/code-804x1024.jpg" alt="code" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-30397" /></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t be afraid of this screen, it is very simple to use and to understand! Game Coder works with drag-and-drop commands that you can choose by tapping the top right button called &#8220;Commands.&#8221; It will show a list of all commands supported by Game Coder. They are classified by the type of command. For example, math commands are grouped together, as well as physics commands, etc. </p>
<p>To add a command to the code, just touch and hold it and drag to the lines. If you drag it to the top or the bottom of the screen and the code has more lines than you can see, the code will be moved so you can put your command right where you want. For example, if you are at the line 42, you can drag the command to the top and it will start to scroll to the top of the code.</p>
<p>After adding a command, you can change its position by holding it again and dragging it. Also, you can delete it by touching the trash icon. To change commands values, touch the value you want to change and a popup will be shown with the value to be changed. </p>
<p>Finally, you need to know that all variables, timers, object names, transitions and procedures are globals, so if you create a procedure inside an object, it will be accessible to the entire project. Keep that in mind. But what if you want to create something just for that object? Just use the word &#8220;this&#8221; and Game Coder will set the values to be the object instance id. We will talk more about that in another post.</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/dropbox-804x1024.jpg" alt="dropbox" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-30398" /></p>
<p>You might be wondering how you add your own images and sounds inside Game Coder. It&#8217;s easy, you just need to use a <a href=https://www.dropbox.com/>Dropbox</a> account. Game Coder has full integration with Dropbox so you can download your content to your app. </p>
<p>Let&#8217;s see an example using an image. On the first screen of the app there is a button called Images.  You can use it to see all your downloaded images from your Dropbox account. The plus button is used to download additional assets from your Dropbox. You just need to choose &#8220;Allow&#8221; and all your files and folders will be shown on the screen. You now can just choose which file you want to download by touching it. A dialog will appear asking if you want to download it and if you choose &#8220;Yes,&#8221; Game Coder will download the image and it will be available for all your projects. Use the same procedure for importing sounds.</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/export-804x1024.jpg" alt="export" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-30399" /></p>
<p>The final thing you need to know is how to export your Game Coder projects to Corona. Choose &#8220;Projects&#8221; in the main menu and touch the little gear next to the project. A popup with two options will appear: &#8220;Corona SDK&#8221; and &#8220;Publish.&#8221; </p>
<p>If you choose &#8220;Corona SDK,&#8221; Game Coder will show your Dropbox and ask where you would like to export it. Choose a folder and Game Coder will generate all the source files, put them in a zip file, and send it to your Dropbox. </p>
<p>If you would like someone to help you publish your apps, use the Publish button. When you touch Publish, Game Coder will ask you to confirm the request and then it will e-mail you instructions for completing the publishing process. App publishing is an extra paid service provided by Beelieve. The price for publishing is determined on a case by case basis. We can provide an estimate of cost for publishing after talking with you about your project.</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/exported_object-1024x657.jpg" alt="exported_object" class="alignnone size-large wp-image-30400" /></p>
<p>After exporting your project to Corona, you will see all the supporting images, sounds, and Lua files in a Corona project folder, just as you would if you had originally created a project on your own. The naming convention for scene and object files, are &#8220;scn_&#8221; before the name of scenes and &#8220;obj_&#8221; before the name of objects. The code is all commented so you can easily understand everything. From here you can fully edit your Corona SDK project files to make your game even better with all the power of Corona!</p>
<p><em>Ricardo Rauber, Owner of Beelieve, Creator of Game Coder</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/03/21/game-coder-101-building-a-mobile-game-on-the-ipad-guest-post/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>App of the Week: Cling!</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/03/18/app-of-the-week-cling/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/03/18/app-of-the-week-cling/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 18:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arcade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=30116</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Featuring gorgeous graphics and endlessly enjoyable gameplay, this pegformer arcade game will capture your attention from the get-go. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-17-at-11.13.35-AM.png" alt="Cling! icon" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-30117" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-17-at-11.13.35-AM.png 205w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-17-at-11.13.35-AM-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 205px) 100vw, 205px" /></p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Cling-screenshot.jpg" alt="Cling! screenshot" class="alignright size-full wp-image-30118" /></p>
<p>If you embraced the cartoon-esque graphics and intuitive gameplay of <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2012/09/10/app-of-the-week-gotta-feed-garp/>Gotta Feed Garp</a>, <a href=http://developer.coronalabs.com/showcase/cling>Cling!</a> will have you instantly hooked. Cling! is a pegformer arcade game that&#8217;s developed by <a href=http://www.first5games.com/>First 5 Games</a>. The Floria based-studio&#8217;s mission is to capture a player&#8217;s attention within the first five seconds to create five lifetimes of enjoyment. By providing endlessly enjoyable gameplay and gorgeous graphics, Cling! holds true to the studio’s motto.</p>
<p>The star of Cling! Is Edgar – a six-tentacled eyeball that lives in a toy vending machine. When a child drops a quarter into the machine to retrieve a prize, Edgar has a chance at freedom. Unfortunately, Edgar’s capsule breaks and he must battle the dangers of the machine to escape. Your job is to guide him through the vending machine maze, reaching a transporter in each level, and avoiding dangerous obstacles and falls.</p>
<p>The gameplay is simple: as you touch pegs on the screen, Edgar uses a unique wall-crawling style of movement and &#8220;clings&#8221; onto the floating pegs. Your finger acts as a focal point for where Edgar travels in the maze. The blue pegs pull Edgar in, while green pegs push him away, and red blocks electrocute him. Edgar also happens to be a bit of a fashionista and loves his headgear &#8211; if you can lead Edgar to safety <em>and</em> pick up hats and other goodies along the way, you’ll earn extra points.</p>
<p>See why fans award Cling! with a 5-star average rating and check is out for $2.99 in the <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cling!/id566573977?mt=8>App Store</a>.</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Imz1668GRmw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="clearfix spacerDiv"></div>
<h3>Honorable Mention</h3>
<div class="clearfix  spacerDiv">
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-17-at-12.47.25-PM.png" alt="Russian Dolls icon" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-30125" /></a></p>
<h4 style="margin-bottom: 10px;">Russian Dolls</h4>
<p>Russian Dolls is a fun, simple dress-up game for young children, that&#8217;s both entertaining and educational. From dresses to overalls to sweaters, Russian dolls offers a variety of fun clothing options to stylishly dress the on-screen doll. As a child dresses the doll by dragging and dropping articles of clothing, the app says the name and color of each selection. Once the doll is dressed in the perfect outfit, children can even snap a photo of their creation and save it to the device&#8217;s gallery. Check out this <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk/>cross-platform game</a> in the <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/russian-dolls-dress-up-little/id594441724>App Store</a> or on <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=ru.hintsolutions.dressdoll>Google Play</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/03/18/app-of-the-week-cling/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>App of the Week: Prancing, Dancing Lily</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/03/11/app-of-the-week-prancing-dancing-lily/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/03/11/app-of-the-week-prancing-dancing-lily/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 22:12:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross-platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle Fire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[storybook]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=29866</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Based on the award-winning book by Marsha Diane Arnold, Prancing, Dancing Lily tells the story of a festive young milking cow that doesn’t quite fit the herd.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-08-at-4.54.06-PM.png" alt="Lily icon" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-29867" />Based on the award-winning book by Marsha Diane Arnold, <a href=http://developer.coronalabs.com/showcase/prancing-dancing-lily>Prancing, Dancing Lily</a> tells the story of a festive young milking cow that doesn’t quite fit the herd. Brought to the digital world by <a href=http://fatredcouch.com/index.php>Fat Red Couch</a>, this heartwarming tale features whimsical illustrations, expressive characters and unique narration that readers of all ages will appreciate.</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Prancing-Dancing-Lily-screenshot.jpg" alt="Prancing, Dancing Lily screenshot" class="alignright size-full wp-image-29868" />Lily, the leading lady, comes from a long line of responsible cow-bellers; yet she herself is clumsy, inattentive and always dancing around the field at the wrong times. Once she realizes she&#8217;s different from her peers, Lily embarks on an adventure, traveling the world in search of the perfect dance. Thanks to her spunky nature, she has the opportunity to grace Radio City Music Hall as a Rockette, learns to tap dance on a cruise ship, and pirouettes on stage as a ballerina in Russia. Through her adventures, Lily learns an important lesson on self acceptance, and returns home to share her exciting new dances with the friends on the farm.</p>
<p>Can Lily sway her herd and become an accepted member? Download Prancing, Dancing Lily for $1.99 from <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/prancing-dancing-lily/id586489276?mt=8>App Store</a>, <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.fatredcouch.pdlilyandroid>Google Play</a>, or the <a href=http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00BDBAVFY/ref=mas_pm_Fat-Red-Couch-Inc-Prancing>Amazon Appstore</a> and find out!</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/BrmH60mYDSc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="clearfix spacerDiv"></div>
<h3>Honorable Mention</h3>
<div class="clearfix  spacerDiv">
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-11-at-1.33.14-PM.png" alt="Brickout Zero Gravity" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-29881" /></a></p>
<h4 style="margin-bottom: 10px;">Brickout Zero Gravity</h4>
<p>Brickout Zero Gravity removes the shackles of Breakout and turns you loose in a challenging arcade game where physics are king. Keep a ricocheting ball in play by moving a paddle on one side of the screen while targeting and smashing bricks on the other. Clear the board to progress to the next level and earn power-ups to give you an edge. Check out Brickout Zero Gravity for $1.99 from the <a href= http://appstore.com/brickoutzerogravity>App Store</a>.</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/qMXIe5Pn-gs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/03/11/app-of-the-week-prancing-dancing-lily/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest Post: Making Progress as a Solo Mobile Game Developer</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/03/08/guest-post-making-progress-as-a-solo-mobile-game-developer/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/03/08/guest-post-making-progress-as-a-solo-mobile-game-developer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 22:57:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=29851</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Making games can be a lot fun, but it can also be a tremendous amount of work. Many people try to create games on their own but far fewer actually succeed -- myself included.

With Kung-Fu Clash, I decided to try things differently than on previous projects. This post discusses some of the approaches that helped me to successfully publish my first game.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Hugo Bonacci is the indie developer and designer of App of the Week winner, <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2012/11/26/app-of-the-week-kung-fu-clash/>Kung-Fu Clash</a>. His passion for gaming began at a young each and Hugo is still a big fan of NES and SNES games (he even plays them with his kids!) and is inspired by games such as Final Fantasy, Zelda, Secret of Mana, and Chrono Trigger.</p>
<p>During the day, Hugo works as a UX Consultant for a company in Dallas, Texas, but his real passion lies in game development. Check out Hugo&#8217;s software development blog and design portfolio at <a href=http://hugoware.net>hugoware.net/</a>.</em></p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Kung-Fu-Clash-150x128.png" alt="Kung-Fu Clash" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-29854" />Making games can be a lot fun, but it can also be a tremendous amount of work. Many people try to create games on their own but far fewer actually succeed &#8212; myself included.</p>
<p>With <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/kung-fu-clash/id571843687?mt=8>Kung-Fu Clash</a> I decided to try things differently than on previous projects. This post discusses some of the approaches that helped me to successfully publish my first game.</p>
<p><strong>Design First</strong></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t be in a hurry to start writing code for your game. Take your time and plan what your game is about, how it works, and get a general idea of what needs to be done. It&#8217;s much quicker to find flaws on paper than to spend hours writing code only to discover an idea won&#8217;t work.</p>
<p>Try to come up with an idea that makes your game distinct from others. Sometimes it&#8217;s as simple as taking a common gaming category (for example, a first person shooter) and giving it a unique twist (e.g. adding orange and blue portals!).</p>
<p>You don&#8217;t need to have a detailed outline of every single screen and behavior in your game. I&#8217;ve found that simple sketches and notes are more than enough to get ideas out of your head.</p>
<p>Planning shouldn&#8217;t be limited to only the start of a project. Any time you want to add a feature or modify the way something works, take some time to jot your ideas down before you begin.</p>
<p><strong>Keep Things Simple</strong></p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Ninja-mockups-264x300.png" alt="Ninja mockups" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-29857" /><br />
As with any project, the number of tasks required for completion can quickly spiral out of control. Each time you think you&#8217;ve identified everything that needs to be done you end up noticing an entirely new set of tasks you&#8217;ve missed.</p>
<p>Start by creating a list of the core requirements for your game, this means removing non-essential game elements like power-ups, high-scores, etc. Next, include each of the sprites, animations, backgrounds, music and other creative assets you&#8217;ll need to create. Lastly, don&#8217;t forget to include tasks that are generally overlooked until they&#8217;re needed, such as managing user settings, handling transitions between scenes, game menus, resource management, etc.</p>
<p>It doesn&#8217;t take long before your &#8220;simple&#8221; game becomes a daunting list work that will take several weeks to finish. Don&#8217;t let this intimidate you. Having an overview of tasks to complete will help you set goals and track progress along the way.</p>
<p>Lastly, if you want to add something to your game then go through this process again. Ask yourself what you will need to code and design to make it happen. Once you&#8217;ve figured out what needs to be done, decide if you really need the feature or if it can wait.</p>
<p>Keeping things simple sometimes means telling yourself &#8220;no&#8221; about adding features to your game.</p>
<p><strong>Stay Focused</strong></p>
<p>It&#8217;s easy to get discouraged when you&#8217;re the only person working on a project, especially when progress is slow or you&#8217;ve been working for several months, but fortunately there are a couple ways to stay motivated.</p>
<p>First, start by sharing your progress with friends, family, and social networks. Let people see what you&#8217;re working on and share in your excitement. Put your game on a device and let people to try it. It&#8217;s exciting, and highly motivating, to see your game in action.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t be discouraged if it doesn&#8217;t work correctly &#8212; it&#8217;s just a demo. Additionally, don&#8217;t act on user feedback immediately. Unless it&#8217;s a critical flaw, simply take note of their suggestions and then review it later. Trying to implement new ideas, even good ones, will slow down progress.</p>
<p>Second, If you find yourself feeling unmotivated, overwhelmed, or simply confused on what you should be doing, then it&#8217;s probably a sign you need to get organized. Take some time to examine your project and write a list of remaining tasks. Simply knowing what needs to be done can go a long way in keeping a project on track.</p>
<p>When you sit down to work, review your list and set yourself a goal of at least one task (or more) to finish and then mark them off as you go.</p>
<p><strong>Use Time Wisely</strong></p>
<p>Try and find ways to preview your ideas before you attempt to write code. For example, I use Flash for character design and animation, but it also works well for visualizing how a character looks moving across a background or to quickly experiment with different kinds of special effects.</p>
<p>Creating art for a game is a very time consuming process so be sure to plan for high resolution displays early by using vector art, 3D, or very large PSDs. Don&#8217;t try and create your own sprite sheets by hand, but instead use applications like <a href=http://www.codeandweb.com/texturepacker>TexturePacker</a> or Zwoptex to streamline the process.</p>
<p>Consider using stock resources for assets you’re not able to create for yourself. For example, I’m not a musician and I’ve wasted weeks of development time in the past trying to create music only to end up with sub-par results. For this project I decided to purchase royalty-free music instead. Not only did the music sound far superior to anything I would have created on my own, it saved a lot of time as a result.</p>
<p>Avoid writing code if an open-source library is available that does the same thing. Even if it&#8217;s not an exact match, it&#8217;s much quicker to modify an existing library than write one from scratch. As interesting as writing &#8220;framework code&#8221; can be, your time is better spent focused on code specific to your game.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t be afraid to spend time on writing scripts that automate repetitive tasks. If you find yourself doing the same process a couple times then it&#8217;s a perfect candidate for automation. When you&#8217;re the only person working on a project, the time spent on tedious activities is time taken away from meaningful accomplishments.</p>
<p>Lastly, avoid over-engineering your code. This isn&#8217;t a call for haphazard programming, but instead a reminder that the most perfectly abstracted code base that never ships is still a failure. Try to reuse code whenever possible (DRY), write helpful comments, and use meaningful function and variable names, but your primary focus should be on creating a flawless user experience. </p>
<p><strong>Don&#8217;t Settle</strong></p>
<p>Look carefully at every detail in your game and never accept &#8220;good enough.&#8221; If you aren&#8217;t happy with something, or it doesn&#8217;t &#8216;feel&#8217; right, then there&#8217;s a good chance that your audience won&#8217;t like it either. Polish every detail until you feel it&#8217;s perfect. Treat your game as if it were a masterpiece &#8212; it deserves no less!</p>
<p>It&#8217;s difficult being the only person working on a project, but it also means you&#8217;re the only one who decides what goes into the final product. Take advantage of having complete control and only accept your best work!</p>
<p><em>Hugo Bonacci, Creator of King-Fu Clash</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/03/08/guest-post-making-progress-as-a-solo-mobile-game-developer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
