<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Corona SDK &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/corona-sdk/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Corona SDK &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Using Corona SDK at Global Game Jam 2016</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/01/27/global-game-jam-2016-tools-2d-game-development-using-corona-sdk/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 22:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GGJ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Global Game Jam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hackathon]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=65412</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We're just days away from Global Game Jam 2016, the largest game hackathon of the year. Learn how you can attend and how you can use Corona SDK to jam!]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re just days away from <a href=http://globalgamejam.org/ target="_blank">Global Game Jam 2016</a>, the largest game hackathon of the year.<br />
<img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-65415" style="margin: 20px 0px 20px 20px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/GGJ-round-logo-150x150.png" alt="GGJ round logo" width="150" height="150" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/GGJ-round-logo-150x150.png 150w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/GGJ-round-logo-300x300.png 300w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/GGJ-round-logo-768x768.png 768w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/GGJ-round-logo-570x570.png 570w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/GGJ-round-logo-500x500.png 500w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/GGJ-round-logo-700x700.png 700w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/GGJ-round-logo.png 900w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /><br />
If you haven&#8217;t heard about it before, Global Game Jam is a great opportunity for both veteran and novice game developers to gather together, collaborate, and make games over the course of one weekend.</p>
<p>In addition to deciding to attend and actually forming a team, choosing a game development tool is one of the main decisions you&#8217;ll have to make. Fortunately, Corona SDK is listed as one of the top tools and technologies in the website&#8217;s list of platforms, so be sure to select it as your platform of choice.</p>
<h3>Why you should choose Corona SDK</h3>
<p><strong>Speed</strong> &#8212; Corona is excellent for rapid prototyping. When you save your code, the Corona Simulator detects the changed file and instantly refreshes itself so that you see the changes instantly. Corona SDK is also based on Lua which is an <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/guide/start/introLua/index.html>easy-to-learn language</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Rich API ecosystem</strong> &#8212; Corona SDK provides an <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/index.html>extensive API set</a> for creating/manipulating images and sprites, playing audio, applying physics, and interacting with game elements. Corona also provides a scene management library to make multiple screens/levels simple. Finally, an ever-expanding <a href=https://store.coronalabs.com>plugin/ library</a> allows you to extend your app beyond the already robust API set.</p>
<p><strong>Diverse platform deployment</strong> &#8212; While Corona SDK is known for being a mobile development platform (iOS, Android, and Windows Phone 8), it is also a TV platform, featuring support for Android TV and Apple&#8217;s new tvOS. Even more important is that Corona SDK can also build to both Windows x86 and OS X desktop. Thus, using the same code base, you can target a whole set of entertainment platforms.</p>
<p><strong>Learning resources</strong> &#8212; Looking for the proper resources to get started? We&#8217;ve got it covered!</p>
<ul>
<li><a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/ target="_blank">Documentation and guides</a> &#8212; Each <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/ target="_blank">API</a> is documented and a collection of <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/guide/index.html target="_blank">guides</a> cover essential topics.</li>
<li><a href=https://github.com/coronalabs/samples-coronasdk target="_blank">Sample code</a> &#8212; Some developers learn best by inspecting existing code. We have many examples which you can use as foundational aspects for your game.</li>
</ul>
<div style="background-color: #fed; border: 1px solid #ccc; padding: 12px 10px 10px 10px;"><a href=/blog/2013/04/19/guest-piece-a-global-game-jam-ggj-developer-story-san-francisco-style/ target="_blank">Read about the experience</a> of a team of Corona developers from Global Game Jam 2013!</div>
<h3>Get started!</h3>
<p>Ready to attend <a href=http://globalgamejam.org/user/signup/to/participate/using target="_blank">Global Game Jam 2016</a>? Sign up on their <a href=http://globalgamejam.org/user/signup/to/participate/using target="_blank">website</a> as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Next, <a href=/products/corona-sdk/ target="_blank">download Corona SDK</a>. With rapid prototyping, a <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/index.html>robust API set</a>, a diverse range of deployable platforms, and plenty of learning resources, Corona is the perfect tool for developing your 2D game at Global Game Jam 2016 and beyond.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Knitty Kitty: Achieving the Impossible in 8 Hours</title>
		<link>/blog/2015/04/23/knitty-kitty-achieving-the-impossible-in-8-hours/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2015/04/23/knitty-kitty-achieving-the-impossible-in-8-hours/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 21:04:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brent Sorrentino]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Game Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=62537</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this guest post, the folks at Playcrafting and Simple Machine discuss how a match three puzzle game was developed in Corona SDK within a single eight hour session, from design decisions to code editing to assembly of promotional material leading up to the game's release.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i>This guest post comes to you courtesy of Dan Butchko at Playcrafting and Kurt Bieg at </i><a href=http://www.simplemachine.co/ target="_blank"><i>Simple Machine</i></a><i>. Playcrafting offers workshops, classes, and events for game developers and those aspiring to make games. To learn more and see what they have coming up, check out </i><a href=http://www.playcrafting.com/ target="_blank"><i>Playcrafting.com</i></a><i>. You can download the game discussed in this post from </i><a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.playcrafting.knittykitty&hl=en target="_blank"><i>the Google Play Store</i></a><i>.</i></p>
<hr />
<p>Late one winter day in New York City, we met to plan upcoming game classes for the robust community of skilled game developers that Playcrafting serves. We started to kick around ideas for educational content that would push the boundaries of traditional instruction. There are plenty of &#8220;Learn X in a day&#8221; classes and workshops, but we realized that none took that next step to show how much goes into the actual release of a game.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s when we jumped at the idea of doing a one-day workshop where the group designs a game from start to finish, then releases it on the store. As an alternative education provider without the recognition of an established university, it’s always a challenge at Playcrafting to show potential students the direct takeaways they will receive from a one-day workshop. We kept thinking about how amazing it would be for students to see their game available for download to the public by the time they got home from the full day workshop.</p>
<p>On the flip side, we realized how groundbreaking this experience would be by showing people just how much work goes into the release of a game, not just on the development side, but also in marketing preparation from creating promotional images to writing the description and uploading the build. Anyone who has shipped a game can tell you that once you&#8217;re done coding, you&#8217;re only half done with getting your game in the hands of players. There&#8217;s all this additional work needed to make your game available to the public, and you can feel blindsided if you don&#8217;t know about it.</p>
<p>The end result of our planning was our “Release Your First Game: Puzzle Edition!” full day workshop. We somehow came up with the perfect takeaway for students: Design and release a game in one day with your name on it. What better way to inspire newcomers to start making games or re-energize veteran developers?</p>
<h3>From the Start</h3>
<p>In one very short eight hour session, we transformed the room into a temporary development studio. Kurt led the group to make live design decisions, edit code and assemble promotional material leading up to release of the game on Google Play at the end of the day. To expedite the process of development and release in one short day, we chose to do a match three puzzle game using Corona SDK.</p>
<p>Working off of a shared Game Design Document, attendees contributed ideas and assets throughout the day. The group used a basic match three puzzle game template as a starting point to then create their own game using Corona SDK. The entire class designed concepts that changed the game in completely unpredictable ways. By the end, we were sifting through ideas and prototyping them live. After settling on a brilliant mechanic where only one piece on the board can be swapped, the class came up with a bunch of themes for the game. Ultimately we arrived at cats, ‘nuff said. The theme of the game became a cat that can move around the board and swap different colored balls of yarn to make a match of three or more. It wasn&#8217;t perfect at first and required several rounds of iteration and testing on Corona SDK, but the team kept pushing until we had something that worked.</p>
<h3>To the End</h3>
<p><a href=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/knitty-kitty-2.jpg><img class="alignright wp-image-62541" style="margin: 0px 0px 20px 25px;" src=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/knitty-kitty-2.jpg alt="knitty-kitty-2" width="260" height="390" /></a>After the game was complete, we had to switch gears and set up the store. With only a few hours left, we generated screenshots, collaborated on a description and came up with too many good names (imagine infinite cat puns). Of course, once &#8220;Knitty Kitty&#8221; was on the table, nothing else even came close. Students jumped in to apply their own skill sets to assets that were needed. One handled the logo, a sub-group whipped up a great description and others used the character and tile assets to enhance sample screens.</p>
<p>It was a mad dash to the end to get the game built out and published to the Google Play Store, but we managed to pull it off. Lo and behold, by the time 5pm came around, we were ecstatic about the success of our mock dev team and Knitty Kitty was live on the store. Students were thrilled to take photos of the build loading into the store and grab the code so they could head home and continue tweaking it in Corona SDK.</p>
<p>This trial workshop was such a success that we’re now doing it once per month using different game genres. It was tremendously empowering for attendees to see how easy and fun it can be to make games. We somehow achieved the impossible — transforming a room of strangers into a team of developers then building and publishing a game in one day. And we would not have been able to do so without the Playcrafting’s enthusiastic community or the ease and accessibility of Corona SDK.</p>
<hr />
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2015/04/23/knitty-kitty-achieving-the-impossible-in-8-hours/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corona SDK is now Free + Mac/Win Desktop Apps + GDC</title>
		<link>/blog/2015/03/02/corona-sdk-is-now-free/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2015/03/02/corona-sdk-is-now-free/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[walter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News & Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App Monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gdc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mac app]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Win app]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=61617</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We have to big announcements! Corona SDK is now completely free, and Mac and Win32 desktop apps are coming soon. Read on for all the details.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week, to coincide with GDC, we&#8217;re making some very exciting announcements!</p>
<h3>Corona SDK is completely FREE</h3>
<p><a href=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/free.png><img src=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/free.png alt="free" width="150" height="150" class="alignright size-full wp-image-61628" /></a>First, Corona SDK is now <a href=/pricing target="_blank">completely free</a>! Starting today, anyone who registers on our site will get the full power of Corona SDK (existing users can just logout and then re-login to the Corona Simulator).</p>
<p>Previously, you had to pay to get access to things like daily builds, in-app purchases, premium graphics, Pro-tier plugins, Windows Phone 8, etc. — now, everyone will get those for free. If you&#8217;re familiar with the old subscription tiers for Corona SDK (Starter, Basic, and Pro), everyone will now get the functionality that was available in Pro. There is now a single &#8220;Corona SDK&#8221; — one tier to rule them all.</p>
<p>It is worth noting that Corona Enterprise, CoronaCards iOS, and CoronaCards Android will continue to be paid products.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re an <strong>existing subscriber</strong> — Basic, Pro, or Enterprise — see <a href="#Subscriber-Upgrades">Free Upgrades for Subscribers</a> at the bottom of this post to learn about some great upgrades.</p>
<h3>Mac App and Win32 App support</h3>
<p><a href=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Mac-Win.png><img src=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Mac-Win.png alt="Mac+Win" width="168" height="76" class="alignright size-full wp-image-61620" /></a>In my <a href=/blog/2015/01/30/state-of-corona-thoughts-and-reflections-2015/>State of Corona</a> address, I mentioned new platforms as a major theme for 2015 and our strategy to make it happen.</p>
<p>And that brings us to our second major announcement: We are bringing Mac App and Win32 App support to the Corona platform!</p>
<p>Yes, you read that right.</p>
<p>We are going to make it incredibly easy for you to create apps that run everywhere — from desktop computers to mobile devices!</p>
<p>Currently, we are in the early stages. Our next milestone is to be able to package this up into a form that can be shared in a beta. More on this soon.</p>
<p>But we have some demos: come by the Fuse Powered/Corona Labs booth at the GDC Expo (Booth 1244, South Hall) this week if you&#8217;d like to see a few really great Corona apps running on desktop computers — as apps! We&#8217;ll also publish some videos of these here on the blog very soon.</p>
<h3>Fuse Powered monetization</h3>
<p><a href=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/treasure-chest.jpg><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/treasure-chest-300x188.jpg" alt="treasure-chest" width="300" height="188" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-61622" /></a>Finally, our parent company, <a href=http://fusepowered.com/>Fuse Powered</a>, is taking monetization to a whole new level with a its player-centric monetization engine. See some <a href=http://venturebeat.com/2015/02/24/fuse-powered-launches-player-centric-mobile-monetization-engine/ target="_blank">recent coverage in VentureBeat</a>.</p>
<p>With this engine, you&#8217;ll be able to do 3 things. First, you&#8217;ll be able to analyze your players, and make meaningful conclusions from their in-game behavior. Next, you&#8217;ll be able to segment them based on these behaviors and figure out the most relevant offer to show them. Finally, you&#8217;ll be able to deliver targeted IAP offers, dynamic rewarded video, and ads.</p>
<p>On top of it all, you&#8217;ll also be able to mediate your own ad networks and leverage AdRally, Fuse’s competitive ad marketplace.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s nothing on the market like this today, and it all translates into helping you make significantly more money!</p>
<p>While select Corona developers are already in private beta with Fuse Powered, we are working hard to nail down all the moving parts — there are a lot of them. Rest assured, we want to get this into your hands as quickly as possible.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;d like to learn more, come to Jon&#8217;s session at GDC on Tuesday, Mar 3: <a href=http://schedule.gdconf.com/session/player-centric-live-ops-monetization-presented-by-fuse-powered-inc>Player Centric Live Ops Monetization</a>.</p>
<p>Or come by the Fuse Powered/Corona Labs booth at the GDC Expo (Booth 1244, South Hall).</p>
<p><a name="Subscriber-Upgrades"></a></p>
<h3>Free Upgrades for Subscribers</h3>
<p>Now that Corona is free, we do realize there are many of you that have bought/renewed your Corona subscriptions recently and we want to make sure we take care of you. If you were an existing Basic, Pro, or Enterprise customer as of this morning, we&#8217;re going to give you some amazing, free upgrades:</p>
<ol>
<li>Current Corona Enterprise customers get CoronaCards iOS and CoronaCards Android licenses (1 month for each month you have left).</li>
<li>Current Corona SDK Pro customers have been upgraded to Corona Enterprise (1.5 months for each month you have left) and will also get CoronaCards iOS/Android.</li>
<li>Current Basic customers have been upgraded to Corona Enterprise (1 month for each month you have left) and will also get CoronaCards iOS/Android.</li>
</ol>
<p>All these upgrades should be in place NOW, but it&#8217;s possible some of you may have to wait a day or so to see the full upgrade.</p>
<p>However, if you&#8217;re a Basic or Pro customer <strong>who bought in 2015 (Jan 1, 2015 or after)</strong>, and you do <strong>not</strong> want these upgrades, you can request a <em>pro-rated</em> refund. Email us at refund@coronalabs.com by Mar 15, 2015 11:59pm PST. If you meet the conditions, we will issue a refund within a few days.</p>
<p>If you have any questions, please review <a href=/frequently-asked-questions/?#what-does-it-mean-that-corona-sdk-is-now-free>the FAQs</a>. If you still have questions or want to discuss, feel free to post in <a href=http://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/54933-corona-sdk-is-now-free/>this thread in the forum</a> and we will do our best to make it all clear!</p>
<hr />
<p>We are super excited about making Corona SDK free and opening it up to an even bigger worldwide developer community. This, together with our expanded platform coverage and the work we are doing with Fuse Powered is making for the start of a great year!</p>
<p>And, as always, we want to thank all our developers for using Corona and for making some amazing things with the Corona platform!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2015/03/02/corona-sdk-is-now-free/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>123</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Game Legend John Romero Joins as Advisor, Talks Corona SDK</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/10/24/game-legend-john-romero-joins-as-advisor-talks-corona-sdk/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/10/24/game-legend-john-romero-joins-as-advisor-talks-corona-sdk/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 13:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[walter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News & Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Videos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advisor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[john romero]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.coronalabs.com/?p=50340</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today, I'm super happy to announce that John Romero has joined as an advisor! John has had an extremely prolific career across over a hundred games, including the iconic works Wolfenstein 3D, DOOM and Quake. He has seemingly boundless energy. He's not only working on new games, but he's also teaching classes in mobile game development and is a tireless advocate for indie game development.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, I&#8217;m super happy to announce that John Romero has joined as an advisor! John has had an extremely prolific career across over a hundred games, including the iconic works Wolfenstein 3D, DOOM and Quake. He has seemingly boundless energy. He&#8217;s not only working on new games, but he&#8217;s also teaching classes in mobile game development and is a tireless advocate for indie game development.</p>
<p>I recently sat down with John to talk about his experiences, perspective on the industry, the challenges facing game developers today, and (of course) what he loves about <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk/>Corona</a>. Here are highlights from that conversation:</p>
<p><iframe width="640" height="436" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/h2QofXwm384?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/10/24/game-legend-john-romero-joins-as-advisor-talks-corona-sdk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corona Editor + Sublime Text</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/10/14/corona-editor-sublime-text/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/10/14/corona-editor-sublime-text/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 21:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[walter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News & Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sublime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[text editor]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.coronalabs.com/?p=49156</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One of our guiding principles in building Corona SDK was that the developer experience mattered. This means enabling you to do things as quickly and easily as possible. Simplicity is key - we want to take something complex and remove all the unnecessary elements, so you can focus on the work that matters.

Recently, we decided to extend that point of view to the actual coding experience. Now the community has already produced some fantastic <a href="/resources/3rd-party-tools-and-services/">mobile tools and IDEs</a>, so instead, we looked at the more basic problem of editing code.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of our guiding principles in building Corona SDK was that the developer experience mattered. This means enabling you to do things as quickly and easily as possible. Simplicity is key &#8211; we want to take something complex and remove all the unnecessary elements, so you can focus on the work that matters.</p>
<p>Recently, we decided we wanted to extend that point of view to the actual coding experience. Now the community has already produced some fantastic <a href=/resources/3rd-party-tools-and-services/>mobile tools and IDEs</a>, so instead, we looked at the more basic problem of editing code.</p>
<h2>Corona Editor</h2>
<p><img src="http://www.coronalabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/Corona-Editor-Sublime-300x109.png" alt="Corona-Editor-Sublime" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-49393" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/Corona-Editor-Sublime-300x109.png 300w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/Corona-Editor-Sublime.png 352w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Today, I&#8217;m happy to announce Corona Editor (Beta), our answer to the old problem of making code editing painless. It takes what we think is the world&#8217;s best text editor, Sublime Text, and provides first-class integration with Corona SDK. </p>
<p>Take a look at this video tour to see how Corona Editor is a natural fit with the Corona philosophy of keeping the tool lightweight, so you&#8217;re able to make good use of it immediately:</p>
<p><iframe width="640" height="480" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/emWUcaX-tyw?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>As you can see, initial features include code completion for all APIs and constants, the ability to bring up API docs directly from your code (public release or daily build docs), and hot keys to launch your app in the Corona Simulator from Sublime. </p>
<p>There are still bugs to be worked out as it&#8217;s still in Beta, but you can play with it today! Head over to Corona Editor for instructions on how to install Sublime Text and the Corona Editor package.</p>
<h2>Open Source</h2>
<p><img src="http://www.coronalabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/github-logo-300x118.png" alt="github-logo" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-49394" />We are making Corona Editor completely <a href=https://github.com/coronalabs/CoronaSDK-SublimeText>open source</a>, so send us your pull requests. Your contributions will help the entire Corona community!</p>
<p>In terms of future improvements, we&#8217;re looking at console integration directly in the Sublime editor and debugging support for breakpoints. Let us know if you&#8217;d like to help!</p>
<p>One of the things we hope this plugin will do is improve code editing in other text editors and IDEs. The Corona Editor project comes with a <a href=https://github.com/coronalabs/CoronaSDK-SublimeText/blob/master/gen_completions/raw-api-definitions>raw list of Corona APIs</a>. They&#8217;re generated straight from our docs to enable code completions in Corona Editor. We will automatically be updating this file to reflect changes in daily builds, so this should be especially handy for enabling completions in other text editors and IDEs.</p>
<p><em>Special thanks to Christopher Spence for his invaluable insights and feedback during development.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/10/14/corona-editor-sublime-text/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Public Release</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/09/04/new-public-release-2/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/09/04/new-public-release-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 23:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[walter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News & Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Analytics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GameStick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nvidia shield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ouya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[socialkit]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.coronalabs.com/?p=43816</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[</a>Today, we are announcing our latest Public Release, 2013.1202. It's immediately available for <a href="https://developer.coronalabs.com/downloads/corona-sdk">download</a> for your <a href="/products/corona-sdk/">app development</a> pleasure!

There are a lots of improvements in the <a href="https://developer.coronalabs.com/content/corona-sdk-release-notes-build-2013-1202">release notes</a>, so I'll just highlight a few.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/130327_ouya_0021.jpg><img src=http://www.coronalabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/130327_ouya_0021.jpg alt="Ouya corona sdk" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-43820" /></a>Today, we are announcing our latest Public Release, 2013.1202. It&#8217;s immediately available for <a href=https://developer.coronalabs.com/downloads/corona-sdk>download</a> for your <a href=/products/corona-sdk/>app development</a> pleasure!</p>
<p>There are a lots of improvements in the <a href=https://developer.coronalabs.com/content/corona-sdk-release-notes-build-2013-1202>release notes</a>, so I&#8217;ll just highlight a few.</p>
<p>First, we&#8217;ve added Ouya, GameStick, and NVIDIA Shield support. This includes support for game controllers and joysticks on those devices. We&#8217;ve also added general support for HID-based devices on Android, so you can connect your keyboard, mouse, and touchpad. If you have a MOGA Pro or a Sony PS3 controller, those are HID-based and work as well!</p>
<p>While we&#8217;re on the gaming theme, we&#8217;ve added real-time multiplayer support via Google Play game services on Android. And we&#8217;ve added turn-based multiplayer support via Game Center on iOS. We&#8217;ve also partnered with <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2013/08/15/guest-piece-photon-cloud-corona-sdk-a-dream-team-for-cross-platform-multiplayer-games/>Photon Cloud</a> for real-time multiplayer support across iOS and Android.</p>
<p>For more business-oriented apps, we&#8217;ve added several features like left/center/right alignment to &#8216;display.newText&#8217;. We&#8217;ve also started to offer support for the iOS SocialKit framework. This is done via a plugin to the &#8216;native.showPopup&#8217; API that lets you post on Facebook, Twitter, and Weibo. We added Address Book popup as an iOS plugin as well.</p>
<p>On the monetization and services side, our roster of 3rd party plugins continues to grow:</p>
<p><a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/PastedGraphic-2.png><img src="http://www.coronalabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/PastedGraphic-2-216x300.png" alt="corona amplitude analytics" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-43818" /></a></p>
<p>* Google Game Play Services<br />
* Vungle<br />
* CrossInstall<br />
* AppRever<br />
* Pinsight Media+</p>
<p>Finally, the last thing I&#8217;ll highlight is we are upgrading our old analytics (a.k.a. LaunchPad) to <a href=https://amplitude.com/>Amplitude</a>. If you&#8217;ve ever played with other analytics services, one thing you know is that you can often wait a day or longer before you see data. As things scale up, you might experience a few hours delay, but Amplitude&#8217;s goal is to give you near real-time data!</p>
<p>As part of this upgrade, we&#8217;ve also cleaned up the web dashboard. We think it&#8217;s a lot more usable and the information is presented in a manner that will help you understand your customers a lot better. During the transition, the old dashboard will not display your data properly.</p>
<p>In terms of timing, the entire transition is happening right now, and we hope to have it completed by the end of September. The great thing is, you won&#8217;t have to do a thing to take advantage of the basic service — it&#8217;s free!</p>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/09/04/new-public-release-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corona weekly update: Turn-based multiplayer support</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/07/31/corona-weekly-update-turn-based-multiplayer-support/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/07/31/corona-weekly-update-turn-based-multiplayer-support/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2013 13:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[walter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Build]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iOS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multiplayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[turn-based]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.coronalabs.com/?p=39663</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ready to invite your friends to play your latest game? You're in luck! 

Starting in Daily Build #1172, you can <a href="http://www.coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk/">develop iOS games</a> that take full advantage of turn-based multiplayer features in Game Center.

We've built all these features into the 'gameNetwork' library so whether you have existing code or new code, it'll be a cinch to use. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/Game-Center-icon1.png><img src=http://www.coronalabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/Game-Center-icon1.png alt="Game-Center-icon" class="alignright size-full wp-image-39677" /></a>Ready to invite your friends to play your latest game? You&#8217;re in luck!</p>
<p>Starting in Daily Build #1172, you can <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk/>develop iOS games</a> that take full advantage of turn-based multiplayer features in Game Center.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve built all these features into the &#8216;gameNetwork&#8217; library so whether you have existing code or new code, it&#8217;ll be a cinch to use.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a full sample available: <a href=https://github.com/coronalabs/gameNetwork-iOS-turnbased-multiplayer>https://github.com/coronalabs/gameNetwork-iOS-turnbased-multiplayer</a>.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a quick tour:</p>
<p>To invite players, you create a match with specific player id&#8217;s:</p>
<p></p><pre class="crayon-plain-tag">gameNetwork.request( &quot;createMatch&quot;,
{
    playerIDs = {&quot;w4o98y3498hg349h&quot;, &quot;wrighfq547hg543&quot;},
    listener=requestCallback
})</pre><p></p>
<p>To auto-match players, you also create a match but you specify the number of players you want to match:</p>
<p></p><pre class="crayon-plain-tag">gameNetwork.request( &quot;createMatch&quot;,
{
    minPlayers = 2,
    maxPlayers = 3,
    listener=requestCallback
})</pre><p></p>
<p>You can also mix and match, inviting some some players and then also auto match players to the same match:</p>
<p></p><pre class="crayon-plain-tag">gameNetwork.request( &quot;createMatch&quot;,
{
    playerIDs = {&quot;w4o98y3498hg349h&quot;, &quot;wrighfq547hg543&quot;},
    minPlayers = 2,
    maxPlayers = 3,
    listener=requestCallback
})</pre><p></p>
<p>When the request listener is fired, the events contain a property &#8216;event.type&#8217; that takes on the following values:</p>
<ul>
<li>invitationReceived </li>
<li>matchEnded </li>
<li>playerTurn</li>
</ul>
<p>Perhaps the coolest thing is that notifications that tell you it&#8217;s your turn are automatic, so you don&#8217;t need to do anything!</p>
<p>Happy coding!</p>
<p>[Update] We also plan to add support for Game Center features added to iOS 6 such as invite messages, player attributes, and player groups.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/07/31/corona-weekly-update-turn-based-multiplayer-support/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corona Weekly Update: Fixing bugs</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/06/24/corona-weekly-update-fixing-bugs/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/06/24/corona-weekly-update-fixing-bugs/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 06:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[walter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Build]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[polish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[widget]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.coronalabs.com/?p=36763</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While we work on lots of features that make <a href="/products/corona-sdk/">mobile app development</a> easier, I want to highlight all the bug fixing that's been going on in parallel.

We've been very vigilant about regressions introduced in daily builds, but if there was one eye sore in our bugbase it was the bugs in the widget framework. We have attacked them with renewed vigor. 
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While we work on lots of features that make <a href=/products/corona-sdk/>mobile app development</a> easier, I want to highlight all the bug fixing that&#8217;s been going on in parallel.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve been very vigilant about regressions introduced in daily builds, but if there was one eye sore in our bugbase it was the bugs in the widget framework. We have attacked them with renewed vigor.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a list of the widget enhancements we&#8217;ve made:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixes the tableView scrollbar skinning with imageSheets. Fixes casenum 23646.</li>
<li>Corrects the switch instantiation via image sheet. Fixes casenum 23648.</li>
<li>Adds a custom params table to the insertRow ethod of the tableview, allowing for easy attachment of custom data to table rows. Fixes casenum 23811.</li>
<li>Fixes the touch permission variable or tableviews if the view has hit bottom or top limit. Fixes casenum 23406.</li>
<li>Added instance methods setScrollWidth() / setScrollHeight(). Fixes casenum 22869, casenum 21859.</li>
<li>Exposes the stepper inc/dec speed and iteration number properties. Fixes casenum 21958.</li>
<li>Creates the API method resizeView( newWidth ) for the progressView widget, allowing resize after creation. Fixes casenum 21874.</li>
<li>Enables choosing elements in the picker widget by tapping on them. Fixes casenum 21788</li>
<li>Fixes the tabBar selected image to scale to custom height if defined. Fixes casenum 21961.</li>
<li>Return the correct value in the Picker when the user taps on a value. Casenum 24148</li>
<li>Removed delay in resetting the tapped cell&#8217;s background color. Casenum 24263</li>
<li>Picker view autocap text when defining large labels, and solving up the scroll issues at high speed to one of the list ends. Casenum 23290</li>
<li>fixes involuntary scrolling after tapping and holding. Casenum 24244, 22607</li>
<li>Added tap event to the tabbar, fixes tap event propagation on the widgets behind tab bars. Casenum 24126</li>
<li>Fixes TabBar errors when custom images not supplied. Casenum 23996</li>
<li>The scrollview gets the .isBounceEnabled property that allows the view to bounce back or not, like the native behaviour. Casenum: 21357</li>
<li>Fixes changing scroll direction when the swipe occurs near one of the view limits. Casenum 22607, 24316</li>
</ul>
<p>We have a few more fixes coming, but widgets are a lot more polished now!</p>
<p>Starting in tomorrow&#8217;s daily build (1150 or later), we&#8217;ll also be fixing a regression introduced late last week where certain plugins were not getting downloaded. This only affects plugins used in the Corona Simulator. Your device builds are unaffected.</p>
<p>On top of that, we have also finished a ton of other polish items such as removing auto-suggestion on Android password fields, improved handling of disposed/invalid audio streams, and ensuring multi-byte POSTs pass the correct content length.</p>
<p>There were also several pesky Windows-only bugs:</p>
<ul>
<li>Remember position of console window between restarts; reduce flashing of windows on startup &#8211; no casenum</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where you can&#8217;t zoom out after zooming all the way in.</li>
<li>Fixed bug where display.newText() would remove trailing spaces on Windows</li>
<li>Fix issue with two instances of Simulator starting when a lua file was specified on the command line &#8211; fixes casenum 23206</li>
</ul>
<p>If you are using 3rd party tools that integrate with the Corona Simulator, that last one is something you&#8217;re really going to like!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/06/24/corona-weekly-update-fixing-bugs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corona Weekly Update: iOS7 Beta, Text alignment, Facebook</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/06/17/corona-weekly-update-ios7-beta-text-alignment-facebook/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/06/17/corona-weekly-update-ios7-beta-text-alignment-facebook/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 04:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[walter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Build]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News & Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ios7]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.coronalabs.com/?p=36151</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Time for a quick update on your favorite <a href="/products/corona-sdk/">mobile app development</a> platform.

Last week, Apple announced iOS7 Beta at WWDC. A lot of cool stuff was shown. The interesting thing is that a lot of the "flat" UI that was demonstrated was exactly the kind of thing we saw some of you <em>already</em> creating using Corona's graphics system. ]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Time for a quick update on your favorite <a href=/products/corona-sdk/>mobile app development</a> platform.</p>
<p>Last week, Apple announced iOS7 Beta at WWDC. A lot of cool stuff was shown. The interesting thing is that a lot of the &#8220;flat&#8221; UI that was demonstrated was exactly the kind of thing we saw some of you <em><strong>already</strong></em> creating using Corona&#8217;s graphics system.</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-36154" alt="Corona iOS 7 Beta device build" src="http://www.coronalabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Screen-Shot-2013-06-17-at-9.04.16-PM-300x171.png" /></p>
<p>For example, <a href=http://foreseetheday.com/>this app</a> was in the works before iOS 7 was even announced!</p>
<p>Apple&#8217;s NDA prevents me from talking too much about iOS7, but what I can say is that we will fully support iOS7. In fact, last week, starting in <a href=http://developer.coronalabs.com/release/2013/1141/>daily build</a> 1141, you can try your app out on iOS 7 Beta. On the right, you just select &#8220;7.0 beta&#8221; from the iOS device build dialog in the Corona Simulator, and presto, you&#8217;ve got an app built against the iOS 7 Beta SDK that you can test on your own device.</p>
<p>I really recommend you do try out your apps on iOS 7. If the past is any indication, we expect iOS 7 to introduce regression bugs that affect all iOS developers, not just Corona developers. The sooner you know about them, the less you&#8217;ll be surprised when iOS 7 is finally released!</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-36163" alt="Corona SDK supports Facebook Connect" src="http://www.coronalabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Screen-Shot-2013-06-17-at-9.25.24-PM.png" /><br />
(Our lawyers will bug me about this, so let me just remind you that if you are using iOS 7 Beta, you must honor Apple&#8217;s developer membership rules.)</p>
<p>We also have upgraded <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/facebook/>Corona&#8217;s Facebook support</a> on Android, so it&#8217;s on par with iOS. Now, you can run Facebook&#8217;s Scrumptious sample on Android just like you can on iOS.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re also working on adding Facebook monetization features like <a href=https://developers.facebook.com/docs/tutorials/mobile-app-ads/>Mobile App Install Ads</a> that can help drive more installations of your app and increase discovery, all things that will help you make more money with your app! This should be coming in a daily build later this week.</p>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-36165 alignright" alt="Corona-text-alignment" src="http://www.coronalabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/Corona-text-alignment-300x45.png" width="300" height="45" /><br />
There were a bunch of other interesting checkins that you&#8217;ll notice in the <a href=http://developer.coronalabs.com/corona-daily-builds/summary>daily build notes</a> related to gaming, but the one I want to highlight is related to business apps or any app that&#8217;s dealing with lots of text.</p>
<p>In the next daily build, we are going to be giving more text alignment capabilities. You&#8217;ll be able to set left, center, right alignment on multiline text objects, the ones created by &#8216;display.newText()&#8217;. There will be more docs forthcoming on our <a href=http://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/>daily build API docs</a>. I&#8217;ll update here when they&#8217;re ready.</p>
<p><strong>UPDATE</strong>: The reference for the text alignment is <a href=http://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/api/library/display/newText.html>here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/06/17/corona-weekly-update-ios7-beta-text-alignment-facebook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wednesday FAQs: Java and Windows Simulators</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/05/15/wednesday-faqs-java-and-windows-simulator/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/05/15/wednesday-faqs-java-and-windows-simulator/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 17:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[tom]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[FAQ]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[java]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.coronalabs.com/?p=34017</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It's Wednesday and time for another frequently asked questions (FAQs) session. Here are some FAQs about Java and the Windows Simulator.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://blog.coronalabs.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/FAQ.png" alt="FAQ Icon" class="alignright size-full wp-image-28552" />It&#8217;s Wednesday and time for another frequently asked questions (FAQs) session. Here are some FAQs about Java and the Windows Simulator.</p>
<h2>1. Java 7 is the most recent version of Java, why does Corona SDK require Java 6?</h2>
<p>Developing for Android requires Java 6, not Java 7 (according to the <a href=http://developer.android.com/index.html>Android site</a>). Corona SDK uses the Java tools for signing the APK, so we have the same requirements as if you were doing native Android development.</p>
<p>When you run Corona SDK and try to do a build, it checks to see if Java 6 is installed. If it doesn&#8217;t find Java 6, you will be prompted to install Java 6.</p>
<p>Note: Starting with Build 1103, we found a way to make Corona SDK run with Java 7, so now both the Mac and Windows Simulators can run with either Java 6 or Java 7 installed.</p>
<h2>2. I keep getting a message on my Windows machine saying Java wants to update my Java (6) to Java 7. Should I upgrade?</h2>
<p>If you are running the public build (971 or 1076), we don&#8217;t recommend running the Java updater because it may remove the JRE 6 binary files, causing Corona SDK build errors.</p>
<h2>3. I can&#8217;t build for Android &#8212; the &#8220;Key Alias&#8221; field is empty</h2>
<p>This generally means the Java 6 install is damaged. You will also get <strong>&#8220;keystore password not valid&#8221;</strong> error if you browse and select the <strong>debug keystore</strong> shipped with Corona SDK.</p>
<p>This can happen if you try to install Java 7 over Java 6 and the Java updater removes the JRE 6 (Java Runtime) binary files. We have seen this happen when you run Java (7) Updater 45. See question 5 for how to restore JRE 6.</p>
<h2>4. I can&#8217;t build for Android &#8212; I get a &#8220;Could not load &#8230;/jvm.dll, error 126&#8221; message.</h2>
<p>We added support for Java 7 in Build 1093 but it only worked correctly if you installed Java JDK7 from Oracle&#8217;s website. We found if you installed Java 7 using the Updater 45, it would remove a key DLL file, causing the above error message when trying to do a build in the Windows simulator. The solution is to use Build 1103, which now properly locates the DLL file. (This turned out to be a known Java Updater bug.)</p>
<h2>5. I&#8217;ve installed Java 7 so how do I get Corona SDK Build 1076 working again?</h2>
<p>Installing the Java 7 Updater removes the JRE 6 binary files but leaves the JRE 6 key in the Windows Registry making Corona SDK think Java 6 is installed. The solution is to re-install Java 6 JRE files. You can download JRE 6 <a href=http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/jre6downloads-1902815.html>here</a>. Make sure you pick the 32-bit version for Windows (Windows X86).</p>
<p>Once you&#8217;ve run the Java 7 Updater and re-installed the JRE 6 files, you can build with both the public releases and the latest Corona SDK Daily Builds (starting with Build 1103).</p>
<p>That&#8217;s it for today&#8217;s questions. I hope you enjoyed them and even learned a few things!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/05/15/wednesday-faqs-java-and-windows-simulator/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
