<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>partners &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/partners-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>partners &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Guest Piece: Announcing Corona Professional Services for Businesses</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/11/19/guest-piece-announcing-corona-professional-services-cps-for-businesses/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/11/19/guest-piece-announcing-corona-professional-services-cps-for-businesses/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 17:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona Professional Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CPS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=51888</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dev Gandhi is the CEO of <a href="http://www.reliablecoders.com/">ReliableCoders</a>. Prior to starting ReliableCoders, Dev was a founding member of <a href="http://www.nexage.com/">Nexage</a>, one of the world’s leading mobile ad networks. Moving on to create something new, Dev aimed to change the way development was executed during the technology boom of this decade.

Today, Dev writes on the launch of <a href="http://services.coronalabs.com/">Corona Professional Services (CPS)</a>, a new partnership between Corona Labs and ReliableCoders. Through this partnership, <a href="http://www.coronalabs.com/i-want-to-build/business-apps/" target="_blank">businesses</a> can take advantage of our mobile development expertise via consulting services, premium support, and customized training.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Dev Gandhi is the CEO of <a href=http://www.reliablecoders.com/>ReliableCoders</a>. Prior to starting ReliableCoders, Dev was a founding member of <a href=http://www.nexage.com/>Nexage</a>, one of the world’s leading mobile ad networks. Moving on to create something new, Dev aimed to change the way development was executed during the technology boom of this decade.</p>
<p>Today, Dev writes on the launch of <a href=http://services.coronalabs.com>Corona/ Professional Services (CPS)</a>, a new partnership between Corona Labs and ReliableCoders. Through this partnership, <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/i-want-to-build/business-apps/ target="_blank">businesses</a> can take advantage of our mobile development expertise via consulting services, premium support, and customized training.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Reliablecoders_2.0_logo_dklt.png" alt="ReliableCoders" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-52000" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Reliablecoders_2.0_logo_dklt.png 337w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Reliablecoders_2.0_logo_dklt-300x58.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 337px) 100vw, 337px" />As human beings, it’s natural for us to want to continually improve ourselves. We want to evolve to become stronger and more effective in what we do every day. As business owners, service providers, and app developers, this especially rings true during this era of fast technological advances.<br />
Here at <a href=http://www.reliablecoders.com/>ReliableCoders</a>, we specialize in helping people become more effective, whether we are showing someone how to build better solutions or doing the development for them. </p>
<p>Our evolution has brought us here to partner with Corona Labs to bring you <a href=http://services.coronalabs.com>Corona/ Professional Services</a> (CPS). Through our partnership, we aim to assist companies and create the best possible mobile content to solve business challenges. With the launch of CPS, we’re offering a free App Benchmark Study for clients who already have a live mobile app, or a Project Analysis Consultation for those with an app in development. <a href=http://services.coronalabs.com>Click/ here</a> for more details.</p>
<p>ReliableCoders is a premium mobile design and development studio based in Silicon Valley, just a stone’s throw from our friends at Corona Labs. We deliver a seamless and compelling user experience for all client projects. We understand that for businesses, the fine details lie in the backend architecture, while for end-users, it’s all about experience. </p>
<p>CPS offers consulting in the following areas:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Competitive Market Landscape Study</strong>: Conduct an analysis of your app within its competitive environment before you start development.</li>
<li><strong>Feasibility Study</strong>: Evaluate the potential success of your app, website, or business venture before you begin working on execution.</li>
<li><strong>Security Audit</strong>: Evaluate your software’s information system, measuring how well it conforms to modern security standards.</li>
<li><strong>Compliance Study</strong>: Analyze your app’s adherence to industry standards by checking its compliance in key areas.</li>
<li><strong>Usability Study</strong>: Ensure that the final details are just right with a user experience analysis.</li>
<li><strong>Social Media Integration</strong>: Identify and execute social network integrations within an app, whether for internal or consumer-facing interactions.</li>
<li><strong>Cross-Platform Application Development</strong>: Analyze workflow processes and requirements for cross-platform app development for a specific project.</li>
<li><strong>Enterprise Data Integration</strong>: Identify of how to best integrate rich data from platforms such as Salesforce, SAP, and Oracle.</li>
</ul>
<p>Merging our development experience with the rich software capabilities of Corona SDK and Corona Enterprise, we’re proud to present the best and brightest consultants and developers at your disposal. Our team has worked with brands including Verizon, Microsoft, Korn/Ferry and VMware and have developed apps for clients in verticals including, but not limited to health, education, human resources, finance, hardware integrations, and mobile gaming.</p>
<p>For more information, please head to the <a href=www.coronalabs.com/services>Corona Professional Services</a> page. We look forward to working with you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/11/19/guest-piece-announcing-corona-professional-services-cps-for-businesses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest Piece: eCPMs to Ad Placement &#8211; Monetization Tips from the Pros</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/10/23/guest-piece-ecpms-to-ad-placement-monetization-tips-from-the-pros/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 20:38:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monetization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=50267</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last Wednesday, a group of San Francisco techies gathered in SOMA to talk eCPMs, ad placement, fill and mediation – in other words, mobile monetization - at Corona Labs’ Monetizing Cross-Platform Apps panel.

Learn more about the panel from SponsorPay's communication manager, Jessa Moon.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Jessa Moon is the communications manager at <a href=http://sponsorpay.com/>SponsorPay</a>, which fuels the app economy through smarter ad monetization solutions. SponsorPay&#8217;s comprehensive ad monetization platform includes mediation, an ad marketplace and ad serving capabilities to empower app developers to integrate, manage and optimize all sources of ad revenues.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/SP_Logo_cmyk_use-this-300x50.jpg" alt="SponsorPay logo" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-50296" />Last Wednesday, a group of San Francisco techies gathered in SOMA to talk eCPMs, ad placement, fill and mediation – in other words, <a href=/resources/plugins/>mobile monetization</a> &#8211; at Corona Labs’ Monetizing Cross-Platform Apps panel.</p>
<p>SponsorPay’s very own David Diaz, senior director of developer relations, joined moderator David Rangel, COO at Corona Labs, and panelists Ben Bear, VP of sales and business development at <a href=http://vungle.com/>Vungle</a>, Maggie Mesa, director of publishing at <a href=http://www.inner-active.com/>Inneractive</a>, and Tim Doyle, publisher development manager at <a href=http://www.playhaven.com/>PlayHaven</a>, for a lively discussion on how to navigate the complex landscape of app monetization.</p>
<p>Check out the video below for the full dialogue or take a quick look at the following outline of key takeaways.</p>
<p class="ac"><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/77620702" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<h3>Monetization Terms 101</h3>
<p>Three-letter acronyms abound in the world of advertising. CPM and eCPMs are commonly used to describe the cost and effectiveness of advertising. Unfamiliar with these terms? Not to worry, our panel provided a summary:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>CPM</strong> – Cost Per Mille is a measurement of the cost for every thousand ads shown and is used in speaking to advertisers. In case you’re confused with the inclusion of “m” in the acronym, mille means thousand in French.</li>
<li><strong>eCPM</strong> – developers use “effective Cost Per Mille” to represent the actual amount of revenue per thousand impressions. This measurement is directly impacted by inventory in that if a developer has 1000 opportunities to show an ad, but only fills 500, then the revenue made by the developer (eCPM) would decrease by 50 percent.</li>
<li><strong>LTV</strong> – Lifetime Value refers to users and generally relates to retention and their inclination to complete IAP (see below).</li>
<li><strong>IAP</strong> – In-App Purchases.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Android vs. iOS</h3>
<p>The difference in monetizing for Android and iOS was a hot topic. Several of the insights included:</p>
<ul>
<li>Incentivized installs are banned on Apple, which affects how developers monetize on the platform. iOS is generally viewed as reaching a more premium audience.</li>
<li>Because LTV (lifetime value) and IAP (in-app-purchases) tend to be lower on Android, advertising is commonly more aggressive.</li>
<li>Apple is a closed environment, so processing payments are uniform across the globe. This isn’t the case for Android, and as a result, this process is more difficult country to country.</li>
</ul>
<h3>Tips from the Pros</h3>
<p>One theme came through loud and clear – everyone is a newbie when it comes to mobile monetization. Read up – developer forums and networks can help. And of course, the pros did a little educating of their own:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Place ads thoughtfully</strong> – Ads that are distracting or interrupt the app experience drive users away, lowering eCPM. Alternately, users do appreciate well-placed advertising. For instance, ads placed in gaming apps when a player dies can reward users with life for watching a video unit.</li>
<li><strong>Establish analytics</strong> – Advertisers are interested in audience segments, so the more information gained on user gender, age, location, etc., the better.</li>
<li><strong>Mediate</strong> – Mediation solutions available in the industry integrate and draw advertising from multiple networks, increasing ad fill and optimizing eCPM.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
