<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>desktop &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/desktop/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>desktop &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Announcing Steamworks, a plugin for Steam apps</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/08/10/announcing-steamworks-a-plugin-for-steam-apps/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2016/08/10/announcing-steamworks-a-plugin-for-steam-apps/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 14:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[achievements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desktop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leaderboards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plugin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[valve]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=67650</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Corona Labs is pleased to announce our plugin for Steamworks. Learn how you can take advantage of this plugin to publish desktop games to Steam!]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-67654" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/share_steam_logo-150x150.png" alt="share_steam_logo" width="150" height="150" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/share_steam_logo-150x150.png 150w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/share_steam_logo-300x300.png 300w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/share_steam_logo-500x500.png 500w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/share_steam_logo.png 512w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />When it comes to PC desktop games, the premier place to publish is <a href=http://store.steampowered.com/ target="_blank">Steam</a>.</p>
<p>Now, Corona developers can build apps for Windows (<code>win32.exe</code>) or macOS and submit them to Steam to be &#8220;greenlit.&#8221; During the greenlight process, the Steam community reviews apps and decides if they want them to be published.</p>
<p>To ensure that your games can compete in the Steam store, Corona Labs has been diligently working to create a <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/steamworks/index.html target="_blank">plugin for Steam</a>. This plugin supports core features requested by developers who have already had their apps successfully published to Steam.</p>
<p>Using the new <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/steamworks/index.html target="_blank">Steamworks plugin</a>, your app can now take advantage of leaderboards, achievements, user stats, player information, and various Steam overlays in your game. These features aren&#8217;t required, but their presence in your game could encourage more people to vote &#8220;yes!&#8221;.</p>
<h3>About the plugin</h3>
<p>This plugin is a bit different than our other game networking plugins. For example, there is no login API. Instead, you must be logged into the Steam client on your computer. The plugin then talks to the Steam client to exchange information with the Steam servers. On macOS, it&#8217;s best to set up the Corona Simulator as a Steam app and launch Corona SDK from Steam for maximum support.</p>
<p>Many of the API calls return data immediately, if the data has been cached or is readily available. For instance, if you are getting information about a user and the plugin previously retrieved the data, it is returned to you immediately. However, if the data is not immediately available, and you have set up an event listener for that type of data, an event will trigger the listener and then you can update your local data with the new information.</p>
<h3>In summary</h3>
<p>Learn more about implementing Steamworks in your game by reading our Steamworks plugin <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/steamworks/index.html target="_blank">documentation</a> and by examining our Steamworks <a href=https://github.com/coronalabs/steamworks-sample target="_blank">sample app</a>. And, join us in the Corona <a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/ target="_blank">forums</a> to discuss this wonderful addition to our plugin library.</p>
<hr />
<div style="font-size: 80%; font-color: #999;">Steam and the Steam logo are trademarks and/or registered trademarks of Valve Corporation in the U.S. and/or other countries.</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2016/08/10/announcing-steamworks-a-plugin-for-steam-apps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>From the Forum — Issue #124</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/05/20/from-the-forum-issue-124/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 14:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[From the Forum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[config.lua]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coronimum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desktop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MySQL]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=66877</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Welcome to the latest installment of From the Forum. In this series, guest blogger Alex Jackson highlights outstanding threads from the Corona Forum. The goal is to bring attention to the most captivating, interesting, and thought-provoking discussions taking place in our very own backyard.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-54943" style="margin: 0px 0px 10px 10px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Icon_Resources_Forum.png" alt="From the Forum" /><em>Welcome to the latest installment of <strong>From the Forum</strong>. In <em>this series</em>, guest blogger Alex Jackson highlights outstanding threads from the <a href=http://forum.coronalabs.com/ target="_blank">Corona Forum</a>. The goal is to bring attention to the most captivating, interesting, and thought-provoking discussions taking place in our very own backyard.</em></p>
<p><em>Please <a href=http://forum.coronalabs.com/ target="_blank">visit the forum</a> to join these conversations or start your own!</em></p>
<hr />
<h3>A little bit more from Google Maps</h3>
<p>This first tip is short and sweet and it revolves around one of the great “gotchas” that is the basis of Corona SDK: the OpenGL layer. As we all know, because of the architecture which underlies Corona SDK, any <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/daily/api/library/native/index.html>native.*</a> API call that creates a native object places that element above graphical objects created within your Corona app.</p>
<p>If you have your sights set on a super-engaging geo-tagging game, this creates quite the boondoggle. You can’t capture maps with <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/library/display/save.html target="_blank">display.save()</a> et. al, nor can you mark up the maps that you create. However, standout Corona developer <strong>AidenWolf</strong> reminds us that we can still leverage the Google Static Maps API. Check out the original thread below and get clued in on how you can modify your map images with very little hassle!</p>
<p><a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/62580-how-to-save-photo-from-nativenewmapview/ target="_blank">https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/62580-how-to-save-photo-from-nativenewmapview/</a></p>
<h3>Remote server querying workflows</h3>
<p>If you aren’t coming from a system administrator background, configuring your Corona project to interface nicely with your remote server can be a bit of a struggle. Wrapping your head around all the moving parts isn’t the most exciting process.</p>
<p>Fortunately, exemplary Corona support engineer Rob Miracle responded to a forum thread with some questions about this topic, and helped out everyone by giving a quick-and-dirty dissertation on the finer aspects of SQL integration. Click through to the original thread to grab a bit more info on this very necessary skill.</p>
<p><a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/63163-its-possible-accessing-remote-sql-server-database/ target="_blank">https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/63163-its-possible-accessing-remote-sql-server-database/</a></p>
<h3>Some tips for desktop window sizes</h3>
<p>The nuts and bolts of Windows and OS X desktop deployment are still being felt out by the Corona community at large. While we do have access to the vast majority of APIs that are standard for mobile development at this point, there are still a few here and there that don’t readily apply.</p>
<p>One of the missing pieces is the read order of our projects. Does the <code>config.lua</code> file get read first, or does the desktop environment get queued in order to identify the various values for the <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/library/display/index.html target="_blank">display.*</a> APIs? As Corona engineer <strong>Joshua Quick</strong> states:</p>
<p>“It&#8217;s a chicken &amp; egg issue. We need to read your &#8216;<code>config.lua'</code> file to determine what the pixel width and height of the window should be, which of course means the <code>display.*</code> Lua APIs can&#8217;t be ready for you to use since the pixel width and height you want to read haven&#8217;t been determined yet.”</p>
<p>I’ve included two different forum threads that tackle this topic in depth, so that you can be well-armed when you run up against this desktop idiosyncrasy. Truck through to the links below to get inundated with desktop display value discussions!</p>
<p><a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/63123-display-in-configlua target="_blank">https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/63123-display-in-configlua</a><br />
<a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/63200-how-to-get-current-screen-resolution/ target="_blank">https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/63200-how-to-get-current-screen-resolution/</a></p>
<h4>About Alex</h4>
<p>Alex Jackson is an indie developer and the founder of <a href=http://www.panc.co/ target="_blank">Panc Interactive</a>, specializing in retro-style gaming. He has created several mobile applications, enjoys long walks on the beach, pixel art, and reading the Corona forums. Contact him by <a href=mailto:alex@panc.co>email</a> or follow him on Twitter: <a href=http://twitter.com/pancinteractive>@pancinteractive</a>. Check out his new game <a href=http://www.panc.co/segreta-download-page.html target="_blank">Segreta</a> on iOS, Android, Windows Phone and Amazon devices.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>From the Forum — Issue #115</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/03/18/from-the-forum-issue-115/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 23:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[From the Forum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desktop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[icon generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Icons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[keyboards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oAuth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[win32]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=66172</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Welcome to the latest installment of From the Forum. In this series, guest blogger Alex Jackson highlights outstanding threads from the Corona Forum. The goal is to bring attention to the most captivating, interesting, and thought-provoking discussions taking place in our very own backyard.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-54943" style="margin: 0px 0px 10px 10px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Icon_Resources_Forum.png" alt="From the Forum" /><em>Welcome to the latest installment of <strong>From the Forum</strong>. In <em>this series</em>, guest blogger Alex Jackson highlights outstanding threads from the <a href=http://forum.coronalabs.com>Corona/ Forum</a>. The goal is to bring attention to the most captivating, interesting, and thought-provoking discussions taking place in our very own backyard.</em></p>
<p><em>Please <a href=http://forum.coronalabs.com>visit/ the forum</a> to join these conversations or start your own!</em></p>
<hr />
<h3>Google oAuth 2.0 and the triumph of success</h3>
<p>And lo, the clouds parted and Google oAuth sign-in has been achieved! It’s always a fantastic revelation to see community members provide code snippets for us to use in our own projects, and I always make a point to applaud these achievements.</p>
<p>Such is the case with the below forum thread. Corona dev <strong>thomas6</strong> exclaims in the discovery and confirmation of getting oAuth to work with Google credentials. Everything necessary to get it to work is in the below forum thread, so what are you waiting for? Click through right now!</p>
<p><a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/62087-succes-google-oauth2-for-corona-and-lua/ target="_blank">https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/62087-succes-google-oauth2-for-corona-and-lua/</a></p>
<h3>Win32 apps and the keyboards that love them</h3>
<p>For Corona developers, Windows desktop is a brave new world that has been sought after for years. Even though it’s been a dominant environment for quite some time, we have been hacking away at the learning curve when releasing our apps and games to a desktop OS. This has run the gamut from “<em>dead-simple</em>” to “<em>hair-pullingly infuriating</em>”, which a large spectrum in between.</p>
<p>One of the more difficult facets of the new Windows OSes (8 and 10, for example) is the relationship between Win32 apps, and virtual and physical keyboards. This is really all the pre-amble you need to before tuning into the below forum thread. It’s really a great read, and has a lot of useful hints for folks that are are in the process of creating or porting apps to the platform, or anyone that has aspirations of their killer app on Windows 10 tablets. Head on over for an insightful discussion!</p>
<p><a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/62083-nativesetkeyboardfocus-doesnt-work-properly-for-win32-apps/ target="_blank">https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/62083-nativesetkeyboardfocus-doesnt-work-properly-for-win32-apps/</a></p>
<h3>More icon generating resources</h3>
<p>As sure as the sun sets in the West, we Corona developers need to puzzle out the arcane sets of icons necessary to release their apps and games to the masses. Plus, with the addition of desktop builds, you’re looking at far more icons and naming conventions than you can shake a stick at.</p>
<p>The best way to create all of these, is to not create them at all. I’ve covered generators and templates before, so think of this as more of a PSA: <strong>Rene</strong> from <strong>Devilsquid</strong> has updated their Photoshop template to include all necessary icons and launch images needed for our apps. There are some other very use links in the thread below, so click through and check’em out!</p>
<p><a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/62150-icon-naming/ target="_blank">https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/62150-icon-naming/</a></p>
<h4>About Alex</h4>
<p>Alex Jackson is an indie developer and the founder of <a href=http://www.panc.co/ target="_blank">Panc Interactive</a>, specializing in retro-style gaming. He has created several mobile applications, enjoys long walks on the beach, pixel art, and reading the Corona forums. Contact him by <a href=mailto:alex@panc.co>email</a> or follow him on Twitter: <a href=http://twitter.com/pancinteractive>@pancinteractive</a>. Check out his new game <a href=http://www.panc.co/segreta-download-page.html target="_blank">Segreta</a> on iOS, Android, Windows Phone and Amazon devices.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
