<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ebook &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/ebook/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>ebook &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>App of the Week: Millie&#8217;s Crazy Dinosaur Adventure &#8211; Millie Was Here, Book 3</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/09/16/app-of-the-week-millies-crazy-dinosaur-adventure-millie-was-here-book-3/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/09/16/app-of-the-week-millies-crazy-dinosaur-adventure-millie-was-here-book-3/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2013 20:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebook]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=45014</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Millie’s Crazy Dinosaur Adventure</a> tells the tale of one adorable dog’s journey back in time to the land of dinosaurs. When Millie attends Kitty’s birthday party, she’s embarrassed to realize that she’s forgotten her gift at home. Millie decides to build a simple time machine to go back in time and retrieve the gift, but to her surprise, she travels a little <em>too</em> far back.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-45016" alt="Screen Shot 2013-09-15 at 8.01.58 PM" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Screen-Shot-2013-09-15-at-8.01.58-PM.png" /><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/au/app/millies-crazy-dinosaur-adventure/id695161183?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D2&lt;br /&gt;
">Millie’s Crazy Dinosaur Adventure</a> tells the tale of one adorable dog’s journey back in time to the land of dinosaurs. When Millie attends Kitty’s birthday party, she’s embarrassed to realize that she’s forgotten her gift at home. Millie decides to build a simple time machine to go back in time and retrieve the gift, but to her surprise, she travels a little <em>too</em> far back.</p>
<p>This tale of adventure and friendship engages children with rich activities that include interacting with the story, exploring elements of the tale, solving puzzles, and practicing/enhancing vocabulary. The read-along feature highlights each word as the narrator reads, and interactivity clues appear as paw prints to help kids along the way. A particularly clever “bedroom mode” offers a calming pre-sleep reading experience with a dimmed screen, soothing music, and lower volume.</p>
<p class="ac"><img class="wp-image-45015" alt="Millie's adventure screenshot" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Millies-adventure.jpeg" /></p>
<p>Developed by the children&#8217;s app studio <a href=http://www.megapops.com/>Megapops</a>, this is the first “in-house” app from founders Randy Lowenstein and Jennifer Taylor. In 2011, the duo hired a professional developer to create their first two apps, <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/millie-was-here-book-1-meet/id452174851?mt=8>Meet Millie</a> and <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/millie-lost-key-millie-was/id452175094?mt=8>Millie and The Lost Key</a>. For their third book, they decided to develop on their own with <a href=www.coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk>Corona SDK</a>, finding the platform incredibly easy to use.</p>
<p>Randy tells us, “The amazing thing is that it took us about 8 months of development to create our first app, coding natively for iOS with a small team of experienced iOS developers. It took me the same amount of time to learn how to program from scratch, with absolutely zero programming experience, and then to do all of the programming for Millie&#8217;s Crazy Dinosaur Adventure, entirely by myself. It took about 4 months of learning, and then 4 months of programming.”</p>
<p>The hard work paid off, as Millie’s Crazy Dinosaur Adventure soared to #1 in Books and #2 in Education on the App Store. To top it off, the book app was graced with a large promotional banner by Apple, as seen below. To read this charming story with your child, head to iTunes and download <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/au/app/millies-crazy-dinosaur-adventure/id695161183?mt=8&amp;ign-mpt=uo%3D2&lt;br /&gt;
">Millie’s Crazy Dinosaur Adventure</a> for $1.99.</p>
<p class="ac"><img class="wp-image-45072" alt="Millie's Adventure" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Millies-Adventure.png" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/09/16/app-of-the-week-millies-crazy-dinosaur-adventure-millie-was-here-book-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>App of the Week: Zala and the Treasure Cave</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/08/26/app-of-the-week-zala-and-the-treasure-cave/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/08/26/app-of-the-week-zala-and-the-treasure-cave/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 22:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kwik]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=42485</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<div>When a group of friends discover a secret treasure map, they need your help to decipher the map and embark on an adventure through the African savanna.</div>
 
<div style="margin-top:10px;">Created for children ages 4-6, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/zala-and-the-treasure-cave/id682584983?mt=8&#38;ign-mpt=uo%3D4">Zala and the Treasure Cave</a> captivates children’s senses — from touch to sound to sight — through vibrant illustrations and engaging elements to pull kids into the story.</div>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-42486" alt="Zala icon" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Screen-Shot-2013-08-23-at-4.39.54-PM.png" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Screen-Shot-2013-08-23-at-4.39.54-PM.png 183w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Screen-Shot-2013-08-23-at-4.39.54-PM-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 183px) 100vw, 183px" /></p>
<p>When a group of friends discover a secret treasure map, they need your help to decipher the map and embark on an adventure through the African savanna. Created for children ages 4-6, <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/zala-and-the-treasure-cave/id682584983?mt=8&ign-mpt=uo%3D4>Zala and the Treasure Cave</a> captivates children’s senses — from touch to sound to sight — through vibrant illustrations, engaging elements to pull kids into the story, and an excellent mix of sounds and narration.</p>
<p>Zala and the Treasure Cave adds a new dimension to the idea of storytelling, combining an animated film with interactive games and puzzles that are woven into the story. The story-driven app uses the tools of film dramaturgy to transport emotions while integrating puzzles into the plot, while the games and a diverse cast of characters allow children to explore and discover app elements in a playful way.</p>
<p>The app&#8217;s creators are a talented husband and wife duo who wanted to develop an educational eBook based on their own experiences growing up in Turkey and Germany. Their goal was to create a memorable story of friendship using characters of different colors, religions, and genders.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="wp-image-42487" alt="Zala screenshot" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Zala-screenshot.jpeg" /></p>
<p>While the creators had a solid background in filmmaking and 3D animation, they were new to the world of mobile development. They evaluated several tools and found that the majority were either too complicated to work with or too simple in their capabilities, especially when it came to straightforward integration of an interactive environment.</p>
<p>Within a few days of discovering Corona SDK, they learned the Lua programming language, analyzed Corona’s sample projects, and read <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/resources/tutorials/getting-started-with-corona/ target="_blank">Corona</a> and <a href=http://www.kwiksher.com/ target="_blank">Kwik</a> tutorials to get up to speed. In less than two weeks, they had a working prototype for testing on all devices, featuring audio integration, fade-in and fade-out between scenes, and much more.</p>
<p>To experience the striking graphics and high quality narration of <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/zala-and-the-treasure-cave/id682584983?mt=8&ign-mpt=uo%3D4>Zala and the Treasure Cave</a>, head to iTunes and download the app for $2.99.</p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/seQpUt3yv5c" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/08/26/app-of-the-week-zala-and-the-treasure-cave/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>App of the Week: Prancing, Dancing Lily</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/03/11/app-of-the-week-prancing-dancing-lily/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/03/11/app-of-the-week-prancing-dancing-lily/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 22:12:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross-platform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle Fire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[storybook]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=29866</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Based on the award-winning book by Marsha Diane Arnold, Prancing, Dancing Lily tells the story of a festive young milking cow that doesn’t quite fit the herd.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-08-at-4.54.06-PM.png" alt="Lily icon" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-29867" />Based on the award-winning book by Marsha Diane Arnold, <a href=http://developer.coronalabs.com/showcase/prancing-dancing-lily>Prancing, Dancing Lily</a> tells the story of a festive young milking cow that doesn’t quite fit the herd. Brought to the digital world by <a href=http://fatredcouch.com/index.php>Fat Red Couch</a>, this heartwarming tale features whimsical illustrations, expressive characters and unique narration that readers of all ages will appreciate.</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Prancing-Dancing-Lily-screenshot.jpg" alt="Prancing, Dancing Lily screenshot" class="alignright size-full wp-image-29868" />Lily, the leading lady, comes from a long line of responsible cow-bellers; yet she herself is clumsy, inattentive and always dancing around the field at the wrong times. Once she realizes she&#8217;s different from her peers, Lily embarks on an adventure, traveling the world in search of the perfect dance. Thanks to her spunky nature, she has the opportunity to grace Radio City Music Hall as a Rockette, learns to tap dance on a cruise ship, and pirouettes on stage as a ballerina in Russia. Through her adventures, Lily learns an important lesson on self acceptance, and returns home to share her exciting new dances with the friends on the farm.</p>
<p>Can Lily sway her herd and become an accepted member? Download Prancing, Dancing Lily for $1.99 from <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/prancing-dancing-lily/id586489276?mt=8>App Store</a>, <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.fatredcouch.pdlilyandroid>Google Play</a>, or the <a href=http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00BDBAVFY/ref=mas_pm_Fat-Red-Couch-Inc-Prancing>Amazon Appstore</a> and find out!</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/BrmH60mYDSc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<div class="clearfix spacerDiv"></div>
<h3>Honorable Mention</h3>
<div class="clearfix  spacerDiv">
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/Screen-Shot-2013-03-11-at-1.33.14-PM.png" alt="Brickout Zero Gravity" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-29881" /></a></p>
<h4 style="margin-bottom: 10px;">Brickout Zero Gravity</h4>
<p>Brickout Zero Gravity removes the shackles of Breakout and turns you loose in a challenging arcade game where physics are king. Keep a ricocheting ball in play by moving a paddle on one side of the screen while targeting and smashing bricks on the other. Clear the board to progress to the next level and earn power-ups to give you an edge. Check out Brickout Zero Gravity for $1.99 from the <a href= http://appstore.com/brickoutzerogravity>App Store</a>.</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/qMXIe5Pn-gs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/03/11/app-of-the-week-prancing-dancing-lily/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
