<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>Comments on: Staff Conversation: Corona SDK Starter and Price Changes</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/coronageek/staff-conversation-corona-sdk-starter-and-price-changes/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/coronageek/staff-conversation-corona-sdk-starter-and-price-changes/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 09:27:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>
	<item>
		<title>By: David Rangel</title>
		<link>/blog/coronageek/staff-conversation-corona-sdk-starter-and-price-changes/#comment-5574</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Rangel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 03:51:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.coronalabs.com/?post_type=coronageek&#038;p=31539#comment-5574</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[David, thanks for the comment. We are definitely in this for the long haul as well, which is why we want to open mobile development to as many developers as possible. While I agree that the unlimited trial was good, free is great. But we are balancing that out by strong Pro and Enterprise versions that developers are happy to pay for as well.

All our builds - daily and public have been increasing in stability and that will continue.]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>David, thanks for the comment. We are definitely in this for the long haul as well, which is why we want to open mobile development to as many developers as possible. While I agree that the unlimited trial was good, free is great. But we are balancing that out by strong Pro and Enterprise versions that developers are happy to pay for as well.</p>
<p>All our builds &#8211; daily and public have been increasing in stability and that will continue.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>By: David</title>
		<link>/blog/coronageek/staff-conversation-corona-sdk-starter-and-price-changes/#comment-5573</link>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 19:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.coronalabs.com/?post_type=coronageek&#038;p=31539#comment-5573</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This announcement makes it sound like CoronaLabs is looking to be purchased. While I am uninformed and pretty ignorant to the business workings of CoronaLabs, I cannot see a good reason to give away a the SDK for free. The free trial is already great for people who want to evaluate the product. In a competitive arena such as mobile development I view technology as a sprint and business practices as a marathon. I am hoping that CoronaLabs is in it for the long haul. 

While my needs do not require the Pro version, I am concerned that as I downgrade from my Indie &quot;paid&quot; subscription to the &quot;free&quot; Starter version, that I will not receive the support or attention from CoronaLabs that I had in the past. I am hoping that the Stable Builds made available to me will actually be stable and bug-free unlike the current versions that require me to use the &quot;beta&quot; Daily Builds.

These are just my concerns and I love the Corona SDK. Keep up the good work and great product!

David]]></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This announcement makes it sound like CoronaLabs is looking to be purchased. While I am uninformed and pretty ignorant to the business workings of CoronaLabs, I cannot see a good reason to give away a the SDK for free. The free trial is already great for people who want to evaluate the product. In a competitive arena such as mobile development I view technology as a sprint and business practices as a marathon. I am hoping that CoronaLabs is in it for the long haul. </p>
<p>While my needs do not require the Pro version, I am concerned that as I downgrade from my Indie &#8220;paid&#8221; subscription to the &#8220;free&#8221; Starter version, that I will not receive the support or attention from CoronaLabs that I had in the past. I am hoping that the Stable Builds made available to me will actually be stable and bug-free unlike the current versions that require me to use the &#8220;beta&#8221; Daily Builds.</p>
<p>These are just my concerns and I love the Corona SDK. Keep up the good work and great product!</p>
<p>David</p>
]]></content:encoded>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
