<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Case Study &#8211; Game Studios &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/topics/case-study-game-studios/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Case Study &#8211; Game Studios &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Case Study: Yogome &#8211; educational games with a passion</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/08/30/case-study-yogome-educational-games-with-a-passion/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2016/08/30/case-study-yogome-educational-games-with-a-passion/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 21:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Case Study - Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Case Study - Game Studios]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=67742</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this case study, read about how Yogome is using Corona to create fun, polished, educational games for children of all ages.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright wp-image-67744" style="margin: 4px 0px 20px 20px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/yogomelogo.png" alt="yogomelogo" width="200" height="60" />It&#8217;s well known that learning can be fun when a game is involved. <a href=http://www.yogome.com/ target="_blank">Yogome</a>, a studio in Mexico City with an office in San Francisco, has jumped into this genre and is creating some fantastic learning adventures for kids of all ages. Their games are targeted towards elementary and middle-school students, but kids under 5 and over 12 can also find value playing their apps.</p>
<p>Yogome currently has <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/developer/yogome-inc/id536072105 target="_blank">30 titles in The App Store</a> and <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/developer?id=Yogome%2C+Inc. target="_blank">11 in Google Play</a>. Founded in 2010, Yogome was the brainchild of Manolo Díaz and Alberto Colin. They have since grown the studio to employ a staff of 40, including on-site language specialists for multiple language support and education experts to make sure the &#8220;education&#8221; goes with the fun.</p>
<p><iframe width="640" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ai59_f5lrFY?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Díaz heard about <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/ target="_blank">Corona</a> in 2011 and, with its ease of use and ability to deploy to multiple platforms, it became their core technology for developing their content and powering their apps and games. Leveraging their staff and their own library of core code, Yogome can produce a game in around three months, even for a larger scope project.</p>
<p>Their latest title, <em>Epic Heroes of Knowledge</em>, challenges students with a mix of over 100 educational mini-games featuring unique characters and a fun, rewarding game mechanic. Players gain &#8220;PowerCubes&#8221; through play to strengthen their <em>Yogotar</em> and defeat the villains of Queen Ignorantia.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-67746" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/yogomess1-1024x767.jpg" alt="yogomess1" width="960" height="719" /></p>
<p>The game has eight &#8220;worlds&#8221; covering eight key subjects like math, science, and programming. These worlds can be explored and students can capture characters like the <em>WiFi Warrior</em>, the <em>Continental Divider</em>, and more. In addition, parents can join in and use the Yogome <em>Parent Dashboard</em> where they can keep track of the child&#8217;s progress and even send them challenges. <em>Epic Heroes</em> includes content developed with the help of the <a href=http://www.play2prevent.org/ target="_blank">play2PREVENT</a> lab at Yale University, including the math content.</p>
<p>The game is very deep in content &#8212; as you progress, you can pick up treasure, capture enemies, get new allies, and feed and care for them. It has its own economic system which teaches kids how to allocate resources. The game even supports multiplayer mode.</p>
<p>Yogome games are generally free with in-app purchases to unlock content. <em>Epic Heroes</em> is subscription-based in that you get more content each month for a monthly or annual fee. Check it out in the <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/epic-heroes-of-knowledge/id904827467?mt=8 target="_blank">App Store</a> and on <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yogome.EpicKnowledge target="_blank">Google Play</a>!</p>
<p><a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/epic-heroes-of-knowledge/id904827467?mt=8 target="_blank"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-64556" style="margin-right: 10px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/app-store-badge.png" alt="app-store-badge" width="50" height="50" /></a> <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yogome.EpicKnowledge target="_blank"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-64594" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/google-play-badge.png" alt="google-play-badge" width="50" height="50" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2016/08/30/case-study-yogome-educational-games-with-a-passion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Case Study: Lonely Woof&#8217;s &#8220;Egz&#8221;</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/06/09/case-study-lonely-woofs-egz/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2016/06/09/case-study-lonely-woofs-egz/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 21:38:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Case Study - Game Studios]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game Development]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=67096</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<em>Egz</em> is an incredibly well designed and easy-to-play game. Learn more about how it came to be.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you haven&#8217;t played <em><a href=http://www.egz-game.com/homepage-en/ target="_blank">Egz</a></em>, you&#8217;re in for a treat. This colorful game, built with Corona SDK, has a unique story, great art, and challenging gameplay.</p>
<p>In <em>Egz</em>, you play a primordial egg: the first life form in a chaotic new world. Your goal is to not &#8220;break&#8221; while exploring a wide, complex, forming world.</p>
<p><iframe width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/R9MjafBlyI4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><em>Egz</em> was created by Lonely Woof&#8217;s Evans Randriamampianina (or Randria for short), an indie developer from Paris, France. It is Randria&#8217;s first game and it plays as a cross between a platformer and a mini-golf game. You control your egg by using a slingshot action to move through the scene, avoiding dangers and collecting pick-ups along the way.</p>
<p>Randria is an art director who worked for several digital agencies and had some ActionScript experience before he started <em>Egz</em>. He decided he wanted to pursue his childhood dream of creating his own video game, experiencing the entire development process from design to programming to art.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-67102" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/03-screenshot-2208x1242-5-1024x576.png" alt="03-screenshot-2208x1242-5" width="960" height="540" /></p>
<p>&#8220;Several mobile games inspired me: <em>Cut the Rope</em>, <em>Tiny Wings</em>, <em>Angry Birds</em>&#8230; mainly because those games were and still are the most famous mobile games. But they also offer something unique: they are quickly enjoyable, simple to play (only one touch is needed to have fun), and they don&#8217;t require players to spend too much time learning new gameplay mechanics.&#8221; Randria said.</p>
<p>Randria admits that he&#8217;s not a huge mobile gamer and that his playing experience comes from the console world. &#8220;I&#8217;ve grown up playing with the Nintendo NES, Sega Master System, Megadrive, Super Nintendo, PC&#8230; and there are several gameplay mechanics in <em>Egz</em> that actually come from classic games like <em>Sonic The Hedgehog</em>, <em>Mario Bros.</em>, <em>Donkey Kong Country</em>, etc. I think that trying to merge those inspirations is what makes <em>Egz</em> unique,&#8221; he added.</p>
<p>Randria found Corona through one of his digital agencies. They needed a mobile ad game and, while researching engines, a video showed how rapid development with Corona can be.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-67103" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/03-screenshot-2208x1242-2-1024x576.png" alt="03-screenshot-2208x1242-2" width="960" height="540" /></p>
<p>&#8220;<em>Egz</em> is a little bit [more] complex than it seems. There are several gameplay mechanics that I probably wouldn&#8217;t have been able to add if it wasn&#8217;t for Corona,&#8221; Randria said. &#8220;The first thing that comes to mind is Corona&#8217;s many libraries, and one of the most impressive libraries is the <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/guide/index.html?#physics target="_blank">physics</a> library. It&#8217;s insane how easy it is to create a simple ball, bouncing on walls. Within a few lines only! I remember trying to achieve the same thing in ActionScript and&#8230; well, just trying to include the Box2D API in my project gave me headaches. With Corona, you call it by literally writing one line!&#8221;</p>
<p>Having tried Flash, ActionScript, and Unity, Randria said &#8220;I believe that Corona SDK is the fastest way to get playable games. Especially if you&#8217;re working on your first mobile game. All those APIs included in the framework can help save a lot of time/money! And in the last couple of years, I&#8217;ve seen Corona getting bigger and bigger, evolving and offering more, but staying simple!&#8221;</p>
<p>As with many projects, he ran into &#8220;feature creep.&#8221; At 80 levels, 7 different worlds, cutscenes, boss levels, and mini-games, the game was quite a bit for him to take on for his first game. But Corona SDK helped Randria through.</p>
<p><em>Egz</em> has been out for a month on iOS and Android. Randria has plans to port it to Amazon, Apple TV, Windows, and OS X. Previews of the app earned <em>Egz</em> a third-best upcoming app by <a href=http://www.slidedb.com/games/egz target="_blank">SlideDB</a>, and it won the <a href=http://www.pocketgamer.co.uk/r/Android/EGZ/news.asp?c=68782 target="_blank">Very Big Indie Pitch</a> at Pocket Gamer Connects London.</p>
<p><a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/egz-the-origin-of-the-universe/id963477453?ls=1&mt=8 target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-64556" style="margin-right: 10px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/app-store-badge.png" alt="app-store-badge" width="50" height="50" /></a><a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.finalegzgame.lonelywoof target="_blank"><img class="alignnone wp-image-64594" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/google-play-badge.png" alt="google-play-badge" width="50" height="50" /></a></p>
<h3>Wrapping up</h3>
<p><em>Egz</em> stands out among the crowd, but it wasn&#8217;t made by a big studio house. Building your app with Corona SDK will speed up your development and give you plenty of power to build something awesome. What can you create?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2016/06/09/case-study-lonely-woofs-egz/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Case Study: Jordanian TV game show &#8220;Arrange it Correctly&#8221; powered by Corona</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/04/26/case-study-jordanian-tv-game-show-arrange-it-correctly-powered-by-corona/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 18:49:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Case Study - Game Studios]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured App]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[.NET]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game Show]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MSSQL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=66576</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Think Corona SDK is for mobile games? Well it's powering a TV game show. Learn more about how this came to be.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Picture this: It&#8217;s 7:00 p.m. and a popular TV game show is coming on. The host with his perfectly-coiffed hair and big smile stands at his lectern and points to a grid of TVs on a wall. Those TVs display categories, dollar amounts, and eventually answers. He also has a display in front of him with the correct answers. Nearby, three contestants stand at their podiums with TVs that show their scores. The contestants have a touch-sensitive screen to write and submit answers on. Behind the scenes, producers, directors, and judges are driving the game, timing commercials, confirming answers, and more.</p>
<p>Someone had to write software for all of that. They had to network it together with a database and build a complex information system that drives the game. It must have required a huge team of developers and months of development time, right?</p>
<p>For the <a href=http://www.roya.tv/ target="_blank">Roya TV</a> station in Amman, Jordan, along with a creative Corona SDK development team, it did not. Challenged to put together a TV game show in just 30 days, <a href=https://www.maysalward.com/ target="_blank">Maysalward</a>, a 16-person studio in Amman and Irbid, Jordan, beat out seven other studios to get the job of creating <a href=http://www.roya.tv/shows/196-%D8%B1%D8%AA%D8%A8%D9%87%D8%A7-%D8%B5%D8%AD/ target="_blank"><em>Arrange it Correctly</em></a><em>,</em> a TV game show about putting things in the right order. The other studios all wanted six months to do the job, but using Corona SDK, the team knew they could finish the job in much less time. Maysalward challenged a four person team consisting of a senior designer, senior developer, and two application testers to build the game. The team put Corona to the test and met their deadline, albeit with some 22-hour work days.</p>
<p><iframe width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LZDrdeZQDgU?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<h3>The game</h3>
<p>In <em>Arrange it Correctly,</em> three teams of two players stand at podiums with a touch screen Windows device for entering answers. This is driven by a full screen Windows desktop app. On the front of each podium is another Windows device running a full screen app to display the current score of each team. Behind the host, the audience sees a huge display known as the &#8220;big board&#8221; with the core game running. Another Corona-built Windows desktop app monitors the database and delivers the game output to the big board via HDMI cable. The host uses an Android tablet that displays the answers and other information. In the control room, the show&#8217;s director and producers control the pace of the game from a control computer. It&#8217;s all powered by a .NET system connected to a Microsoft SQL server.</p>
<p>Apps built with Corona SDK can run on all of these devices. <a href=https://www.maysalward.com/ target="_blank">Maysalward</a> chose Corona because of how it could both connect to networked, database-driven solutions and create the game&#8217;s displays easily.</p>
<p>According to Tariq Khatib, the senior developer on the project, &#8220;We used reusable stable code from other previous projects which shortened the total time needed for database connections.&#8221; Nour Khrais, Founder and CEO of Maysalward, added, &#8220;We have good experience with Corona and it&#8217;s a smooth development when it comes to mobile and desktop.&#8221;</p>
<p>Corona&#8217;s ease and speed of development for both mobile and desktop came into play as the project moved towards the deadline. &#8220;It was really easy to manage change requests. Sometimes we did immediate onsite changes based on visual feedback from [the] TV Presenter or director or producer&#8230; it was really quick to recompile and replace old versions.&#8221; Khatib continued.</p>
<p>He concluded &#8220;We are very proud of it, and it could have never been built in this time, with this performance, without Corona. Actually we agreed on the delivery time knowing that Corona can do it.&#8221;</p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>We are constantly amazed at where we find Corona being used. Developers are using it to create great new entertainment apps, utility apps, and apps to enrich people&#8217;s lives. This may be one of the most unique case studies yet!</p>
<p>Roya TV has already filmed 40 episodes of <em>Arrange it Correctly </em>with even more to come.</p>
<p>What amazing things can you do with Corona? Cheer for the Maysalward team by reading more about their success in the <a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/62726-live-tv-show-contest-with-prizes-for-winners-made-with-corona-sdk/?#entry325559 target="_blank">Corona forums</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Case Study: Climberia &#8211; a challenging climbing game</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/04/05/case-study-climberia-a-challenging-climbing-game/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Case Study - Game Studios]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured App]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2d]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3D]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[case study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=66351</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this case study, we look at a new Corona-powered game called Climberia. In this innovative game, you play a legless pirate skeleton that climbs from the ocean floor, collecting coins while avoiding a greedy octopus.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-66359" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/icon-150x150.png" alt="icon" width="150" height="150" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/icon-150x150.png 150w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/icon-300x300.png 300w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/icon-768x768.png 768w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/icon-570x570.png 570w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/icon-500x500.png 500w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/icon-1000x1000.png 1000w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/icon-700x700.png 700w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/icon.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />Corona developers are very creative and regularly produce amazing works. In this case study, we look at a new game called <a href=http://www.climberia.com/ target="_blank">Climberia</a>. In this innovative game, you play a legless pirate skeleton that climbs from the ocean floor, collecting coins while avoiding a greedy octopus.</p>
<p>Climberia is the brainchild of Nikola Georgiev and Stoyan Pedev of <a href=http://www.kvaba.com/ target="_blank">Kvaba</a>, a small studio in Sofia, Bulgaria. Georgiev and Pedev decided to start building games in their spare time while having a drink in their local pub.</p>
<p><iframe width="800" height="450" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XFdnalWr-pY?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>After trying a couple of projects that didn&#8217;t gain momentum, they stumbled upon the idea for Climberia. Using a Google search to find a 2D gaming platform, they discovered Corona SDK and quickly had a working demo of their idea. </p>
<p>The gameplay was challenging and fun, but there was a problem: neither Georgiev or Pedev were artists and the game didn&#8217;t look very good. Fortunately, they found <a href=http://robo.bg/ target="_blank">Robo Video Lab</a> who fell in love with the game and the two companies formed a partnership to produce Climberia. The art team used low-polygon 3D models, converted them to 2D still images, and assembled it all into colorful scenes.</p>
<p>The gameplay is very challenging. Like rock climbing, your pirate has to swing his arm and body to grab the next hand-hold. If the pirate lets go, he falls to the ocean floor and dies. Players must keep one finger on the screen the entire time while using another finger to swing the pirate and reach another hand-hold.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-66360" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/Climberia-02-1024x576.png" alt="Climberia-02" width="960" height="540" /></p>
<p>&#8220;We wanted to create a game where the player is challenged not only in the virtual world of the game but also in the physical world – to test his muscles and nerves&#8221;, said Georgiev. &#8220;The original idea was for a climber who has to constantly keep at least one of his hands on the wall, so a player&#8217;s thumb must always drag the screen. With the initial demo, we saw that we could improve the concept by adding the swinging and jumping features.&#8221;</p>
<p>Corona SDK has been critical to their development process. As beginners in the game development field, Georgiev and Pedev found that it was easy to get started developing a 2D game in Corona. Rapid prototyping allowed them to assess the project early on and adjust certain aspects as the project matured.</p>
<p>Climberia is available for iOS on April 5, 2016, and Kvaba plans to release an Android version in the coming months. Check it out in the app store!</p>
<p><a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/climberia-pirates/id1054929556?ls=1&mt=8 target="_blank"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-66270" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/iTunesStore-150x50.png" alt="iTunesStore" width="150" height="50" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Case Study: Glitch Games &#8211; building successful cross-platform adventures</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/03/31/case-study-glitch-games-building-successful-cross-platform-adventures/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2016 18:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Case Study - Game Studios]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corona sdk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indie]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=66259</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this case study, we take a look at Glitch Games, a two-man indie studio from Oxfordshire, UK, and their success using Corona SDK to build popular adventure games.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-66275" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/Blqvc8LmI3JaPAFkANVHAfF2aQ8JBiTaaNOQf_6zKh1VRFt0hDIw320KOSYYyVKJCAw300-150x150.png" alt="Blqvc8LmI3JaPAFkANVHAfF2aQ8JBiTaaNOQf_6zKh1VRFt0hDIw320KOSYYyVKJCA=w300" width="150" height="150" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/Blqvc8LmI3JaPAFkANVHAfF2aQ8JBiTaaNOQf_6zKh1VRFt0hDIw320KOSYYyVKJCAw300-150x150.png 150w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/Blqvc8LmI3JaPAFkANVHAfF2aQ8JBiTaaNOQf_6zKh1VRFt0hDIw320KOSYYyVKJCAw300.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />This is a tale of two best friends since college: Graham Ransom the programmer and Simon Pearce the artist. Even though they went to different universities, both went on to study game development. They started <a href=http://www.glitchgames.co.uk/ target="_blank">Glitch Games</a> in January 2012 working on kids&#8217; educational titles. Within a month after they met, they took part in their first 48 hour game jam and tried to build an adventure game.</p>
<p>The result was  a title called <em>The Hauntening</em> which went on to win that game jam. They ended up releasing the game in the App Store for free to see if there was any interest in it. The feedback was positive and they began working on their first full-fledged adventure game. Eight months later, <em><a href=http://www.foreverlostgame.com/ target="_blank">Forever Lost</a>: Episode 1</em> was released for iOS and Android. Since then they have completed the trilogy and a free prequel game.</p>
<p><iframe width="1060" height="596" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/H9ethihZrMw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" gesture="media" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Graham first discovered Corona SDK in 2009 when Corona was a fledgling framework. When he and Simon formed Glitch Games, it only made sense to continue using Corona SDK.</p>
<p>Having been around for a while, it&#8217;s safe to call Graham a pioneer in mobile adventure games and an early adopter of Corona Labs&#8217; technologies as they come out, including our recent desktop support. Not only is the full suite of games available on Apple&#8217;s App Store, Google Play, and Amazon, it&#8217;s also available on both OS X and Windows desktop. In addition, they have built their own adventure framework called Serenity which sits on top of Corona SDK and allows them to rapidly build adventure games.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-66276" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/hnReR4Kbe1NXOQoHjVgZ60lbkNO1jJKYQPp3JWi0r1otpgKah5zw0873xgmUat_bL6ch900-1024x640.png" alt="hnReR4Kbe1NXOQoHjVgZ60lbkNO1jJKYQPp3JWi0r1otpgKah5zw0873xgmUat_bL6c=h900" width="960" height="600" /></p>
<p>When asked &#8220;Why Corona?&#8221; Graham said &#8220;If it wasn&#8217;t for Corona, <em>Forever Lost</em> wouldn&#8217;t exist today. We&#8217;d most likely have to go get real jobs.&#8221;  With multiple-millions of downloads across all the the stores, Glitch games is one of the proverbial success stories for indie studios. <em>Forever Lost</em> has been #1 in multiple countries and it was short-listed for the TIGA awards a couple of years ago.</p>
<p>Graham likes Corona for ease of development and quick iteration. Their first kids&#8217; apps were turned around in less than a month, while their full adventure games take around eight months to build. Graham&#8217;s advice to those new to app development? &#8220;Download Corona and start making a game!&#8221;</p>
<h3>Availability</h3>
<p><a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/forever-lost-episode-1-hd/id542364897?ls=1&mt=8 target="_blank"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-66270" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/iTunesStore-150x50.png" alt="iTunesStore" width="150" height="50" /></a><a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.glitchgames.foreverlostepisode1hd target="_blank"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-66269" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/GooglePlayStore-150x52.png" alt="GooglePlayStore" width="150" height="52" /></a><a href=http://www.amazon.com/Forever-Lost-Episode-1-HD/dp/B00BF9USIO/ target="_blank"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-66271" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/AmazonStore-150x52.png" alt="AmazonStore" width="150" height="52" /></a><a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/forever-lost-episode-1/id1036708333?ls=1&mt=12 target="_blank"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-66274" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/MacStore-150x52.png" alt="MacStore" width="150" height="52" /></a><a href=http://glitchgames.itch.io/forever-lost-episode-1 target="_blank"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-66273" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/ItchIoStore-150x50.png" alt="ItchIoStore" width="150" height="50" /></a></p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>With a great idea and patience, you can built successful games with Corona SDK. Dream, Build, Ship!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Developer Profile: QuizTix</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/01/19/developer-profile-quiztix/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2016/01/19/developer-profile-quiztix/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 17:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Case Study - Game Studios]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona native builds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[app development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[workflow]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=65262</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Occasionally we have the pleasure of highlighting Corona Developers who are doing great things with Corona SDK. This week we would like to introduce you to QuixTix, a small London based studio, founded by Ian Masters and Albert Marshall.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-65269" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Founders_IanAlbert-300x200.jpg" alt="Founders_Ian&amp;Albert" width="300" height="200" />Occasionally we have the pleasure of highlighting Corona Developers who are doing great things with Corona SDK.</p>
<p>This week we would like to introduce you to QuixTix, a small London based studio, founded by Ian Masters and Albert Marshall.</p>
<p>QuizTix uses Corona Enterprise to produce a series of quiz games, including a BBC branded edition called QuizTix: BBC Comedy Genius, which lets you pit your wits against comedy fans via leaderboards to become the brains of British comedy.</p>
<p>Here’s what Alan, QuizTix&#8217;s star coder, had to say about using Corona SDK to develop their apps.</p>
<h3>Introducing QuizTix</h3>
<p>In 2013, <a href=http://quiztix.co/ target="_blank">QuizTix</a> was founded with the aim of creating a series of family-friendly themed quiz games. The team all had previous experience using <a href=/products/corona-sdk/ target="_blank">Corona SDK</a> so it was our first choice for QuizTix, because of how easily we can create new content.</p>
<p>So much of the &#8216;core&#8217; is taken care of for us that we can concentrate on game play which is where we really wanted to be focusing our attention. However we knew that Corona SDK did not have some functionality that we crucially needed (such as offline builds), and so we looked into <a href=/products/enterprise/ target="_blank">Corona Enterprise</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks to Corona Enterprise, we have seven QuizTix games out now:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href=https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/quiztix-pop-music-quiz/id815117943?mt=8 target="_blank">QuizTix: Pop Music</a></li>
<li><a href=https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/quiztix-movies-quiz/id815118690?mt=8 target="_blank">QuizTix: Movies</a></li>
<li><a href=https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/quiztix-world-football-quiz/id839727240?mt=8 target="_blank">QuizTix: World Football</a></li>
<li><a href=https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/quiztix-video-games-quiz/id815122318?mt=8 target="_blank">QuizTix: Video Games</a></li>
<li><a href=https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/quiztix-musicals-quiz/id836007687?mt=8 target="_blank">QuizTix: Musical</a></li>
<li><a href=https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/quiztix-bbc-comedy-genius/id1015985090?mt=8 target="_blank">QuizTix: BBC Comedy Genius</a></li>
<li><a href=https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/quiztix-international-rugby/id1015985491?mt=8 target="_blank">QuizTix: International Rugby</a></li>
</ul>
<p>We met the BBC at GDC in 2015 (a long way to go to meet someone from London!) and approached them with the idea about the game. The idea of QuizTix has always been to partner with brands to create new versions of QuizTix. We can offer proven game play and exceptional engagement. While the experience is QuizTix, the brand is the real content.</p>
<h3><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-65270" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/promo_1024x500-1024x500.png" alt="promo_1024x500" width="750" height="366" /></h3>
<h3>Why Corona Enterprise?</h3>
<p>A deliberate decision was made to have a separate app for each theme in order to make each game appeal to people who particularly enjoy that subject rather than just being marketed as a general quiz app.</p>
<p>One of the biggest challenges that this created was that we needed a project structure with a single code base which could be used to create multiple apps, in order to minimize development and testing time.</p>
<p>Each game would contain its own unique questions, artwork and audio but changes to the core game mechanics would be applied to all games. This would allow us to release new games with fresh content at a much faster rate, whilst always keeping the existing games up-to-date with the latest features</p>
<p>The most important functionality we needed was the ability to build all versions of the game with a single command. While it&#8217;s a simple enough process to build a single APK / IPA using Corona SDK, it does not have the ability to build two games at once.</p>
<p>Seeing as we currently have seven versions of QuizTix out already and with more on the way, that would mean: Loading one game in the sim, build for iTunes, build for Google Play, build for Amazon. Rinse and repeat six more times!</p>
<p>Corona Enterprise gave us the option to build from the command line. This allows us to create scripts which can build many builds at once, in different configurations (e.g. Google Play builds for all games, iOS+GooglePlay+Amazon builds for a single game). Since the simulator does not get used at all for offline builds, we can continue working while waiting for the builds to complete.</p>
<p>Using Enterprise also allowed us to develop our own plug-ins. This has allowed us to test out many SDKs that we otherwise would not have had access to, which has been essential for monetization/anayltics/etc. QuizTix is targeted at a super casual audience our focus is on monetizing all players via high quality, responsible and largely unobtrusive ads. We have worked hard on finding the best partners to get great fill and eCPM’s.</p>
<h3>Additional tools</h3>
<p><img class="alignright wp-image-65271 size-medium" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/iPhone6_4-169x300.png" alt="iPhone6_4" width="169" height="300" />Keeping the overall file size as low as possible was very important to us, as it can be a significant factor when trying to achieve downloads in markets with lower internet speeds or data caps. To facilitate this, we integrated a number of other tools into our build system, with very little effort required:</p>
<p><strong><a href=https://www.codeandweb.com/texturepacker target="_blank">TexturePacker</a></strong> &#8211; This has a command line implementation so by putting artwork into separate folders in our source folders, we can pack them into single texture images. This allows us to save on memory usage by packing all game characters into a single PNG. Corona already has built-in functions to then use each image from the texture sheet, so it&#8217;s a great way to save space.</p>
<p><a href=http://www.mapeditor.org/ target="_blank"><strong>Tiled</strong></a> &#8211; Similarly we use Tiled to create the background for our game, which packs the background into a map in exactly the same way as TexturePacker but allows us to place the background tiles in a nice GUI.</p>
<p><strong><a href=http://www.imagemagick.org/script/index.php target="_blank">ImageMagick</a></strong> &#8211; One of the more time consuming parts of asset creation for us was exporting multiple sizes to account for devices with differing resolutions. While it&#8217;s not a huge problem to create a single image, then an @2x and @4x version, when those images then need tweaking and new images need to be made the time quickly adds up. We implemented ImageMagick so that we can just include the highest resolution images in our source folders, and then have ImageMagick create the lower resolution versions.</p>
<p><strong>PNG Compression</strong> &#8211; Even using TexturePacker, we knew we could reduce the size of our app down further. We use a PNG compression tool called <a href=https://pngquant.org/ target="_blank">PNGQuant</a> to convert all images from 24bit to 8bit color. This reduces the file size to around 1/3 of its original size (e.g. one image I&#8217;ve just picked at random went from 201KB to 72KB). This helped us to get closer to our goal of bringing the file size of each app down to ~20MB. This works for us because our game has a cartoony look, however if your game contains photos then it may not work quite so well.</p>
<p><strong>Audio Compression</strong> &#8211; like the artwork, we keep full size audio files in our source folders, but copy and process them into the final project folders in order to reduce the file size.</p>
<p>We also made the decision to convert the files to mono, as many mobile devices have a single speaker and so do not benefit from stereo sound files.</p>
<p>Generally we use WAVs as the source file, and then convert to Oggs for Android, and CAF for iOS. OSX has a built in audio conversion tool called <a href=https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/documentation/Darwin/Reference/ManPages/man1/afconvert.1.html target="_blank">afconvert</a>. For Android we downloaded a tool called <a href=http://www.rarewares.org/ogg-oggenc.php target="_blank">oggenc</a>.</p>
<p>There are a few more tools we have used alongside Enterprise, separately from our main build script process. Most of these could be used with Corona SDK projects, but are still worth a mention due to how useful they are.</p>
<p><a href=http://esotericsoftware.com/ target="_blank"><strong>Spine</strong></a> &#8211; This has made character animations significantly easier, and they look better than if we had tried to create them in code using transitions.</p>
<p><a href=https://git-scm.com/ target="_blank"><strong><img class="size-medium wp-image-65274 alignright" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/iPhone6_2-169x300.png" alt="iPhone6_2" width="169" height="300" />Git</strong></a> &#8211; I cannot emphasize how important good version control is, especially if multiple people are working on the project.</p>
<p>Many people start out by simply duplicating their project folder when they reach a safe point, which is &#8220;ok&#8221; for a small project with one developer.</p>
<p>Using Git/<a href=https://www.mercurial-scm.org/ target="_blank">Mercurial</a>/something similar is fantastic because it allows you to do things like:</p>
<ul>
<li>Have 2 people working on different parts of the same file, Git will then work out what changed and attempt to merge both peoples work.</li>
<li>Go back in time! If you use a nice GUI tool like <a href=https://www.sourcetreeapp.com/ target="_blank">SourceTree</a>, you can see a long list of all the changes you have committed. This is great because sometimes you know you changed a file, but don&#8217;t remember what it looked like before, or when you changed it. You can search back through the file&#8217;s history to find what changed.</li>
<li>*Create &#8216;branches&#8217; which allows you to say &#8220;leave the current project as it is, but create a separate line of changes from this point&#8221;. This is handy if you want to test a new library without risking the stable working version of the project for other people.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><a href=https://aws.amazon.com/s3/ target="_blank">Amazon S3</a></strong> &#8211; Sometimes we make changes to the game that we do not feel require an update (e.g. fixing a typo), but would still prefer were in the game as soon as possible. We use Amazon S3 to store images and files which contain strings/values/etc which are used in the game. This allows us to fix small issues in the game by updating the S3 files, which are then pulled into the app on startup. Obviously you would need to include a hard-coded copy of these files for times when no internet connection is available.</p>
<h3>Challenges</h3>
<p>In terms of limitations, I would say the biggest hurdles we&#8217;ve encountered with Enterprise is that you need to have an understanding of how iOS and Android native development works.</p>
<p>The sample projects should help you out a lot on this front, and dare I say that with a bit of playing around everyone should be able to get the basics working in a short time.</p>
<p>Some things may seem confusing at first. For instance, with Enterprise you do not add plug-ins to your build.settings file, you add their files manually and will often need to add details to other files such as AndroidManifest.</p>
<p>However, you&#8217;ll quickly realize that this is a small price to pay for the freedom it gives you. Enterprise really is a way of creating native projects that let you use Corona&#8217;s Lua libraries to make game creation easier.</p>
<p>We are at the point where we can release new versions quicker each time!  Going forward we can only see Enterprise making it easier for us to continue this way.</p>
<p>So if any developers out there are on the fence about whether Enterprise would be useful, for us it’s a no-brainer, but I would recommend re-reading some of the advantages &amp; disadvantages I&#8217;ve pointed out. The Corona staff and forum community are always extremely helpful if you need any more guidance.</p>
<h3>Success</h3>
<p>The players over the seven titles have answered questions more than 30 million times and that&#8217;s very attractive to brands looking to find a place in the mind&#8217;s of consumers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2016/01/19/developer-profile-quiztix/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
