<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>inna &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/author/inna/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>inna &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Guest piece: Finding a niche market, publishing three-figure apps</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/12/06/guest-piece-finding-a-niche-market-publishing-three-figure-apps/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/12/06/guest-piece-finding-a-niche-market-publishing-three-figure-apps/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 22:25:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=52190</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Matthew Chapman is the owner of Origin Technologies and a Florida-based Corona Ambassador. Matthew has been creating apps for the iPhone since the App Store was first launched and has published mobile content for iOS, Android, Kindle and NOOK. His most recent release, and his first game, is called Coin Adventure and is now available on the App Store.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Matthew Chapman is the owner of <a href=http://www.origintech.net>Origin/ Technologies</a> and a Florida-based Corona Ambassador. Matthew has been creating apps for the iPhone since the App Store was first launched and has published mobile content for iOS, Android, Kindle and NOOK. His most recent release, and his first game, is called <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/coin-adventure/id674322544?mt=8>Coin Adventure</a> and is now available on the App Store.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Matthew-Chapman.png" alt="Matthew Chapman headshot" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-52477" />My first foray into mobile was building an app called <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/florida-poisonous-snakes/id331177720?mt=8>Florida Poisonous Snakes</a>. While I realize that snakes are in fact venomous, not poisonous, someone had already taken that name, despite the fact that they never released the app. I wrote the app in NimbleKit (now owned by Sencha) and showed some basic information about six venomous snakes in Florida along with several pictures. The app has since evolved, and I rewrote it in <a href=coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk/>Corona SDK</a> along with all 15 of my current apps.</p>
<p>While I am particularly fond of my first app, what I am most proud of is the unique niche I created for my company. Over 13 years ago, I partnered with Jackson Mumey of <a href=http://www.celebrationbarreview.com>Celebration/ Bar Review</a> to help with their technology needs. Over time, the partnership progressed into digitizing audio lectures into first a streamable format, then for the iPod, and eventually putting the courses into an app format.</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Celebration-Bar-Exam-Review-169x300.jpeg" alt="Celebration Bar Exam Review" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-52199" />Over the past several years, my company created seven apps that cover the Bar Exams in various states including <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/california-bar-exam-course/id408028413?mt=8>California</a>, <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/florida-bar-exam-course/id408054018?mt=8>Florida</a> and <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/new-york-bar-exam-course/id408402766?mt=8>New York</a>. Each of these apps start at a price point of $199.99. That is not a typo. I&#8217;m responsible for the programming while Jackson Mumey works on the content. From there, we split the profits after Apple’s take. </p>
<p>The result: students that use the apps have an extremely high pass rate. Delving into the mobile world provided a way for Jackson to reach more students with his coursework with no startup costs. Some students of the app go on to mentor directly with Celebration Bar Review, helping Jackson further grow his business. These apps also provided us with a fantastic revenue stream and the continuation of a long-term business partnership. </p>
<p>At first, we received downloads twice a year for a few months as students ramped up for tests that are only offered twice a year. Now, downloads are more consistent month to month and student feedback has been phenomenal. We are releasing updates on a regular basis and continuing to invest the time into delivering a great product for our students. Recently, I even updated the Celebration Bar Review apps to have the look and feel of iOS 7. While we don&#8217;t discuss download numbers, it suffices to say that receiving even 5-10 downloads a month at this price point is far better than receiving ten app downloads at the standard $.99 cost.</p>
<p>The niche and high price point of my apps has allowed a bit of fame, income, and the flexibility to build the apps that my kids want to play.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/12/06/guest-piece-finding-a-niche-market-publishing-three-figure-apps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>App of the Week: Windsquire</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/12/02/app-of-the-week-windsquire/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/12/02/app-of-the-week-windsquire/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 00:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=52653</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Windsquire is an addicting game that combines skill-based racing and maze-like obstacles. Created by Baltimore-based <a href="http://www.mindgrub.com/">Mindgrub</a>, the storyline follows a squire who ventures on a quest to amass treasure. When the squire tumbles onto mystic runes, he becomes infused with the ability to fly by controlling the wind. His mission: to find treasure while escaping a ferocious dragon.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-52654" style="margin: 0px 20px 10px 0px;" alt="Windsquire icon" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Screen-Shot-2013-11-26-at-9.57.56-AM.png" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Screen-Shot-2013-11-26-at-9.57.56-AM.png 182w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Screen-Shot-2013-11-26-at-9.57.56-AM-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 182px) 100vw, 182px" /><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-52979" style="margin: 0px 2px 10px 20px;" alt="Windsquire screenshot" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/screen568x568-1-e1386013540947.jpeg" />Windsquire is an addicting game that combines skill-based racing and maze-like obstacles. Created by Baltimore-based <a href=http://www.mindgrub.com/>Mindgrub</a>, the storyline follows a squire who ventures on a quest to amass treasure. When the squire tumbles onto mystic runes, he becomes infused with the ability to fly by controlling the wind. His mission: to find treasure while escaping a ferocious dragon.</p>
<p>Windsquire was originally conceived to be a puzzle game involving mazes and a floating balloon, but game director Mark Mirchandani told us that &#8220;Windsquire quickly evolved into a fantastically whimsical and intense experience involving dragons, magical powers, and weapons used to fight through the five unique worlds within Dragon Castle.&#8221; After nine months of development, the game evolved into a unique and creative title, now available for iOS and Google Play.</p>
<p>Download Windquire from <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/ca/app/windsquire-race-from-dragon/id722392292?mt=8>iTunes</a> or <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mindgrub.games.windsquire>Google Play</a> and begin your adventure as a brave young squire!</p>
<p><iframe width="1060" height="596" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FFg85GjRsVw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" gesture="media" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/12/02/app-of-the-week-windsquire/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cast your vote for November&#8217;s App of the Month!</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/11/27/cast-your-vote-for-novembers-app-of-the-month/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 19:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News & Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App of the Month]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vote]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=52735</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This month, we've witnessed a bunch of star Corona-powered apps and games and selected a handful as Apps of the Week. <strong>Cast your vote</strong> for your favorite November app below and share the poll with friends, family and fans! You can check out reviews of each of the finalists by clicking on their corresponding icons.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are few things the Corona team loves more than discovering incredible mobile content from the Corona community. Your creativity inspires us and we encourage you to <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/share>share your apps</a> so that we can promote them as App of the Week, in the press, and beyond!</p>
<p>This month, we&#8217;ve witnessed a bunch of star Corona-powered apps and games and selected a handful as Apps of the Week. <strong>Cast your vote</strong> for your favorite November app below and share the poll with friends, family and fans! You can check out reviews of each of the finalists by clicking on their corresponding icons.</p>
<p>Thank you and happy holidays from the entire Corona team!</p>
<table style="width:100%;">
<tr>
<td><a href=/blog/2013/11/25/app-of-the-week-this-monster-creatures-that-love-color/><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Screen-Shot-2013-11-25-at-12.27.37-PM-147x150.png" alt="This Monster icon" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-52515" /></a></td>
<td><a href=/blog/2013/11/18/app-of-the-week-baby-turkey-trouble/><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Screen-Shot-2013-11-18-at-10.45.51-AM-150x147.png" alt="Baby Turkey Trouble" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-51863" /></a></td>
<td><a href=/blog/2013/11/11/app-of-the-week-perplexicon/><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Screen-Shot-2013-11-08-at-2.29.09-PM-150x147.png" alt="Perplexicon icon" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-51320" /></a></td>
<td><a href=/blog/2013/11/04/app-of-the-week-elevator-joe/><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/Screen-Shot-2013-10-31-at-1.19.52-PM-150x150.png" alt="Elevator Joe icon" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-50951" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/Screen-Shot-2013-10-31-at-1.19.52-PM-150x150.png 150w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/Screen-Shot-2013-10-31-at-1.19.52-PM.png 184w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" /></a></td>
</tr>
</table>
<hr />
<div class="row-fluid">
<div class="span7"> [poll id=&#8221;3&#8243;]</div>
<div class="span7">&nbsp;</div></div>
<p><em>This poll will close on Friday, December 6 at 23:59pm PT.</em></p>
<div id="custom-tweet-button">
  <a href=https://twitter.com/share?text=October+App+of+the+Month+-+Cast+your+vote%21 class="twitter popup">Tweet this poll</a>
</div>
<hr />
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>App of the Week: This Monster &#8211; Creatures that Love Color</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/11/25/app-of-the-week-this-monster-creatures-that-love-color/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/11/25/app-of-the-week-this-monster-creatures-that-love-color/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 02:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=52514</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Combining the power of <a href="http://www.coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk">Corona SDK</a> and <a href="http://www.Kwiksher.com/">Kwik</a>, a previous art director and graphic designer at Kate Spade created <a href="http://thismonster.info/">This Monster</a> for the enjoyment of young players. This Monster is a homage to hand-made, textured art, offering children a fun, safe environment to explore their creativity on the iPad.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-52515" style="margin: 0px 20px 10px 0px;" alt="This Monster icon" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Screen-Shot-2013-11-25-at-12.27.37-PM.png" />Combining the power of <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk>Corona SDK</a> and <a href=http://www.Kwiksher.com>Kwik/</a>, a previous art director and graphic designer at Kate Spade created <a href=http://thismonster.info/>This Monster</a> for the enjoyment of young players. This Monster is a homage to hand-made, textured art, offering children a fun, safe environment to explore their creativity on the iPad.</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-52518" style="margin: 0px 0px 10px 20px;" alt="This Monster screenshot" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/This-Monster-.jpeg" />Nearly every element of the app incorporates charm and a small lesson for young players. For example, by feeding a monster that enjoys eating &#8220;colors,&#8221; children learn about different hues like turquoise and fuchsia. There&#8217;s also no shortage of unique characters, ranging from a polka-dot painter to a musical mermaid. After spending a bit of time with This Monster, I found the most charming element to be the app&#8217;s incorporation of &#8220;visual textures&#8221; — puff balls, cloth fabric, construction paper, and more — all of which add a layer of &#8220;realness&#8221; rarely seen in mobile content.</p>
<p>This special touch was even recognized by <a href=http://www.fastcodesign.com/3021126/wanted/former-kate-spade-art-director-develops-an-adorbs-childrens-book-app>Fast Company</a> as writer Shonquis Moreno noted that, &#8220;It&#8217;s rare to see and &#8216;touch&#8217; things on the iPad screen that evoke the texture, color, and unpolished feel of real life.&#8221; To experience the app for yourself, download <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/this-monster-creatures-that/id675399364?mt=8>This Monster</a> from iTunes for $1.99.</p>
<p><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/71056125" height="281" width="500" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p><a href=http://vimeo.com/71056125>this monster</a> from <a href=http://vimeo.com/user19756274>super circle</a> on <a href=https://vimeo.com>Vimeo/</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/11/25/app-of-the-week-this-monster-creatures-that-love-color/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest piece: Adding polish to your mobile game</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/11/21/guest-piece-adding-polish-to-your-mobile-game/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/11/21/guest-piece-adding-polish-to-your-mobile-game/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 23:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transition library]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=52228</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Noah Malewicz is the founder of <a href="http://www.chunkyapps.com/">Chunky Apps</a>, an independent development studio of one. He is passionate about making fun, cartoony games for mobile devices and uses Corona SDK to accomplish this goal. His latest game, City Birds, was Corona's App of the Week in mid-October and Noah was featured as a <a href="http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/coronageek/corona-geek-hangout-61/">guest on Corona Geek</a> shortly thereafter.

After attending a NY-based Meetup, Noah was inspired to focus on adding polish to his game - starting with jazzing up the "Menu" screen. In his guest piece, he shares how he accomplished this task, along with offering tips for other indie developers.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Noah Malewicz is the founder of <a href=http://www.chunkyapps.com/>Chunky Apps</a>, an independent development studio of one. He is passionate about making fun, cartoony games for mobile devices and uses Corona SDK to accomplish this goal. His latest game, <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2013/10/21/app-of-the-week-city-birds/>City Birds</a>, was a Corona App of the Week in mid-October and Noah was featured as a <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/coronageek/corona-geek-hangout-61/>guest on Corona Geek</a> shortly thereafter.</p>
<p>After attending a NY-based Meetup, Noah was inspired to focus on adding polish to his game &#8211; starting with jazzing up the &#8220;Menu&#8221; screen. In his guest piece, he shares how he accomplished this task, along with offering tips for other indie developers.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Noah-Malewicz-headshot.jpg" alt="Noah Malewicz headshot" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-52272" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Noah-Malewicz-headshot.jpg 180w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Noah-Malewicz-headshot-150x150.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 180px) 100vw, 180px" />Making your game look polished can take a lot of work. In this post, I will talk about an often overlooked part of your game &#8211; the &#8220;Menu Screen&#8221; &#8211; and what you can do to add a little life and excitement to it.</p>
<h2>Revamping the Menu screen</h2>
<p>Over the summer, I attended a <a href=http://www.meetup.com/gaming/events/123242362/?gj=wc1c_e&a=wc1c_gnl&rv=wc1c_e&_af_eid=123242362&_af=event>Meetup in New York City</a> conducted by Jesse Freeman from Microsoft entitled: “How to Successfully Polish Your Game.&#8221; He had many good insights and I’d like to share one of them with you that really took <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2013/10/21/app-of-the-week-city-birds/>City Birds</a> to the next level: polishing my Menu screen.</p>
<p>The basic idea is to get &#8220;movement&#8221; on your Menu screen. This could be anything from a blinking Start button to having the individual elements slide into position from offscreen. That movement or animation, even if it&#8217;s very minimal, has a big impact on the look and feel of the game.</p>
<p>Up until that particular Meetup, I had been working hard on my gameplay without really considering the Menu screen. I planned on showing the game logo with a big &#8220;PLAY&#8221; button and I figured that any other buttons I needed would somehow “fit in.&#8221;</p>
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Redesigned-menu-screen-City-Birds-300x225.png" alt="Redesigned menu screen - City Birds" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-52229" />After the event, I decided to completely redesign my Menu screen to fit the feel of the game. I pulled in one of the building images I was using in the game and put a birdcage, with a bird occupant, on the roof of it. This gives players a hint to the gameplay, where they will need to drag the birds into cages. I also carried the “city” theme into my Menu by making my buttons actual street signs that you would see in a city.</p>
<h2>Bringing in the movement</h2>
<p>I was happy with the look of the screen, so it was time to work on the movement. Using <a href=http://docs.coronalabs.com/api/library/transition/to.html>Corona’s transition library</a>, I was able to easily make the street signs slide in from the left and the building slide in from the right. Voilà; instant action! Then for a little effect, I had the other two buttons on the bottom slide in last, just to stack the animation, so everything didn&#8217;t happen at once.</p>
<p>Once I was happy with the finished Menu screen, I wanted to up the ante a bit and thought: &#8220;What if the birds actually flew through the screen?&#8221; I already had the code to make them fly so why not try it here? Turns out, it looked really cool. The Menu screen had constant movement now and once the birds reached the end of the screen, they would reappear from the left again. It really brought the game to life.</p>
<p><iframe width="1060" height="795" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/DIbv4wtbnOo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" gesture="media" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<h2>Some final touches</h2>
<p>Finally, I tried adding the whole in-game dragging mechanic to the birds on the Menu screen. While I liked it at first, I ultimately decided it was too much and took it out. I also wanted to create a 3D feel with some birds off in the distance that would fly behind the building, so the dragging just didn&#8217;t make sense.</p>
<p>The final touch I added may not be noticed by many but it&#8217;s still pretty cool. In City Birds, you can unlock more and more birds. I decided once you unlock a bird in the game, they would also unlock on the Menu screen. So once you unlock a bird or two, look closely and you should see your new friend flying happily about on the Menu screen with his pals.</p>
<h2>In conclusion</h2>
<p>All in all, I&#8217;m very happy with the way the final Menu screen came out &#8211; it&#8217;s much better than what I had originally planned. All this improvement came from just trying to get a little movement into my Menu screen. A good takeaway lesson is that you&#8217;re not finished after all the gameplay has been coded and the game is playing just right &#8211; don&#8217;t forget to make the wrapper look just as good as what you have on the inside.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/11/21/guest-piece-adding-polish-to-your-mobile-game/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest piece: Launching an app on a tight budget</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/11/21/guest-piece-launching-an-app-on-a-tight-budget/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/11/21/guest-piece-launching-an-app-on-a-tight-budget/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 16:01:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=52167</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Erick V. Garayblas is a game designer and founder of Kuyi Mobile, a game development company based in Manila. Erick has been developing games for over 12 years and created a number of award-winning and successful titles including <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/streetfood-tycoon/id498812738?mt=8">Streetfood Tycoon</a>, which has received millions of downloads worldwide.

In his guest piece, Erik shares valuable tips for indies on launching an app on a tight budget. This piece was originally published on <a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/ErickGarayblas/20131118/205060/Launching_an_app_on_a_tight_budget.php">Gamasutra.com</a>.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Erick V. Garayblas is a game designer and founder of Kuyi Mobile, a game development company based in Manila. Erick has been developing games for over 12 years and created a number of award-winning and successful titles including <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/streetfood-tycoon/id498812738?mt=8>Streetfood Tycoon</a>, which has received millions of downloads worldwide.</p>
<p>In his guest piece, Erik shares valuable tips for indies on launching an app on a tight budget. This piece was originally published on <a href=http://www.gamasutra.com/blogs/ErickGarayblas/20131118/205060/Launching_an_app_on_a_tight_budget.php>Gamasutra.com</a>.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Erick-Garayblass-headshot.png" alt="Erick Garayblas&#039;s headshot" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-52226" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Erick-Garayblass-headshot.png 200w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Erick-Garayblass-headshot-150x150.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" />So you&#8217;ve finally finished that <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/i-want-to-build/games/>Corona SDK-powered game</a> and submitted it to Apple. What to do next? Creating a nice game is only half the battle, what you do after you finish your game is another story. </p>
<p>Eight years ago, it was as easy as finishing a game, selling it online and waiting for sales to come in. Now, there&#8217;s even more work involved after submitting your game to the App Store. So how do you spread the word about your game? </p>
<p>Sad to say, a huge part of a successful launch depends on what you do during the development stage, weeks or months even before you release your game. Below is a list that I used to guide me for the release of <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2013/11/04/app-of-the-week-elevator-joe/>Elevator Joe</a>, a game that I built with <a href=coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk/>Corona SDK</a>. It&#8217;s the same list I used when launching <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/streetfood-tycoon/id498812738?mt=8>Streetfood Tycoon</a>, a game that earned me 9M+ downloads across multiple app markets!</p>
<h2>Prior to launch</h2>
<p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Setup my own app network.</strong> I have nine apps to date, all of which have the ability to &#8220;push&#8221; news to my players. If this is your first app, be sure you have something within your app that you can use to promote new products easily or simply push news and updates about your games. This will come handy as your catalogue (and user base) grows.</li>
<li><strong>Social media.</strong> I know, I know. You&#8217;ve been too busy developing your game that you didn&#8217;t even have time to open up a Twitter account or a Facebook page. This isn&#8217;t the 90s. News travels faster than a speeding train nowadays especially on social media, so make it a point to open up your social channels even before you start your development. You&#8217;ll be glad you did.</li>
<li><strong>The power of blogging.</strong> As indie developers, one of our advantages is that we can be more &#8220;personal&#8221; to our fans and players and one way we can do that is by sharing our experiences through a blog. It doesn&#8217;t matter if you post once a week or once a month as long as you engage with your users, get feedback from them and keep them posted about what you&#8217;re doing. You&#8217;ll be able to grow your fan base by the time you launch your app.</li>
<li><strong>Schedule cross-promotions.</strong> Believe it or not, there are lots of indie developers out there who are willing to promote your app in exchange for a promotion so immerse yourself within the indie development community (a lot of them are active on Twitter) and connect with them. You will not only get support, but gain friends!</li>
<li>A<strong>pp icon, screenshots, keywords and product description.</strong> There&#8217;s really no guarantee to what works or what doesn&#8217;t but be sure you have eye-catching and convincing assets. Experiment with these whenever you push a new update and always measure the results.</li>
</ol>
<p>
<h2>Following the launch</h2>
<p>
<ol>
<li><strong>PRMac.</strong> I have tried a lot of online press release services and PRMac by far, has produced the best results for me. At $20, it&#8217;s a good deal to have your news posted to as many as 800 sites covering iOS and Mac software news. Nope, I&#8217;m not affiliated with them, I&#8217;m just a happy customer.</li>
<li><strong>Family and friends.</strong> Word of mouth is still the best form of marketing so if your friends and family can help you spread the word within their own circles, you will have a good head-start.</li>
<li><strong>YouTube.</strong> Free isn&#8217;t enough anymore to guarantee a download or convince a player to try your app. Some players would prefer see your app in action without even trying it so be sure to have a trailer of your game handy. Include the video in your press release, website and promote it to your social media channels.</li>
<li><strong>Review sites.</strong> Submit your app to as many review sites as possible. The more reviews you can get, the better visibility you will have. It may take hours of your day it&#8217;s but worth it, especially if you can establish connections with the media. Here&#8217;s a list of sites that I reach out to: <a href=http://maniacdev.com/2012/05/ios-app-review-sites>http://maniacdev.com/2012/05/ios-app-review-sites</a>.</li>
<li><strong>Schedule contests and promos.</strong> Players love rewards and prizes. Arrange small contests either on Twitter or Facebook and reward your avid players. Promos are also a great way to have your fans spread the word about your new game.</li>
<li><strong>Share your work.</strong> Lastly, don&#8217;t forget to <a href=/community/share/>share your app with Corona Labs</a> for potentiall more exposure!</li>
</ol>
<p>
<p>Do you have any tips to share?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/11/21/guest-piece-launching-an-app-on-a-tight-budget/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest Piece: Announcing Corona Professional Services for Businesses</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/11/19/guest-piece-announcing-corona-professional-services-cps-for-businesses/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/11/19/guest-piece-announcing-corona-professional-services-cps-for-businesses/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 17:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona Professional Services]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CPS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=51888</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dev Gandhi is the CEO of <a href="http://www.reliablecoders.com/">ReliableCoders</a>. Prior to starting ReliableCoders, Dev was a founding member of <a href="http://www.nexage.com/">Nexage</a>, one of the world’s leading mobile ad networks. Moving on to create something new, Dev aimed to change the way development was executed during the technology boom of this decade.

Today, Dev writes on the launch of <a href="http://services.coronalabs.com/">Corona Professional Services (CPS)</a>, a new partnership between Corona Labs and ReliableCoders. Through this partnership, <a href="http://www.coronalabs.com/i-want-to-build/business-apps/" target="_blank">businesses</a> can take advantage of our mobile development expertise via consulting services, premium support, and customized training.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Dev Gandhi is the CEO of <a href=http://www.reliablecoders.com/>ReliableCoders</a>. Prior to starting ReliableCoders, Dev was a founding member of <a href=http://www.nexage.com/>Nexage</a>, one of the world’s leading mobile ad networks. Moving on to create something new, Dev aimed to change the way development was executed during the technology boom of this decade.</p>
<p>Today, Dev writes on the launch of <a href=http://services.coronalabs.com>Corona/ Professional Services (CPS)</a>, a new partnership between Corona Labs and ReliableCoders. Through this partnership, <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/i-want-to-build/business-apps/ target="_blank">businesses</a> can take advantage of our mobile development expertise via consulting services, premium support, and customized training.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Reliablecoders_2.0_logo_dklt.png" alt="ReliableCoders" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-52000" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Reliablecoders_2.0_logo_dklt.png 337w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Reliablecoders_2.0_logo_dklt-300x58.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 337px) 100vw, 337px" />As human beings, it’s natural for us to want to continually improve ourselves. We want to evolve to become stronger and more effective in what we do every day. As business owners, service providers, and app developers, this especially rings true during this era of fast technological advances.<br />
Here at <a href=http://www.reliablecoders.com/>ReliableCoders</a>, we specialize in helping people become more effective, whether we are showing someone how to build better solutions or doing the development for them. </p>
<p>Our evolution has brought us here to partner with Corona Labs to bring you <a href=http://services.coronalabs.com>Corona/ Professional Services</a> (CPS). Through our partnership, we aim to assist companies and create the best possible mobile content to solve business challenges. With the launch of CPS, we’re offering a free App Benchmark Study for clients who already have a live mobile app, or a Project Analysis Consultation for those with an app in development. <a href=http://services.coronalabs.com>Click/ here</a> for more details.</p>
<p>ReliableCoders is a premium mobile design and development studio based in Silicon Valley, just a stone’s throw from our friends at Corona Labs. We deliver a seamless and compelling user experience for all client projects. We understand that for businesses, the fine details lie in the backend architecture, while for end-users, it’s all about experience. </p>
<p>CPS offers consulting in the following areas:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Competitive Market Landscape Study</strong>: Conduct an analysis of your app within its competitive environment before you start development.</li>
<li><strong>Feasibility Study</strong>: Evaluate the potential success of your app, website, or business venture before you begin working on execution.</li>
<li><strong>Security Audit</strong>: Evaluate your software’s information system, measuring how well it conforms to modern security standards.</li>
<li><strong>Compliance Study</strong>: Analyze your app’s adherence to industry standards by checking its compliance in key areas.</li>
<li><strong>Usability Study</strong>: Ensure that the final details are just right with a user experience analysis.</li>
<li><strong>Social Media Integration</strong>: Identify and execute social network integrations within an app, whether for internal or consumer-facing interactions.</li>
<li><strong>Cross-Platform Application Development</strong>: Analyze workflow processes and requirements for cross-platform app development for a specific project.</li>
<li><strong>Enterprise Data Integration</strong>: Identify of how to best integrate rich data from platforms such as Salesforce, SAP, and Oracle.</li>
</ul>
<p>Merging our development experience with the rich software capabilities of Corona SDK and Corona Enterprise, we’re proud to present the best and brightest consultants and developers at your disposal. Our team has worked with brands including Verizon, Microsoft, Korn/Ferry and VMware and have developed apps for clients in verticals including, but not limited to health, education, human resources, finance, hardware integrations, and mobile gaming.</p>
<p>For more information, please head to the <a href=www.coronalabs.com/services>Corona Professional Services</a> page. We look forward to working with you!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/11/19/guest-piece-announcing-corona-professional-services-cps-for-businesses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>App of the Week: Baby Turkey Trouble</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/11/18/app-of-the-week-baby-turkey-trouble/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 23:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mobile App of the Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=51862</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To bring you a bit of Thanksgiving cheer, we've selected an App of the Week that combines quirky baby turkeys with the popular match-3 game genre. As the official app of the <a href="http://www.freebirdsmovie.com/">Free Birds</a> movie, Baby Turkey Trouble is a family-friendly holiday game that stars Tuff Puffs, adorable baby turkeys from the feature film.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-51863" style="margin: 2px 20px 20px 0px;" alt="Baby Turkey Trouble" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Screen-Shot-2013-11-18-at-10.45.51-AM.png" />To bring you a bit of Thanksgiving cheer, we&#8217;ve selected an App of the Week that combines quirky baby turkeys with the popular match-3 game genre. As the official app of the <a href=http://www.freebirdsmovie.com/>Free Birds</a> movie, Baby Turkey Trouble is a family-friendly holiday game that stars Tuff Puffs, adorable baby turkeys from the feature film.</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-51864" style="margin: 2px 2px 10px 20px;" alt="Baby Turkey Trouble Screenshot" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Baby-Turkey-Trouble-Screenshot-169x300.jpeg" />When these helpless baby birds get stuck in an oak tree, they need your help to make it to safety. Use your finger to swap the location of birds on a grid and create matches of three or more to score points and unlock power-ups. The more matches you create, the higher your score and the more silly sound effects you&#8217;ll enjoy.</p>
<p>By far, the most endearing element of the game was Reel FX&#8217;s incorporation of characters&#8217; sound snippets from the movie, voiced by Owen Wilson, Woody Harrelson, George Takei and Amy Poehler. If you&#8217;re curious to learn more, you can read about the making of Baby Turkey Trouble in last week&#8217;s guest piece by Dan Ferguson, head of the digital/interactive group at Reel FX.</p>
<p>Baby Turkey Trouble is a free game, available on <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/app/id739560013>iTunes</a>, <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.reelfx.btt&hl=en>Google Play</a> and the <a href=http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00GM3ITMA>Amazon Appstore</a>. Download it today and check out the film, now in theaters.</p>
<p><iframe width="1060" height="596" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r-RnGP63rpM?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" gesture="media" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest piece: 8 tips on creating engaging mobile content for young minds</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/11/15/guest-piece-8-tips-on-creating-engaging-content-for-young-minds/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2013/11/15/guest-piece-8-tips-on-creating-engaging-content-for-young-minds/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 16:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[educational apps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kids apps]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=51740</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Elpida Voulgari is the co-founder of <a href="http://www.avokiddo.com/">Avokiddo</a>, a studio focused on creating high quality educational apps for young children. Avokiddo’s Beck and Bo has received several awards, including a 2013 Parents’ Choice Approved Award and was recognized as an App of the Week by Corona Labs. The studio’s latest title, Avokiddo Emotions, was featured on iTunes’ main banner in Education and graced by Apple as New and Noteworthy. Apple also handpicked both apps as “Best for ages 5 and under.”

In today's piece, Elpida shares tips on developing children’s apps and discusses elements to consider when creating mobile content for youngsters.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Elpida Voulgari is the co-founder of <a href=http://www.avokiddo.com/>Avokiddo</a>, a studio focused on creating high quality educational apps for young children. Avokiddo’s <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2013/01/28/app-of-the-week-beck-and-bo/>Beck and Bo</a> has received several awards, including a 2013 Parents’ Choice Approved Award and was recognized as an App of the Week by Corona Labs. The studio’s latest title, Avokiddo Emotions, was featured on iTunes’ main banner in Education and graced by Apple as New and Noteworthy. Apple also handpicked both apps as “Best for ages 5 and under.”</p>
<p>In today&#8217;s piece, Elpida shares tips on developing children’s apps and discusses elements to consider when creating mobile content for youngsters.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Elpida-Voulgari-1-277x300.jpg" alt="Elpida Voulgari headshot" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-51741" />At Avokiddo we’re always brainstorming the best approach for creating educational content for youngsters. We ask ourselves: “Why are children drawn into an app, what piques their interest, how do they process information, how do they learn, what keeps them engaged and what makes them laugh?”</p>
<p>Creating educational content for children is rewarding work. Our apps have received overwhelmingly positive reviews and are used by teachers and educators around the world. Both our apps &#8211; Corona App of the Week winner <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/blog/2013/01/28/app-of-the-week-beck-and-bo/>Beck and Bo</a> and <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/avokiddo-emotions-playful/id661758013?mt=8>Avokiddo Emotions</a> &#8211; have been reviewed by major media outlets and handpicked by Apple as “Best for ages 5 and under.” We also receive daily testimonies from parents of children with special needs, saying that Avokiddo Emotions has helped their children better express emotions.</p>
<p>When it comes to development, we rely on <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/i-want-to-build/education-kid-apps/>Corona SDK</a>, a framework that allows us to publish to multiple platforms and reach a broad audience. Corona SDK’s intuitive architecture and well-documented API makes it easy for our team to bring ideas to life without wasting time on technicalities.</p>
<p>That being said, creating apps for kids takes much more than technical know-how. It takes personal involvement and strategy. To create our games, we put ourselves in children’s shoes to see things from their perspective. Here are the basic guidelines we recommend when designing <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/i-want-to-build/education-kid-apps/>educational content</a>:</p>
<p>1. <strong>Define your app’s purpose</strong>: Before diving into development, identify a problem within an educational branch and utilize technology to provide the solution. When it comes to designing educational apps for kids, you must take a holistic approach &#8211; spending quality time with kids, studying their behavior, and understanding what they like and dislike. These observations are not something you can find in a user manual.</p>
<p>2. <strong>Balance fun and learning</strong>: These two elements go hand-in-hand. When kids enjoy something, they are more likely to absorb new information. Learning is not merely about memorizing &#8211; which is a passive and repetitive process – but about absorbing information and truly understanding it through a hands-on approach.</p>
<p>3. <strong>Encourage creativity and self-expression</strong>: A mobile device is merely the medium &#8211; it should provide a challenging and stimulating environment where children obtain knowledge through active exploration and interaction. As kids are already born with a creative mind, take the opportunity to cultivate this quality.</p>
<p>4. <strong>Simplicity and clarity is a must</strong>: Eliminate complicated scenarios, multiple screen levels and complex UI. Neither children nor parents should have to read instructions on how to play, as engagement needs to occur naturally. An app with a clear look and feel helps kids avoid distractions. In Avokiddo Emotions, we explore facial expressions, feelings and behaviors. The app uses no textual instructions or other language-related UI making it a universal success without localization restrictions.</p>
<p>5. <strong>Create a beautiful UI</strong>: The overall aesthetics and graphics should be exceptional. Many designers underestimate this, thinking that kids can’t appreciate the difference. It’s our responsibility to offer children the very best experience to stimulate their imagination and train their brains and eyes to recognize and appreciate beauty.</p>
<p>6. <strong>Be innovative, yet familiar</strong>: Find a balance between the familiar and the new in order to make an age-appropriate app. In Beck and Bo, we encourage kids to experiment by dragging and dropping objects around the screen while listening to the objects’ names and sounds. Kids learn that the sun and clouds belong in the sky, that a boat floats on the water, and that apples fall from a tree. The concept of gravity is introduced to them using everyday items that they’re already familiar with.</p>
<p>7. <strong>Encourage real-life interactions and relationships</strong>: While technology favors communication, it also breeds isolation. Learning should be inclusive and stimulate real-life relationships. Educational apps should encourage kids, parents, and educators to actively participate together.</p>
<p>8. <strong>Consider privacy and safety</strong>: Since revisions to the Children&#8217;s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) went into effect on July 1, 2013, app developers are required to comply with a set of rules regarding the collection of personal information and the use of external links inside their apps. The <a href=http://momswithapps.com/about>“Know What’s Inside”</a> program is a great initiative that helps family-friendly app developers adopt best practices and comply with the new COPPA standards.</p>
<p>While the mobile world is evolving fast, more and more teachers and parents will continue to use mobile devices to educate and inspire children. To stay competitive in the educational content space, it’s important to be passionate about what you do and offer content of value. Educating kids is a very delicate process that needs to be approached with love and responsibility. It is our duty as developers to create apps that inspire, arouse interest in learning and cultivate creativity among youngsters.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2013/11/15/guest-piece-8-tips-on-creating-engaging-content-for-young-minds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guest Piece: The Benefits of Creating an eBook Series Over a Standalone App</title>
		<link>/blog/2013/11/13/guest-piece-the-benefits-of-creating-an-ebook-series-over-a-standalone-app/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 17:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[inna]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eBooks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=51417</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Randy Lowenstein is a creative executive with over 15 years of experience in digital media. In 2011, he co-founded <a href="http://www.megapops.com/">Megapops</a>, an interactive children’s entertainment company focused on creating original content for touch devices. The company's flagship property, Millie Was Here, is a series of book apps that follow the imaginary adventures of a real-life dog. The Millie Was Here series has been featured multiple times on the App Store.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Randy Lowenstein is a creative executive with over 15 years of experience in digital media. In 2011, he co-founded <a href=http://www.megapops.com/>Megapops</a>, an interactive children’s entertainment company focused on creating original content for touch devices. The company&#8217;s flagship property, Millie Was Here, is a series of book apps that follow the imaginary adventures of a real-life dog. The Millie Was Here series has been featured multiple times on the App Store.</em></p>
<hr />
<p><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Millie-collage.png" alt="Millie collage" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-51421" />When we started our app studio, <a href=http://www.megapops.com/>Megapops</a>, one of the very first decisions we made was to create an app series rather than a single standalone app. It’s a choice that&#8217;s proved to be successful, as working on a series has helped us develop our brand, build an audience, hone our workflow, and maximize marketing efforts. We were developing interactive books so an episodic/serial approach was a particularly good fit. It&#8217;s also a strategy that I believe could benefit apps of all genres. </p>
<h2>Creating a Brand</h2>
<p>Branding an app is difficult, but can be easier and evolve more organically if it’s done over time throughout several apps. Each app in a series provides a new opportunity to establish your creative direction, to develop your characters/narrative (where applicable), and to convey your brand’s unique voice and values. This allows you to build a stronger product and develop a deeper relationship with your users over time, which leads to increased brand recognition and consumer loyalty.</p>
<h2>Building an Audience</h2>
<p>The most important way a serial approach can help build an audience lies in the inherent ability of a series to cross-promote. Basically, each app in a series serves as an advertisement for every other app that you create.</p>
<p>When one of our apps happens to get featured in an app store or receive a favorable review on a review site and users download that individual app, they naturally discover our series. Our latest app, <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/millies-crazy-dinosaur-adventure/id695161183?mt=8>Millie’s Crazy Dinosaur Adventure</a> was recently featured by Apple. Throughout the duration of this feature, all four of the other apps in the series saw a 20-40% increase in downloads.</p>
<p>App reviewers, bloggers, members of the media, and app store curators are also an important part of the audience, and building a series allows you to connect with them in a similar way. For example, if a blogger/reviewer enjoys the first app in your series, she/he will likely welcome the second and third.</p>
<p>The media outreach that went along with our first apps, <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/millie-was-here-book-1-meet/id452174851?mt=8>Meet Millie</a> and <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/millie-lost-key-millie-was/id452175094?mt=8>Millie &#038; The Lost Key</a> (we actually launched with a pair of apps, one free and one paid), took about a month to complete. With our Halloween-themed release, <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/millies-book-tricks-treats/id472429219?mt=8>Millie’s Book of Tricks and Treats</a>, we were able to quickly reach out to the same group of people in a single afternoon. Because they were already familiar with the first books, their responses were often immediate. In some cases, we actually had reviews up in a matter of days.</p>
<p class="ac"><img src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Millie-screenshot.png" alt="Millie screenshot"></p>
<h2>Piloting is Much Harder Than Rolling Out</h2>
<p>Aside from the branding and audience-building benefits of a series, there are also a number of production benefits. A lot of hard work goes into prototyping and developing an app. A million details need to be worked out on both the creative and engineering fronts. Why start over again with every new release?</p>
<p>Once you&#8217;ve created a successful “pilot,” you can capitalize on all of that hard work in subsequent releases. You’ve already answered all of the hard questions about creative direction, architecture, style, and editorial voice. You’ve also already created a ton of code, graphics, sound effects, and music. You’ll always have to develop new assets for each new app, but having a library to draw from is a huge head start.</p>
<p>Production efficiency is definitely one of the key benefits that we’ve seen to a serial approach. From concept to App Store release, our first apps took us about 8 months to develop; our next app took us a fraction of that time and was developed at a fraction of the cost.</p>
<p>For “Millie’s Crazy Dinosaur Adventure,” we rebuilt everything from the ground up using <a href=www.coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk>Corona SDK</a> as our mobile development platform. By using Corona’s set of APIs, we’ve been able to make our apps more modular and easier to code. Also, Corona’s ability to build for multiple platforms with one code base makes it a perfect fit for the “pilot then rollout” model.  </p>
<h2>Maximizing Your Marketing</h2>
<p>Another benefit to developing a property rather than a standalone app is in the marketing. Marketing apps is extremely difficult, time consuming, and expensive (especially for independent developers).</p>
<p>In this bizarre app economy where $0.99 is commonly referred to as &#8220;expensive,&#8221; if every dollar you spend on marketing isn’t generating over a dollar in revenue, you’re losing money. One of the benefits to marketing a series over marketing an individual app is that a single marketing effort can benefit a number of different apps. Your marketing actually becomes more cost-effective with every new app in your series.</p>
<p>Obviously, not every app will work equally well as part of a series, and not everything I’ve outlined above applies equally to all types of apps, but it’s not that hard to turn most apps into a series of some sort. In fact, even a productivity app can be part of a suite of tools. It takes a little bit of extra planning upfront, but the possible benefits make it worth considering for your next release. In our experience we’ve found it to be a great approach.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
