<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>textures &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/textures/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>textures &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Introducing external bitmap textures</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/09/22/introducing-external-bitmap-textures/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 19:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Corona native builds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News & Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plugins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bitmap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graphics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[textures]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=67990</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Corona Labs engineers have created a new graphics-related feature and a new plugin which Enterprise/plugin developers can expand upon to build some very powerful graphical capabilities. Read further to learn more!]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Corona engineers have been doing some wonderful things lately, especially on the graphics engine side. One of these items is a feature which allows plugin creators and Corona Enterprise users to push textures directly into the Corona Graphics pipeline, effectively providing bitmap data. Resulting textures will behave similarly to those created by <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/library/graphics/newTexture.html target="_blank">graphics.newTexture()</a>.</p>
<h3>Below the surface</h3>
<p>Normally with Corona <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/library/display/index.html target="_blank">display</a> APIs, images are loaded and textures are created in memory, processed via the graphics processing unit (GPU). Once the image is in that realm, it becomes difficult to do pixel-level manipulation &#8212; setting and getting individual pixel information is a time-consuming effort, making it impractical for most operations.</p>
<p>Fortunately, the Corona Graphics API set provides capabilities to create textures with custom data from C-based plugins. The resulting objects inherit properties of <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/type/TextureResourceExternal/index.html target="_blank">TextureResourceExternal</a> as well as <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/type/TextureResource/index.html target="_blank">TextureResource</a> properties. Once created, these objects have <code>filename</code> and <code>baseDir</code> properties which can be used in any <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/library/display/index.html target="_blank">display</a> API or for assigning fills.</p>
<h3>Possibilities?</h3>
<p>An example of a plugin which might utilize these capabilities is a plugin which loads SVG (Scalable Vector Graphics) files, rasterizes them on the native C side, and pushes the results to Corona to return a texture object. That texture object could then be used to create typical display objects.</p>
<p>Other examples include image manipulation plugins based on <a href=http://www.imagemagick.org/script/index.php target="_blank">ImageMagick</a> or another C library, custom text and font renderers, and importing images from unsupported formats &#8212; the possibilities are endless!</p>
<h3>Take it for a test drive!</h3>
<p>To demonstrate this technology, our engineers have created a very simple plugin called <a href=https://marketplace.coronalabs.com/plugin/memory-bitmap target="_blank">memoryBitmap</a>. Available in the <a href=https://marketplace.coronalabs.com/plugin/memory-bitmap target="_blank">Corona Marketplace</a>, this plugin has just a single method, <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/memoryBitmap/newTexture.html target="_blank">memoryBitmap.newTexture()</a>. This creates a blank texture of specified dimensions and the result is a new <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/type/TextureResourceExternal/index.html target="_blank">TextureResourceExternal</a> object with two additional methods: <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/memoryBitmap/type/MemoryBitmap/setPixel.html target="_blank">:setPixel()</a> and <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/memoryBitmap/type/MemoryBitmap/getPixel.html target="_blank">:getPixel()</a>.</p>
<p>Directly &#8220;out of the box,&#8221; this plugin isn&#8217;t particularly useful to Corona SDK developers, since it cannot access your existing images. However, its <a href=https://github.com/coronalabs/plugins-sample-memoryBitmap target="_blank">source code</a> may be useful to Corona Enterprise plugin developers as a template for cross-platform Corona plugins supported on macOS, iOS, tvOS, Android, and Windows.</p>
<h3>Example</h3>
<p>We made a quick demo to create Spirograph™ style drawings using this new plugin&#8217;s <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/memoryBitmap/type/MemoryBitmap/setPixel.html target="_blank">:setPixel()</a> method. To test it, you&#8217;ll need to activate the plugin in the <a href=https://marketplace.coronalabs.com/plugin/memory-bitmap target="_blank">Corona Marketplace</a> and add the plugin to your <code>build.settings</code>.</p>
<p><a href=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/memory-bitmap.png><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-68106" src=/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/memory-bitmap.png alt="memory-bitmap" width="960" height="540" /></a>Below is the code for creating the texture and manipulating it by setting pixels:</p><pre class="crayon-plain-tag">local memoryBitmap = require( &quot;plugin.memoryBitmap&quot; )

local tex = memoryBitmap.newTexture(
{
    width = 1024,
    height = 1024,
    format = &quot;rgba&quot;
})

local function makeSpirals( texture, xOffset, yOffset, innerRadius, outerRadius, penOffset, color )
    -- Based on: http://introcs.cs.princeton.edu/java/15inout/Spirograph.java.html
    local R = outerRadius
    local r = innerRadius
    local a = penOffset

    for t = 0.0, 100, 0.01 do
        local x = (R+r) * math.cos(t) - (r+a) * math.cos(((R+r)/r)*t)
        local y = (R+r) * math.sin(t) - (r+a) * math.sin(((R+r)/r)*t)
        local degrees = -1 * math.deg((R+r)/r)*t
        texture:setPixel( x + xOffset, y + yOffset, color )
    end
    texture:invalidate()
end

makeSpirals( tex, 512, 512, 100, 55, 20, { 1, 0, 0, 1 } )</pre><p>In this example, the <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/plugin/memoryBitmap/newTexture.html target="_blank">memoryBitmap.newTexture()</a> function is returning a blank slate to work with. Essentially, you tell it the size of the object and the color depth rules and then you can start manipulating pixels as much as you like.</p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>We are excited to see what enterprising Corona developers will create with <a href=https://docs.coronalabs.com/api/type/TextureResourceExternal/index.html target="_blank">TextureResourceExternal</a> and the <a href=https://marketplace.coronalabs.com/plugin/memory-bitmap target="_blank">memoryBitmap</a> plugin as a basis for amazing features. Got a great idea? Please join us in the <a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/forum/615-advanced-graphics/ target="_blank">Corona forums</a>!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>From the Forum — Issue #108</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/01/29/from-the-forum-issue-108/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 23:15:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[From the Forum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cloud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[documentation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graphics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ldoc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parse.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[textures]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=65456</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Welcome to the latest installment of From the Forum. In this series, guest blogger Alex Jackson highlights outstanding threads from the Corona Forum. The goal is to bring attention to the most captivating, interesting, and thought-provoking discussions taking place in our very own backyard.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-54943" style="margin: 0px 0px 10px 10px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Icon_Resources_Forum.png" alt="From the Forum" /><em>Welcome to the latest installment of <strong>From the Forum</strong>. In <em>this series</em>, guest blogger Alex Jackson highlights outstanding threads from the <a href=http://forum.coronalabs.com>Corona/ Forum</a>. The goal is to bring attention to the most captivating, interesting, and thought-provoking discussions taking place in our very own backyard.</em></p>
<p><em>Please <a href=http://forum.coronalabs.com>visit/ the forum</a> to join these conversations or start your own!</em></p>
<hr />
<h3>Parse leaves a void</h3>
<p>For those of us who have been living under a rock may be surprised to learn that <strong>Parse</strong>, one of the most powerful third party server backends, has announced plans to shutter its service in a year&#8217;s time. There are a fair amount of Corona apps created with a Parse backbone, so this is potentially a huge blow to the community.</p>
<p>Where do we go from here? There are several different options in the realm of backends server products. You can&#8217;t shake a stick without hitting one. However, today we&#8217;re going to highlight a solution that combines a few different pieces into a virtual Voltron of awesomeness.</p>
<p>Corona dev (and our new best friend) <strong>Simon Fearby</strong> details how to get a managed server solution implemented that replaced Parse in functionality, with step by step instructions. Do yourself a favor and check out the link, and don&#8217;t forget to say thanks!</p>
<p><a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/61378-parse-is-dying-now-what/ target="_blank">https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/61378-parse-is-dying-now-what/</a></p>
<h3>Documentation: the elephant in the room</h3>
<p>I love backstory. I usually err on the side of over-explaining, sometimes, to my detriment. When it comes to documentation, though, I drop the ball and just start creating syntax that is nigh-impossible to decipher.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re like me, there is how fire us after all. Instead of resorting to electric shock, we can leverage a handy program called <a href=http://stevedonovan.github.io/ldoc/ target="_blank">Ldoc</a>. Developer <strong>Rene</strong> from <strong><a href=http://devilsquid.com/ target="_blank">DevilSquid</a></strong> lays out the details on its use, and even gives some instructions and pointers for getting started.</p>
<p>Check out the original thread to see where Ldoc can fit into your workflow. Documentation for a program that generated documentation? What a time to be alive.</p>
<p><a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/61391-how-to-document-lua-code-with-ldoc/ target="_blank">https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/61391-how-to-document-lua-code-with-ldoc/</a></p>
<h3>A fill, three years in the making</h3>
<p>Way back during the pre-Graphics 2.0 days, we imagined new ways to use our compositions and captured images in interesting ways. With the advent of snapshots, many though a fill using the same was just around the corner.</p>
<p>At last, <strong>Vlad</strong> from Corona has delivered the coolest of fills, allowing us to finally use snapshots. It’s a new feature, and one that needs the tired kicked on it by the entire Corona community. So do Vlad and yourself a favor, check out the original thread, and see how you can start using snapshot fills in your apps and games right now!</p>
<p><a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/40590-snapshot-as-paint-input/ target="_blank">https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/40590-snapshot-as-paint-input/</a></p>
<h4>About Alex</h4>
<p>Alex Jackson is an indie developer and the founder of <a href=http://www.panc.co/ target="_blank">Panc Interactive</a>, specializing in retro-style gaming. He has created several mobile applications, enjoys long walks on the beach, pixel art, and reading the Corona forums. Contact him by <a href=mailto:alex@panc.co>email</a> or follow him on Twitter: <a href=http://twitter.com/pancinteractive>@pancinteractive</a>. Check out his new game <a href=http://www.panc.co/segreta-download-page.html target="_blank">Segreta</a> on iOS, Android, Windows Phone and Amazon devices.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
