<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Remote Control &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/remote-control/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Remote Control &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>From the Forum — Issue #132</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/07/15/from-the-forum-issue-132/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 18:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[From the Forum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[composer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona Enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[enterprise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memory management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Remote Control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tvOS]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=67463</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Welcome to the latest installment of From the Forum. In this series, guest blogger Alex Jackson highlights outstanding threads from the Corona Forum. The goal is to bring attention to the most captivating, interesting, and thought-provoking discussions taking place in our very own backyard.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-54943" style="margin: 0px 0px 10px 10px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Icon_Resources_Forum.png" alt="From the Forum" /><em>Welcome to the latest installment of <strong>From the Forum</strong>. In <em>this series</em>, guest blogger Alex Jackson highlights outstanding threads from the <a href=http://forum.coronalabs.com/ target="_blank">Corona Forum</a>. The goal is to bring attention to the most captivating, interesting, and thought-provoking discussions taking place in our very own backyard.</em></p>
<p><em>Please <a href=http://forum.coronalabs.com/ target="_blank">visit the forum</a> to join these conversations or start your own!</em></p>
<hr />
<h3>tvOS helper code makes life much easier</h3>
<p>Getting our apps onto as many devices and platforms as possible is clearly a top priority among Corona developers. Why else would we decide to leverage the best SDK that can target the most OSes with minimal code changes between them?</p>
<p>One of the most exciting (and most challenging) platforms has been tvOS. It’s a fascinating option for deployment that brings with it some unique challenges, including a custom controller and no &#8220;save-state&#8221; option on the device.</p>
<p>Fortunately, stalwart developer <strong>Rakoonic</strong> has gifted us with a little utility that should streamline one aspect of tvOS development: a &#8220;remote controller&#8221; library which helps to standardize input for your apps and games. Speed over to <a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/64503-remote-controller-library-test/ target="_blank">the original thread</a> and check out what he’s offering!</p>
<h3>A memory manager by any other name</h3>
<p>Maintaining a trim and slim app can be a key to success. The way you manage the load time your program is incurring is something that users expect from modern developers. It’s also an integral part of software development that requires both creativity and focus to master.</p>
<p>One developer was wondering why the memory in their game was going up significantly during testing. Corona Support Engineer <strong>Rob Miracle</strong> chimed in with some serious knowledge on Composer scene management and image sheet optimization. It never hurts to brush up on the best methods to keep your app overhead low and your user base high! Check out those techniques in <a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/64515-why-does-texture-memory-jump/ target="_blank">the forum thread</a>.</p>
<h3>A leg up on Corona Enterprise for Android</h3>
<p>I realize that the number of Corona SDK users dwarfs the user base for Corona Enterprise, but that doesn’t mean we can’t highlight some awesomeness from the Enterprise sub-forum!</p>
<p>Recently, one Enterprise developer had some questions regarding sending messages from native iOS and what would be the best way to implement single message response callbacks on the Corona side. What they received was a great response pointing to the exact iOS API that should be utilized, a super reference to related tutorials, and a fantastic GitHub link with working code around the theory.</p>
<p>The Corona engineer that responded went both “above” and “beyond” with a great answer to the question. Click through to <a href=https://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/64566-delegate-self/ target="_blank">the original link</a> to for more information on this process!</p>
<h4>About Alex</h4>
<p>Alex Jackson is an indie developer and the founder of <a href=http://www.panc.co/ target="_blank">Panc Interactive</a>, specializing in retro-style gaming. He has created several mobile applications, enjoys long walks on the beach, pixel art, and reading the Corona forums. Contact him by <a href=mailto:alex@panc.co>email</a> or follow him on Twitter: <a href=http://twitter.com/pancinteractive>@pancinteractive</a>. Check out his new game <a href=http://www.panc.co/segreta-download-page.html target="_blank">Segreta</a> on iOS, Android, Windows Phone and Amazon devices.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
