<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Case Study &#8211; Education &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/topics/case-study-education/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 12:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/cropped-icon_32x32@2x-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Case Study &#8211; Education &#8211; Corona Labs</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Case Study: Yogome &#8211; educational games with a passion</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/08/30/case-study-yogome-educational-games-with-a-passion/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2016/08/30/case-study-yogome-educational-games-with-a-passion/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 21:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Case Study - Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Case Study - Game Studios]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=67742</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this case study, read about how Yogome is using Corona to create fun, polished, educational games for children of all ages.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright wp-image-67744" style="margin: 4px 0px 20px 20px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/yogomelogo.png" alt="yogomelogo" width="200" height="60" />It&#8217;s well known that learning can be fun when a game is involved. <a href=http://www.yogome.com/ target="_blank">Yogome</a>, a studio in Mexico City with an office in San Francisco, has jumped into this genre and is creating some fantastic learning adventures for kids of all ages. Their games are targeted towards elementary and middle-school students, but kids under 5 and over 12 can also find value playing their apps.</p>
<p>Yogome currently has <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/developer/yogome-inc/id536072105 target="_blank">30 titles in The App Store</a> and <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/developer?id=Yogome%2C+Inc. target="_blank">11 in Google Play</a>. Founded in 2010, Yogome was the brainchild of Manolo Díaz and Alberto Colin. They have since grown the studio to employ a staff of 40, including on-site language specialists for multiple language support and education experts to make sure the &#8220;education&#8221; goes with the fun.</p>
<p><iframe width="640" height="480" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ai59_f5lrFY?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Díaz heard about <a href=http://www.coronalabs.com/ target="_blank">Corona</a> in 2011 and, with its ease of use and ability to deploy to multiple platforms, it became their core technology for developing their content and powering their apps and games. Leveraging their staff and their own library of core code, Yogome can produce a game in around three months, even for a larger scope project.</p>
<p>Their latest title, <em>Epic Heroes of Knowledge</em>, challenges students with a mix of over 100 educational mini-games featuring unique characters and a fun, rewarding game mechanic. Players gain &#8220;PowerCubes&#8221; through play to strengthen their <em>Yogotar</em> and defeat the villains of Queen Ignorantia.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-67746" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/yogomess1-1024x767.jpg" alt="yogomess1" width="960" height="719" /></p>
<p>The game has eight &#8220;worlds&#8221; covering eight key subjects like math, science, and programming. These worlds can be explored and students can capture characters like the <em>WiFi Warrior</em>, the <em>Continental Divider</em>, and more. In addition, parents can join in and use the Yogome <em>Parent Dashboard</em> where they can keep track of the child&#8217;s progress and even send them challenges. <em>Epic Heroes</em> includes content developed with the help of the <a href=http://www.play2prevent.org/ target="_blank">play2PREVENT</a> lab at Yale University, including the math content.</p>
<p>The game is very deep in content &#8212; as you progress, you can pick up treasure, capture enemies, get new allies, and feed and care for them. It has its own economic system which teaches kids how to allocate resources. The game even supports multiplayer mode.</p>
<p>Yogome games are generally free with in-app purchases to unlock content. <em>Epic Heroes</em> is subscription-based in that you get more content each month for a monthly or annual fee. Check it out in the <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/epic-heroes-of-knowledge/id904827467?mt=8 target="_blank">App Store</a> and on <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yogome.EpicKnowledge target="_blank">Google Play</a>!</p>
<p><a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/epic-heroes-of-knowledge/id904827467?mt=8 target="_blank"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-64556" style="margin-right: 10px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/app-store-badge.png" alt="app-store-badge" width="50" height="50" /></a> <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yogome.EpicKnowledge target="_blank"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-64594" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/google-play-badge.png" alt="google-play-badge" width="50" height="50" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2016/08/30/case-study-yogome-educational-games-with-a-passion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Case Study: DoodleMaths &#8211; teaching math the fun way</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/03/17/case-study-doodlemaths-teaching-math-the-fun-way/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 01:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Case Study - Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Corona SDK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lua]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doodle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[math]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[primary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[secondary]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=66123</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this case study, dive into EZ Education's DoodleMaths, a math education app from this UK based development studio. Learn more about this innovative team and their accomplishments.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-66126" style="margin: 0px 0px 20px 20px;" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/vIay5wqa-150x150.png" alt="vIay5wqa" width="150" height="150" srcset="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/vIay5wqa-150x150.png 150w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/vIay5wqa-300x300.png 300w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/vIay5wqa-500x500.png 500w, /wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/vIay5wqa.png 551w" sizes="(max-width: 150px) 100vw, 150px" />In this post, we highlight <a href=https://www.doodlemaths.com/ target="_blank">DoodleMaths</a> by <a href=http://www.ezeducation.co.uk/ target="_blank">EZ Education</a>. DoodleMaths is an intuitive math app for children that allows them to consistently work at the best level for them. Its algorithm works to understand the level a child is currently working at and then it creates a work program for them so they can continually consolidate and learn new topics, rather than playing it safe and only doing what they know well.</p>
<p>Tom Minor, along with co-founder Nicola Chilman, founded EZ Education in 2012 with the aim of enhancing  the way kids learn through adaptive learning programs. As experienced classroom educators, they have first-hand experience working with kids, and DoodleMaths is the top-selling math app for elementary school children in the UK.</p>
<p><iframe width="1060" height="596" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PvokxEqIDOo?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" gesture="media" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>DoodleMaths has won many accolades. &#8220;We have had 5-star reviews from the Educational App Store and have recently won Best Mobile App at The SPARKies, run by TechSPARK. We have been in the top 10 of the education apps in iTunes, and we have been shortlisted for KPMG&#8217;s Best British Mobile Startup,&#8221; says Tom. &#8220;As a company, we have received numerous rewards and can proudly say we have the best selling primary maths app in the United Kingdom.&#8221;</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-66127" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/screen640x640.jpeg" alt="screen640x640" width="640" height="360" /></p>
<h3>Building their app</h3>
<p>The developers realized how much children engage with tablets and the huge potential for them to learn in a way that individually suits their needs. Their background as teachers and tutors meant that they had first-hand experience of how an app could work alongside common teaching methods in order to draw the most out of the child.</p>
<p>For EZ Education, app development is an ongoing process, so they continuously iterate on their design and code base. The company has used Corona for development of their three existing applications and their upcoming fourth application. Thanks to Corona and the Lua language, they can develop a core app in around three months and smaller projects even faster.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-66128" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/unnamed.jpg" alt="unnamed" width="512" height="384" /></p>
<p>When asked about advice for developers, Tom says &#8220;My first bit of advice would be for newcomers. I would recommend that they read the tutorials and try out some sample applications to see how much time they could save. Corona really streamlines the development process.&#8221; He continues, &#8220;It was important to my team to establish a set of programming standards and best practices and we were easily able to find wonderful examples on the Corona <a href=https://code.coronalabs.com/code target="_blank">Code Exchange</a>. I recommend that others look there for patterns and inspiration when developing their own application.&#8221;</p>
<h3>Going online</h3>
<p>Some developers chase problems which they have little experience in solving. For some, it&#8217;s a challenge to learn new things, but sometimes recognizing that you need help is an important step. For EZ Education, their staff is educators. Building and hosting an online service is challenging, but DoodleMaths needed features to enable teachers to get the most out of the app. EZ Education found the solution in Bluefuse Systems (<a href=http://www.bluefusesystems.com>www.bluefusesystems.com/</a>) to develop parent and teacher dashboards. These dashboards contain features such as live monitoring, live messaging, and leaderboards, giving the students the ability to challenge each other while keeping the parents and teachers involved in their progress.</p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>If you want to check out DoodleMaths and EZ Education&#8217;s other apps, visit their <a href=https://www.doodlemaths.com/ target="_blank">website</a> at <a href=https://www.doodlemaths.com/ target="_blank">https://www.doodlemaths.com/</a>. From there, you can download each of their apps on all of the supported platforms. DoodleMaths is a fun (but serious) tool used to educate children, and it was all built with Corona SDK. <a href=/ target="_blank">Get started today!</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Case Study: Corona SDK and Abilene Christian University</title>
		<link>/blog/2016/01/12/case-study-corona-sdk-and-abilene-christian-university/</link>
		<comments>/blog/2016/01/12/case-study-corona-sdk-and-abilene-christian-university/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Miracle]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Case Study - Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=65075</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Learn how a forward thinking university in West Texas is bringing mobile development to the main stream for it's students and how Corona SDK is making the program richer and more rewarding for its students.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><a href=/products/corona-sdk/ target="_blank">Corona SDK</a>, along with <a href=/products/enterprise/ target="_blank">Corona Enterprise</a> and <a href=http://coronacards.com/ target="_blank">CoronaCards</a>, are used by a wide variety of developers and usually with great success. This week we want to highlight one of those success stories: Abilene Christian University and <a href=http://www.acu.edu/academics/sitc/faculty/burton-brian.html target="_blank">Dr. Brian Burton, Ed.D</a>.</em></p>
<hr />
<h3>What is the background of ACU (age, number of students, locations, etc.)?</h3>
<p>Abilene Christian University (ACU) is a liberal arts university located in West Texas. Founded in 1906, ACU currently has more than 4,500 students and is a leader in Christian higher education.</p>
<p>In 2008, ACU was nationally recognized as the first university to offer iPhones or iPod touches to its incoming freshman. It has since been named the No. 2 Most Innovative Schools in U.S. News &amp; World Report (2016), 2014 Apple Distinguished School, on Forbes list of America’s Top Colleges for 2014, 2009 Institutional Excellence Award ACUTA, and named a College of Distinction in 2015.</p>
<p>ACU offers courses in Digital Entertainment and Mobile Computing programming with concentrations in digital design, game development, and film production.</p>
<h3>What is your background (technical and teaching)?</h3>
<p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-65147" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/Brian-Burton2-200x300.jpg" alt="Brian-Burton2" width="200" height="300" />I am one of the original computer geeks. I got started programming in high school on a TRS-80. In college, I majored in Computer Information Systems and Secondary Education (double major) and minored in Computer Science.</p>
<p>In 2007, I joined the faculty at Abilene Christian University where I developed a major and minor Digital Entertainment Technology, which offers an interdisciplinary approach to game development.</p>
<p>In the spring of 2009, after the introduction of the iOS SDK, I began teaching mobile app development courses.</p>
<h3>How did you first learn about Corona?</h3>
<p>In 2008, ACU became the first University to adopt the use of the iPhone in a major mobile emphasis on campus. As a part of that emphasis we started teaching mobile application development. For the first couple of years that was strictly Objective-C.</p>
<p>In early 2010, I began looking for a better way to teach app development. I was frustrated that to develop an app for iOS and Android required a complete re-programming of the project and knew there had to be a better way.</p>
<p>While I found several options for developing cross-platform applications, Corona was clearly head and shoulders above the rest.</p>
<h3>Why are you using Corona?</h3>
<p>The final decision to use Corona was made easy by Corona’s capability to be flexible and build for so many different platforms. With Corona, our students could develop sophisticated apps and games in a fraction of the time. Competing SDKs permitted us to make only apps OR games, not both.</p>
<h3>How is Corona being used in class?</h3>
<p>In the Introduction to Information, Technology, and Computing, the course project is centered on using Corona to learn how to program and develop mobile applications and games.</p>
<p>Our Introduction to Mobile Application class is for non-majors who want to learn the basics of app development. The class introduces how to program using LUA and Corona SDK.</p>
<p>In Mobile Computing I &amp; II, which are for Computer Science and Information Technology majors, Corona is used to provide students experience in developing cross-platform applications. These classes make use of the more advanced features such as GPS, accelerometer, and client/server systems.</p>
<p>In Digital Entertainment courses, students use Corona to prototype and develop mobile games. Corona has become our primary tool for developing 2D games and apps.</p>
<h3>What have been the results of using Corona?</h3>
<p>Corona has enabled me to spend more class time teaching how to make apps instead of teaching Objective-C or Java. Projects that were taking 6 weeks to complete are now completed in days. This extra time has allowed me as a professor to go deeper into app development, human-computer interface considerations, and network concerns. My students are now able to learn far more in one semester than when I was teaching pure iOS development.</p>
<h3>Would you recommend Corona to other schools?</h3>
<p>It depends on the school’s goal. Do they want their students to learn one development environment that will most likely change significantly with the next version or do they want to teach their students to make apps and games quickly and effectively without getting bogged down in the semantics of a single platform? Without question, Corona is the right choice for our university.</p>
<h3>Tell us about your textbooks</h3>
<p>I started migrating to Corona in 2010. I made the decision that the next academic year we would shift completely to Corona. So, I needed support materials. This was the early days of Corona and while the documentation was good, it wasn’t what was needed for a classroom. Thus I found myself writing lessons that could be used for my classes. This evolved into the first textbook Beginning Mobile App Development with Corona.</p>
<p>All of my textbooks are updated regularly at no additional cost. They are available at <a href=http://BurtonsMediaGroup.com/books target="_blank">Burton&#8217;s Media Group</a>.</p>
<h3>Sample student projects</h3>
<p>Here is a sample of the apps produced by students using Corona SDK.</p>
<h4>5 Second Frenzy</h4>
<p>A fast paced collection of mini games that will challenge your wits as well as your reflexes. Players have 5 seconds to solve each puzzle, each uniquely utilizing touch, tilt, or motion controls. See how long you can last and if you can solve each puzzle in time!</p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-65148" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/acu2.png" alt="acu2" width="178" height="267" /><a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/5-second-frenzy/id880726851 target="_blank"><img class="size-medium wp-image-65149 alignleft" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/acu3.png" alt="acu3" width="178" height="267" /></a></p>
<div style="clear: both;"></div>
<p>Download: <a href=https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/5-second-frenzy/id880726851 target="_blank">Apple App Store</a> |  <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.burtonsmediagroup.fivesecfrenzy target="_blank">Google </a><a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.burtonsmediagroup.fivesecfrenzy target="_blank">Play</a></p>
<h4>Gem Mine</h4>
<p>Become the next high scoring miner! Gem Mine is an intense, multilevel, gem catching, rock avoiding, ax throwing, power-up game that will have you playing for hours! The object of the game is to catch gems while avoiding the falling rocks of the mine. Try to reach a high score by throwing your ax and using power up shields to avoid the rocks. Other mysteries and hazards exist as well deeper in the mine, and you only have 3 lives, so beware of what you collect in the mine!</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-65150" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/acu1.png" alt="acu1" width="218" height="292" /></p>
<p>Download: <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=edu.acu.arg12c.Gem_Mine target="_blank">Google Play</a></p>
<h4>Subterranean Rocket Mailmen</h4>
<p>In this fast-paced platformer, play as a futuristic mailman jumping to make his delivery. Pick up other jet packs to help him boost to his destination. Be careful, though. There are several hazards including dysfunctional jet packs, spikes, and even an angry dog! Get rocketing!</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-65151" src="/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/acu4-300x169.png" alt="acu4" width="300" height="169" /></p>
<p>Download: <a href=https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=edu.acu.cjm13a.SRM&hl=en target="_blank">Google Play</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/blog/2016/01/12/case-study-corona-sdk-and-abilene-christian-university/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
